Seeker: [dishes clanking] You said it's multicolored?
c00002
DM: Yep.
c00003
Unknown: Is that different from the other one?
c00004
DM: No.
c00005
Unknown: Do you have a teacup yet?
c00006
DM: No, I don't have a teacup.
c00007
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c00008
DM: Okay. Thank you.
c00009
Unknown: Yeah.
c00010
DM: [dishes clanking] Oh, wait.
c00011
DM: We need music. [gentle music]
c00012
DM: So you have a few minutes to discuss out of character what you wanna do, and then we're rolling initiative.
c00013
DM: [gentle music]
c00014
Unknown: Tear away to the center.
c00015
Unknown: Cut it open. [coughs]
c00016
Seeker: Leviathan mode or no?
c00017
Delwath: Um, [coughs] I probably think you should stay in Leviathan mode because-
c00018
Unknown: Yeah
c00019
Delwath: ... you're practically immune to its damage.
c00020
Unknown: Um, we'll talk about it.
c00021
Delwath: Like, what are you gonna do, punch it?
c00022
Unknown: Right.
c00023
Unknown: Um,
c00024
Delwath: I'm feeling like Del- like the damage output from the Leviathan is pretty weak compared to Delwath's damage output.
c00025
Unknown: So-
c00026
DM: Um, thank you
c00027
Delwath: ... it's nice from the like,
c00028
Seeker: a, a immune to damage perspective apparently
c00029
Delwath: [dishes clanking] But, um, just... Coming down the smites scale armor damage.
c00030
Unknown: [dishes clanking]
c00031
Wellby: Is it not that we need to do anything different than just dump a whole bunch of damage to get into the center?
c00032
Wellby: Like we...
c00033
Wellby: Who knows if some... Is there a different way to attack the problem?
c00034
Seeker: Well, [clears throat] I think I can swim through
c00035
Unknown: to this direction.
c00036
Unknown: So we'll have to test that.
c00037
Unknown: I mean,
c00038
Unknown: possibly
c00039
Unknown: the idea is that
c00040
Delwath: everybody, uh,
c00041
DM: fights it while Seeker tries to swim.
c00042
Delwath: Like we fight towards the thing, and Seeker tries to go
c00043
Delwath: more into it and get the
c00044
Unknown: whatever it's guarding.
c00045
Seeker: Just retrieve it and then-
c00046
Unknown: And retrieve it.
c00047
Unknown: See if we can-
c00048
Delwath: See if we can bypass its defenses more easily-
c00049
Unknown: Right
c00050
Delwath: ... as Leviathan.
c00051
Unknown: I like that.
c00052
Kenzo: But we have to kill the thing in the middle, right?
c00053
Unknown: Well, uh, is that...
c00054
Seeker: Maybe I'll get it out.
c00055
Unknown: Right.
c00056
DM: Get what out?
c00057
Unknown: Whatever that thing is.
c00058
Delwath: The nodule of chaos that caused this whole problem.
c00059
Kenzo: Oh, so we think it's like an actual, like physical artifact?
c00060
Wellby: We need to like-
c00061
DM: Water organ
c00062
Wellby: ... like to x-ray the whole thing to understand.
c00063
Kenzo: Well, it's kind of, kind of how the...
c00064
Kenzo: Yeah. I'm sure we have the right kind of a metal mapper at least.
c00065
Seeker: We need to do the high res version of this.
c00066
DM: No, yeah. The, the like two little orbiting bits of...
c00067
DM: That's what you were sensing in the middle of the well, and that's presumably what's in the middle of this.
c00068
DM: It was, yeah.
c00069
Wellby: Is it like, is that like a battery that we can take out, or do we have to like destroy the whole of the thing out there?
c00070
DM: Kenzo's sense of it was it is a,
c00071
DM: it is a crystallized fragment of limbo that presumably must be destroyed in order to...
c00072
DM: Otherwise, anytime water gets in the cistern it'll just create another Unus.
c00073
Unknown: So basically...
c00074
Unknown: Right. So, so we send...
c00075
Unknown: But we don't know how to destroy it just yet.
c00076
Wellby: Can you banish an object
c00077
Wellby: back to its home dimension?
c00078
Unknown: Good question.
c00079
Unknown: I mean,
c00080
Delwath: could hold onto it and plane shift.
c00081
Seeker: Oh, drop it off and plane shift back.
c00082
Unknown: Yeah. I mean-
c00083
Wellby: You can't rainbow bridge back, but we could plane shift back?
c00084
Delwath: Uh, if Seeker come, if Seeker comes he can use a wand.
c00085
Unknown: Yeah.
c00086
Delwath: Actually, that suggests kind of one strategy would be for Seeker and Delwath to run towards the thing, try and get to the crystal center
c00087
Delwath: as Leviathans,
c00088
Delwath: grab onto the crystal center, plane shift to Limbo, and then plane shift back.
c00089
Wellby: Can you plane shift an unwilling creature or?
c00090
DM: No.
c00091
Wellby: Hm.
c00092
Unknown: We probably have to cut it out somehow.
c00093
Unknown: Also, do I have a wand?
c00094
Seeker: Not
c00095
Unknown: a spell.
c00096
Delwath: You'd have to turn into Delwath and then plane shift us.
c00097
Unknown: Hm.
c00098
Kenzo: We're gonna need to use your wand. We cannot go Leviathan anymore.
c00099
Unknown: Right.
c00100
Unknown: [dishes clanking]
c00101
Unknown: But it's unclear,
c00102
Delwath: it's very unclear if this thing is
c00103
Delwath: more like an organ
c00104
Delwath: that we would have to somehow cut out-
c00105
Seeker: Or a magic item
c00106
Delwath: ... or more like a,
c00107
Unknown: an item.
c00108
Wellby: Or if it can't be separated from the rest of the creature whatsoever.
c00109
Delwath: Right. Can Kenzo tell actually?
c00110
Unknown: The what?
c00111
DM: I mean, it's a...
c00112
DM: Yes, from Kenzo's perspective, it is a...
c00113
DM: It is, it is like the driver mutation of a cancerous tumor
c00114
Seeker: So if we drop it in the Green Sea and wait a few years, the entire Green Sea will be ooze.
c00115
Unknown: Yes.
c00116
Wellby: That'd be amazing.
c00117
Unknown: Yeah.
c00118
DM: But it's probably, like, you can't...
c00119
DM: I mean, you can't just pick it up, right?
c00120
Unknown: Right.
c00121
Unknown: It's probably, like...
c00122
Delwath: It's more like an organ.
c00123
DM: It's more like an organ than it is a...
c00124
DM: It's not like an item that's surrounded by ooze.
c00125
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
c00126
DM: To the extent the ooze has any internal structure, whatever, which it might have a lot of.
c00127
DM: We don't know.
c00128
DM: It's... I mean, you saw, right, that it was creating all these little filamentous strands.
c00129
DM: So it's possible that it's, like, surrounded by an acid net that will restrain you if you try and get close or anything, something like that.
c00130
Wellby: Right.
c00131
Wellby: And so that all serves to just kill the ooze and then
c00132
Wellby: deal with the thing once the ooze is dead?
c00133
Unknown: Well, I guess...
c00134
Wellby: But if you, you know, if it's the Dread Mutagen, then
c00135
Wellby: the rest of it's already grown.
c00136
Wellby: Like...
c00137
Delwath: But it's unclear...
c00138
Wellby: Like, we'd still have to kill the ooze even if we took the thing out of the center of it.
c00139
Seeker: That's the question, yeah.
c00140
Wellby: Which is...
c00141
Unknown: Well, I don't know.
c00142
Wellby: Is that the analogy you're making, Tim?
c00143
Delwath: The other ooze turned to crystal when we cut its connection.
c00144
DM: If you get r-
c00145
Unknown: Really?
c00146
DM: Yes. Like, possibly it will just turn to crystal if you
c00147
DM: get this thing out, but I'm just saying you c- I wouldn't expect you to be able to just swim into the middle of it and-
c00148
Wellby: Yeah
c00149
DM: ... lift it out, right?
c00150
DM: You're gonna have to do a significant amount of damage to
c00151
DM: cut... Like, you would have to cut it out, right?
c00152
DM: Like...
c00153
Seeker: I wonder if there's a way magically to slice a section of space
c00154
Seeker: and m- move it somewhere else, so like Wall of Stone kind of cuts through space.
c00155
Seeker: Any plane makes a door in space.
c00156
Seeker: What are the other things? Ooh, we have, like, a...
c00157
Seeker: to sort of extract something.
c00158
DM: So your wand...
c00159
Seeker: Oh, can that make an interplanar slice?
c00160
DM: So you could just make another w- another wound to Limbo, and then we could run last, yesterday's adventure all over again.
c00161
Seeker: [laughs] That's not so bad.
c00162
Seeker: Love it.
c00163
Wellby: Uh...
c00164
Delwath: Wait, so you need a spell, but you c- you still have your wish, right?
c00165
Unknown: That's-
c00166
DM: What? No
c00167
Seeker: ... a thing we could do.
c00168
Delwath: Seeker still has his wish?
c00169
Delwath: Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no.
c00170
DM: No. Shape change.
c00171
Delwath: You used shape change.
c00172
Seeker: Oh, that's right. Yeah.
c00173
Unknown: You used it on the wish.
c00174
Wellby: We have a Scroll of Wish and we have a genie in a bottle.
c00175
DM: You have a Scroll of Wish.
c00176
Seeker: The genie... What can the genie in a bottle do?
c00177
DM: It has a 10% chance of trying to kill you, a 10% chance of granting you a wish, and a 9- and an 80% chance of
c00178
DM: obeying your commands for one hour.
c00179
Unknown: Genie. That's pretty cool.
c00180
Wellby: It's pretty wonder- just to have an ally on the field.
c00181
Unknown: I like that.
c00182
DM: But remember, it's also an efreet.
c00183
Delwath: We should save it.
c00184
Unknown: It's, it's fire.
c00185
Delwath: For Plane of Fire.
c00186
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah.
c00187
DM: No, I mean if you want to learn something about the Plane of Fire, it's a person to talk to.
c00188
Unknown: cool guy.
c00189
Unknown: Um,
c00190
Delwath: Scroll of Wish is definitely something we could use.
c00191
Unknown: Well...
c00192
Seeker: And then, um...
c00193
Kenzo: I think my attitude is if we got items, let's fucking use them.
c00194
Unknown: Yeah.
c00195
Kenzo: If we wanna have... If we, if we have saves
c00196
Seeker: ... now is the time.
c00197
Unknown: Like,
c00198
Kenzo: spend your bardics, you know.
c00199
Kenzo: Well, that, that last adventure, Tim was like-
c00200
Unknown: We could use, um...
c00201
Kenzo: I was gonna say, Ti- Tim was like, "Y- you know you've got this potion of...
c00202
Kenzo: Like, check, check your inventory,"
c00203
Unknown: Yeah
c00204
Kenzo: ... and I was like, "What's in my inventory?" I was like, "Oh, fuck, I can turn into a dragon."
c00205
Kenzo: He's like, "Yeah, sure you wanna, you know, do that?"
c00206
Kenzo: Like, I was, like, debating whether or not to use it, and then at some point I was like, "Fuck it, just use it."
c00207
Unknown: Yeah.
c00208
Seeker: Well, I still have my invulnerability.
c00209
Delwath: We could use disintegrate.
c00210
Delwath: It's a sixth level spell.
c00211
Delwath: If the creature is huge or larger, the spell disintegrates a 10 foot cube portion of it.
c00212
Wellby: That's interesting.
c00213
Seeker: Versus telekinesis will lift it out.
c00214
Wellby: Or even, like, disintegrating our way in.
c00215
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00216
Wellby: Like, if it's a crystallized piece of another plane, maybe disintegrate doesn't apply to the-
c00217
Unknown: Or it does
c00218
Unknown: ... itself, right?
c00219
Delwath: ... things in the material plane.
c00220
Unknown: Yes.
c00221
Kenzo: How far in is it from where we are?
c00222
Kenzo: Like, we're at the surface.
c00223
DM: So okay. So let's set the scene bef- right, and then you're gonna roll initiative.
c00224
DM: You are s- so there's a, there's a pit that's c- there's like...
c00225
DM: So there's the cistern beneath the city that was once the, like, magical waters of Isingue, right?
c00226
DM: The... And there are wells.
c00227
DM: The w- the center well has collapsed, and so now there's a drop that goes down about 40 feet, just, like, rum- like,
c00228
DM: all the pillars have collapsed, the dirt has fallen in.
c00229
DM: There's just, like, rubble,
c00230
DM: um, below you
c00231
DM: sloping down, so it, like, makes a...
c00232
DM: It's like a sinkhole in the middle of the plaza, basically.
c00233
Unknown: Yeah.
c00234
DM: The ooze itself is, like, 400 feet big, but the center of the ooze is at the bottom of that 40 foot drop, and then it has all these, like, tendrils that
c00235
DM: are climbing up out of the, out of the pit.
c00236
DM: So imagine... Like, imagine a crater like this, like a sloped descent in a big circle.
c00237
DM: It's at the center of that, and there's, like, a fair bit of mass around it.
c00238
DM: There's... Like, it's...
c00239
DM: The ooze itself is, like, bubbling 30 feet up from the
c00240
DM: bottom of the ground, so there's at least, like, 30 feet of density of just ooze.
c00241
DM: It's almost more like an environment than a creature itself, right?
c00242
DM: And it's sending out long tendrils, like, 100 feet in each direction around the center of this collapsed
c00243
DM: mass. [coughs]
c00244
Wellby: Uh, what are its immunities and resistances again?
c00245
Kenzo: Immune to, like, everything.
c00246
Unknown: Resistant to everything.
c00247
DM: So it is immune to acid, necrotic poison.
c00248
DM: It's resistant to everything.
c00249
Unknown: [laughs]
c00250
DM: Charmed, exhausted, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, stunned, unconscious.
c00251
DM: Has blind sight. It's not immune to incapacitated.
c00252
Unknown: Oh.
c00253
DM: That's the only thing it's not immune to.
c00254
DM: [laughs]
c00255
Unknown: And
c00256
Seeker: w- its weakest saves?
c00257
DM: Uh, its, its weakest save is charisma.
c00258
DM: Strongest save is con.
c00259
Kenzo: Um, but the... This density,
c00260
Kenzo: where, where is that? It's, like, kinda-
c00261
DM: In the, in the middle.
c00262
Kenzo: But how far down? How many feet?
c00263
DM: It's, like, 30 feet down.
c00264
DM: There's, like, a blob that's, like, a 30 foot by 30 foot cube in the middle of the sinkhole.
c00265
Unknown: Yeah.
c00266
DM: And that's the thickest part of the ooze.
c00267
Unknown: Got it.
c00268
DM: And the nodule's, like, in the middle of that.
c00269
Kenzo: Got it. Guys, you know what we're fighting?
c00270
Kenzo: Like, this is, I think, the best analogy.
c00271
Kenzo: It literally is, um, the fucking ending of Akira.
c00272
Unknown: Yeah.
c00273
DM: Mm.
c00274
Seeker: Oh my God, that movie.
c00275
Unknown: Yeah.
c00276
Unknown: That's what this is.
c00277
Unknown: Wow.
c00278
Seeker: So banishment [clears throat] is a charisma save.
c00279
Delwath: I mean, we could just...
c00280
Kenzo: That's good 'cause it'll... They could burn legendary resistance instead of these if you try to banish it.
c00281
Unknown: Right.
c00282
DM: Well-
c00283
Unknown: It just-
c00284
DM: You only have banishment through your wand, right?
c00285
Delwath: I mean, I can cast Banish.
c00286
Seeker: I have seven charges of Banishment through the wand.
c00287
DM: No, but I mean you can't use your wand while you're cracked.
c00288
Seeker: Well, we're alive. We'll be fine.
c00289
Delwath: But it also comes back when banishment ends.
c00290
Delwath: Although, if the target is...
c00291
Kenzo: But it also makes it use the, use up its, its resistances.
c00292
Unknown: Yeah, yeah,
c00293
Delwath: yeah. It's unclear, I guess, if it would come back or if it counts as...
c00294
DM: Yeah, is it one of those types where you
c00295
DM: Uh, not
c00296
DM: according to the time sheet, it is not native to Limbo.
c00297
Seeker: Right. Right. So is it an aberration, a celestial, an elemental, a fey, or a fiend?
c00298
DM: No, it's an ooze.
c00299
Unknown: Yeah. Oh, that's a whole category.
c00300
DM: That's a whole creature type.
c00301
Unknown: So, yeah.
c00302
DM: It was created by the magic of the Limbo contamination.
c00303
DM: It was created by a Limbo contamination-
c00304
Unknown: No, but it's native to the Material Plane
c00305
DM: ... but it's, it's actually...
c00306
DM: Fundamental material is the Waters of Isingue.
c00307
Seeker: Mm. So it would come back from banishment.
c00308
DM: Yes.
c00309
Seeker: We could try imprisonment.
c00310
Unknown: Using the Scroll of Wish.
c00311
Unknown: Or just make-
c00312
DM: No, imprisonment is a 9th level spell
c00313
Seeker: No, we could try it using the Bindings.
c00314
DM: It would cost a minute to cast.
c00315
Unknown: Yeah. But I'm not-
c00316
Delwath: I, I, I think, I think we need to just, I think we need to just fight it, right?
c00317
DM: Well, right now you need to roll initiative 'cause it is attacking you.
c00318
Seeker: So we cannot use imprisonment.
c00319
DM: It's not just waiting for you to, like, do whatever you want to it.
c00320
Unknown: Right.
c00321
DM: So roll initiative.
c00322
Unknown: All right.
c00323
Seeker: So the other ooze
c00324
Seeker: seems to focus its attacks on the thing that it noticed was attacking it.
c00325
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00326
Seeker: Which suggests to me that I should use Summon Construct to have a separate target to-
c00327
Delwath: Oh, yeah. That's a great idea
c00328
DM: The two things the other ooze did that you might want to remember is it had...
c00329
DM: It managed to c- make itself resistant to a certain damage type
c00330
DM: and it focused attacks on whoever had last attacked it.
c00331
DM: But whether this thing does the same thing, I don't know.
c00332
Kenzo: Tim, you want this last little bit here?
c00333
DM: No, I'm good. I still have some on my plate.
c00334
Unknown: But only two-
c00335
Unknown: Mike, any more?
c00336
Delwath: No, I had the last bite. I'm good.
c00337
Unknown: All right. I'm just gonna do this.
c00338
Wellby: To a certain damage type?
c00339
DM: Well, that was what the other ooze did.
c00340
Seeker: Yeah.
c00341
Unknown: Wait.
c00342
Seeker: It... So wait, it could switch to one-
c00343
DM: Yeah
c00344
Unknown: ... damage type.
c00345
Seeker: Oh, and I can't hear my initiative.
c00346
Unknown: Well, I-
c00347
Seeker: I'm modifying damage
c00348
Delwath: ... cannot use your wand in the land, but okay.
c00349
DM: Okay, initiative. [rolls dice] Uh, uh, what's my plus?
c00350
Unknown: It's just, uh,
c00351
Unknown: 7. 21.
c00352
Wellby: 30 for me.
c00353
Unknown: 30.
c00354
c00355
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c00356
Unknown: 19.
c00357
Unknown: 15.
c00358
Wellby: [laughs] No, plus 7 is, uh...
c00359
Unknown: Uh, it's 25.
c00360
Unknown: Oh, 20. Sorry.
c00361
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. I got a, um, also a really high
c00362
Seeker: initiative modifier is 20.
c00363
Unknown: Wait, should we bring up the Paraceratops?
c00364
Unknown: Oh, 31.
c00365
DM: Can't. Seven-day recharge.
c00366
Unknown: Oh.
c00367
DM: 31?
c00368
Kenzo: Yeah. I rolled an 18.
c00369
Kenzo: I have a plus 13.
c00370
Wellby: The, uh, the fly we can see if we bring out, but the fly is not exactly a friend yet.
c00371
Unknown: Right.
c00372
DM: Sorry, who was 21? Seeker was 20 and Delwath was 21?
c00373
Kenzo: Kenzo's 31.
c00374
DM: Are you gonna switch?
c00375
Delwath: Uh, do you want- Wait, what's our order?
c00376
Unknown: Kenzo-
c00377
DM: Kenzo, Wellby, Delwath, Seeker
c00378
Unknown: ...
c00379
Delwath: I mean, should, should just, should, uh, Kenzo go first so that everybody...
c00380
Delwath: Oh, no, it doesn't matter 'cause everybody gets...
c00381
Unknown: Everybody gets what?
c00382
Delwath: You'll get advantage on your second round if [coughs] this versus your first round.
c00383
Kenzo: Because I'm in melee.
c00384
Wellby: Uh [coughs] e- everyone gets advantage once.
c00385
DM: Everyone gets advantage one, on one turn.
c00386
Wellby: Whether you go before me or after me, it doesn't matter.
c00387
DM: Yeah.
c00388
Wellby: You'll get advantage on the next one.
c00389
Wellby: I think the sort of mechanic... I don't know.
c00390
Wellby: Maybe it's simpler for me to go first, but, uh...
c00391
Unknown: But then
c00392
Unknown: you'll get [inhales]...
c00393
Unknown: Well, you don't get sneak attack unless there's allies.
c00394
Delwath: Or you steady aim.
c00395
Unknown: Or you steady aim.
c00396
Unknown: If you steady aim-
c00397
Wellby: Wait, how far up was the, um, was Vindr Sharna when it attacked?
c00398
DM: 600 feet.
c00399
Unknown: Uh, that's too far.
c00400
Delwath: But there's not much upside in not steady aiming because you have nothing else to do with your bonus action.
c00401
Unknown: Uh, true.
c00402
Delwath: 'Cause attacking twice isn't r- I mean, sure, you could get, do another 1D6.
c00403
Unknown: Yeah.
c00404
Kenzo: Advantage for me is fucking, like-
c00405
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c00406
Unknown: ... massively awesome
c00407
Unknown: ... 50/50.
c00408
Unknown: Okay, so you go first.
c00409
DM: Okay, so it's-
c00410
DM: What'd you roll for initiative?
c00411
DM: 30.
c00412
Unknown: 31.
c00413
DM: 31.
c00414
Unknown: [laughs]
c00415
Kenzo: 31. What'd you get?
c00416
Unknown: 30.
c00417
Wellby: [laughs]
c00418
Kenzo: [laughs] And you thought you were going to get ridiculous initiative.
c00419
Wellby: [laughs] I really thought I had it this time, Kenzo.
c00420
Kenzo: Well, this is a plus... I, this is because it's the level 20 thing.
c00421
Kenzo: My, my, my initiative modifier used to be plus 11.
c00422
Kenzo: Now it's plus 13.
c00423
Wellby: [laughs]
c00424
Kenzo: What's your, what's your modifier?
c00425
Wellby: Only plus 11.
c00426
Kenzo: Eh.
c00427
Wellby: I know. Yeah, I'm slowing down.
c00428
Kenzo: You are slowing down.
c00429
Kenzo: Old age.
c00430
DM: Okay. So Kenzo, or sorry, Wellby.
c00431
DM: You're now, you're cur- uh, it's gonna be...
c00432
DM: The battle map is a little bit complicated, but you're currently presumably something like,
c00433
DM: uh, 200 feet away from it as you step through the...
c00434
Kenzo: Oh, because we can see-
c00435
Wellby: Oh, to the edge of the-
c00436
Delwath: 'Cause that's like the edge, 'cause it's like 400 feet.
c00437
Kenzo: We're probably like 100 feet away, right?
c00438
Kenzo: When the edge of the-
c00439
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. You're 100 feet away
c00440
Delwath: ... it's 600 feet... It's 300 feet across, right?
c00441
DM: Yeah.
c00442
Delwath: I mean, 600 feet across
c00443
Wellby: How tall is that? Is it all the way up?
c00444
DM: Is what?
c00445
Wellby: Is it like a sphere of clearness-
c00446
DM: High
c00447
Wellby: ... or is it a column of clearness?
c00448
DM: Uh, it's a, it's a column.
c00449
DM: It, like, goes up pretty high.
c00450
Wellby: Mm.
c00451
DM: But yeah, you're... It's, the ooze itself is like 300 feet across
c00452
DM: and
c00453
DM: is moving towards the river, so it's bi- it's biased towards the river.
c00454
DM: And you are at the riverside, so the ooze is 200 feet away from the-
c00455
Kenzo: Okay
c00456
DM: ... clear spot.
c00457
Delwath: We come out, we're 200 feet away.
c00458
DM: You come out, you're 200 feet away from it.
c00459
Unknown: Well...
c00460
DM: Wellby?
c00461
Wellby: I...
c00462
Delwath: Our planning is planned.
c00463
DM: We're gonna do what we're gonna do.
c00464
Kenzo: We're just gonna attack it, right?
c00465
DM: Yeah.
c00466
Kenzo: Attack and try to get to the middle.
c00467
Wellby: What was the planning that we did again?
c00468
Delwath: [laughs] We didn't. That's...
c00469
Wellby: [laughs]
c00470
Kenzo: Kenzo's like, "Roll initiative."
c00471
Wellby: Yeah, but we basically just like had a way-
c00472
DM: We need to get to the center and-
c00473
Kenzo: Get to the middle, yeah
c00474
Delwath: ... get to the middle.
c00475
Kenzo: But it's like wh- it's like how we cut off the edge of the thing.
c00476
Kenzo: Like it just-
c00477
DM: Yeah
c00478
Kenzo: ... it's not smart. It's just gonna attack whoever attacked it last.
c00479
Kenzo: It's gonna try to protect itself.
c00480
Seeker: Seeker's excited to be immune to acid and will just dive right in the center.
c00481
Seeker: I can dash all the way to it on my turn, I think.
c00482
Delwath: You could also use a legendary action to move after-
c00483
DM: You can use a legendary action to move after-
c00484
Delwath: ... after everybody else
c00485
Unknown: Right.
c00486
Seeker: So I can [coughs] before my turn.
c00487
DM: Yeah.
c00488
Kenzo: It's a little like capture the flag-ish.
c00489
Wellby: A- as a legendary turn.
c00490
Delwath: It's a legendary action. You can move after anybody's turn.
c00491
Wellby: Yeah. Uh, all right.
c00492
DM: Yeah.
c00493
Wellby: Wellby emerges,
c00494
Wellby: pauses, hovering in midair.
c00495
DM: You said it's 100 feet from us?
c00496
Unknown: Oh, but it's only-
c00497
DM: 200 feet from you.
c00498
Wellby: Okay.
c00499
DM: There's only 40 on land. Yeah.
c00500
Wellby: Takes a slow, steady breath.
c00501
Kenzo: But it'll still be over there.
c00502
Wellby: Aims for the
c00503
Wellby: ooziest part
c00504
Wellby: and... Oh, shit.
c00505
Wellby: That's not great.
c00506
Wellby: Uh, is it armored?
c00507
DM: It is not armored.
c00508
Wellby: Uh, I'm scared. It's another one, so that is, uh, 23.
c00509
DM: 23 hits.
c00510
Kenzo: 23.
c00511
Wellby: But in the sort of tone of voice that 22 might not?
c00512
DM: N- mm.
c00513
Wellby: No, 22 might not. 22 might not.
c00514
DM: You'll have to roll again. 22 we can see.
c00515
Kenzo: It is, it is strong.
c00516
Wellby: Yeah.
c00517
Kenzo: Oh.
c00518
Wellby: Okay. And I, none of my things can do anything to it, so it's gonna do some damage.
c00519
Wellby: Uh, six, six, 12, 15.
c00520
Wellby: Uh, 15 is 38.
c00521
Delwath: So wait, we're 200 feet away.
c00522
Wellby: Okay.
c00523
Wellby: Are there bardic inspirations to do that?
c00524
Kenzo: Not as a level five thing.
c00525
Wellby: Oh.
c00526
DM: Yeah.
c00527
Unknown: Oh, really?
c00528
Delwath: You can't use your class ability if it wants forecasting.
c00529
DM: Yeah.
c00530
Unknown: Ah, good to know.
c00531
Kenzo: So, no.
c00532
DM: So, no. Okay.
c00533
DM: Sorry, what did you roll for damage?
c00534
Wellby: 38.
c00535
Kenzo: We just went straight into this, huh? So we're, we didn't short rest.
c00536
Kenzo: We didn't do anything. We're just like-
c00537
DM: No. Yeah, but you, you can regain your ki with initiative.
c00538
Kenzo: Oh, I just... That's right
c00539
DM: ... and also heal.
c00540
Kenzo: I, that's right. So I am actually all set.
c00541
Unknown: Let me see.
c00542
Delwath: Uh, I'm gonna use a legendary action to move 40 feet closer to it.
c00543
DM: Okay.
c00544
Unknown: I'll also then...
c00545
DM: So you're both 160 feet away now.
c00546
DM: That's what it is.
c00547
DM: Uh, it is going to use a legendary action to
c00548
DM: blast
c00549
DM: Wellby with a pseudopod.
c00550
Wellby: What if instead it thinks about the next person who might cause it damage?
c00551
Wellby: [dice rolling]
c00552
Wellby: [laughs]
c00553
Kenzo: I mean, Ken-
c00554
Unknown: Rather than the last one who did.
c00555
Kenzo: Come on. Think ahead, it is.
c00556
DM: Uh, that's a range of, a reach of 600 feet.
c00557
DM: [die rolling] That's a 26.
c00558
Wellby: That's a hit.
c00559
DM: And you take 22 points of force damage.
c00560
Wellby: I, uh-
c00561
Kenzo: That's interesting
c00562
Wellby: ... at this point,
c00563
Wellby: I might as well.
c00564
Unknown: Yeah.
c00565
Wellby: Let's make that 11, and that's my reaction.
c00566
DM: And it also shifts
c00567
DM: and-
c00568
Wellby: Is the pseudopod now like...
c00569
Wellby: Oh, go ahead, sorry. [coughs]
c00570
DM: It comes, like you can see the ooze becoming a little bit more, um,
c00571
DM: uh, liquidy such that arrows will fly through it.
c00572
Wellby: What?
c00573
Kenzo: Oh.
c00574
DM: It is now resistant to piercing damage.
c00575
Seeker: It's just updating its resistance.
c00576
Wellby: Yeah.
c00577
Seeker: Which means it's not resistant to whatever it was resistant to before.
c00578
Kenzo: Well-
c00579
Wellby: Is there now a pseudopod like hanging out next to me, or did it like go back?
c00580
DM: No, it goes...
c00581
DM: Hits you in the face and retreats.
c00582
Wellby: All right.
c00583
Seeker: So it just has the singular damage types.
c00584
Delwath: Yeah, which is tough as leviathans.
c00585
Unknown: But so-
c00586
Kenzo: It's also omnilugent
c00587
Delwath: ... and acid, but presumably permanently immune to acid.
c00588
DM: You know it's immune to acid.
c00589
Unknown: Yeah.
c00590
DM: Kenzo, you're up.
c00591
Kenzo: Yeah, uh, so when I Sol Sign it again, is it still, is it still the same immunities and resistances, or now is it...
c00592
DM: Uh, it is now resistant to piercing damage, immune to acid, necrotic poison, same other immunities, same saves.
c00593
Kenzo: Okay. Well, um,
c00594
Kenzo: so I have to do superior defense again.
c00595
Kenzo: Yeah, for one minute, so I'd have to do it again.
c00596
Kenzo: All right. So I'll do superior defense,
c00597
Kenzo: spend three ki on that.
c00598
Unknown: Um,
c00599
Kenzo: oh, I can't do that part.
c00600
DM: Is that you're resistant to all damage types but force.
c00601
DM: Is that correct?
c00602
Kenzo: Uh, let me double check. No, I think, I think it's just all, all damage types.
c00603
Unknown: It's all damage?
c00604
Unknown: Yeah.
c00605
Kenzo: Uh...
c00606
Kenzo: Oh, except force damage. Uh,
c00607
Kenzo: does it know that? It doesn't, it doesn't know that.
c00608
DM: It did force damage to Wellby.
c00609
Kenzo: Huh?
c00610
Delwath: It did force damage to Wellby.
c00611
Kenzo: Oh. [clears throat] Um, I can't use Lunyow's Claw again, huh?
c00612
DM: No.
c00613
Kenzo: No.
c00614
Unknown: All right. Well, I will...
c00615
Kenzo: Oh, but I haven't used my, um, my crazy attack yet.
c00616
DM: Oh, that's true. You can use your crazy attack.
c00617
Kenzo: Yeah. What the fuck, why not?
c00618
Kenzo: What are we here for? I'll do that.
c00619
Kenzo: I will, um,
c00620
Kenzo: I will use my staff to, uh,
c00621
Kenzo: do some crazy shit.
c00622
Kenzo: I get advantage now, right, because of you?
c00623
Wellby: Yes.
c00624
DM: Yes.
c00625
Kenzo: Awesome. All right, so I'm gonna do Vital Burst.
c00626
Kenzo: So now I get...
c00627
Kenzo: Until the beginning of my next turn, all attacks against me have disadvantage, my speed is doubled, and when I take the...
c00628
Kenzo: I get four attacks instead of two.
c00629
Kenzo: Well, that's perfect, 'cause now, 'cause we're 200 feet away, right?
c00630
DM: Yeah.
c00631
Kenzo: And I can fly.
c00632
DM: What's your move?
c00633
Kenzo: 70, but-
c00634
Delwath: It's doubled, so.
c00635
DM: So it's doubled, so 140.
c00636
Kenzo: But also, as an astral dude.
c00637
DM: I think that's just your speed.
c00638
Kenzo: [laughs] Okay.
c00639
Kenzo: Oh, that's all...
c00640
Delwath: So you can...
c00641
Kenzo: Oh, I can only...
c00642
Kenzo: Well, maybe I shouldn't use it now then, right?
c00643
Kenzo: Or can I get there in time?
c00644
Delwath: Well, you, you only if you use your bonus action.
c00645
DM: You could bonus action dash
c00646
DM: and get there and make four attacks with your staff.
c00647
Kenzo: Or otherwise I, otherwise I could just, I could save it for next round and then do seven attacks all at once.
c00648
Unknown: Well, but-
c00649
Delwath: But Wellby's advantage is gonna last only for this round.
c00650
Kenzo: Ah.
c00651
Unknown: You should, you should just-
c00652
Kenzo: Do it now
c00653
Delwath: ... you should do it now. Do four attacks with your staff with advantage.
c00654
Kenzo: Okay. All right.
c00655
Unknown: Yeah.
c00656
Kenzo: I'll do that.
c00657
DM: And if you want, um, well, probably no one else wants to get closer.
c00658
DM: If you're gonna use Step of the Wind-
c00659
Kenzo: Ah
c00660
DM: ... you can bring somebody with you.
c00661
Kenzo: You want to bring a leviathan?
c00662
Unknown: Sure.
c00663
Seeker: I'm the one that's trying to go straight in, so I should probably go first.
c00664
Delwath: Bring, bring Seeker with you.
c00665
Unknown: Yeah.
c00666
Kenzo: All right. Wow.
c00667
Unknown: Amazing.
c00668
Kenzo: What a scene.
c00669
Kenzo: Okay, so-
c00670
Seeker: That's, that's weird. I like it.
c00671
Kenzo: Yeah, I Step of the Wind and I...
c00672
Kenzo: You're within five feet of me.
c00673
Kenzo: Oh, shit. I can bring a willing creature that is large or smaller.
c00674
Unknown: Wow.
c00675
DM: No, so you can't bring a leviathan.
c00676
Kenzo: That's bigger.
c00677
Unknown: That's a good point.
c00678
DM: A little bit too big to carry, even for a 20th level monk.
c00679
DM: [laughs]
c00680
Kenzo: That's a little... That would've been quite a sight, though.
c00681
Kenzo: Like-
c00682
DM: You can bring Wellby if he wants to get closer.
c00683
Kenzo: I don't think you do. Do you?
c00684
Wellby: I don't think so.
c00685
Unknown: No.
c00686
Kenzo: I don't think you do.
c00687
Unknown: Although-
c00688
Unknown: Does it matter?
c00689
Wellby: Not really at this point.
c00690
Kenzo: All right. I'll... All right, so now I guess I get up in-
c00691
Delwath: It has an acid... The other one had an acid goo shot.
c00692
Kenzo: Yeah.
c00693
Delwath: Being spread out is probably a good idea.
c00694
Unknown: Mm.
c00695
Kenzo: Yeah, spread out is good. Okay, and I will do four staff attacks with advantage.
c00696
Kenzo: Okay, let's see.
c00697
Seeker: Such a balance.
c00698
Seeker: Okay, so this is plus 15.
c00699
Unknown: 15.
c00700
Kenzo: All right, so first attack.
c00701
Kenzo: Oh, crit.
c00702
Unknown: One.
c00703
Unknown: Nice.
c00704
DM: Nice.
c00705
Kenzo: Okay.
c00706
Delwath: And you can do an extra D12, right?
c00707
DM: Yep.
c00708
Kenzo: Yeah. First attack.
c00709
DM: It's on your first attack, so you can-
c00710
Kenzo: Second attack, that definitely hits.
c00711
Kenzo: Third attack.
c00712
Kenzo: Ooh, 8, uh, 8 plus 15 is 23.
c00713
DM: That hits.
c00714
Kenzo: Third attack hits.
c00715
Kenzo: Fourth attack hits. Okay, so all four hit and I crit, so that's...
c00716
Unknown: So that's 4.
c00717
Delwath: That's, eh, 8.
c00718
Kenzo: No, no, no.
c00719
Unknown: 8D12.
c00720
Kenzo: 8D12?
c00721
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause you critted on the one that you get two D12s.
c00722
DM: You crit it on your first hit.
c00723
Kenzo: Yeah.
c00724
DM: Your first hit gives you two D12s.
c00725
Unknown: So that's four... Oh, no, seven.
c00726
Kenzo: 7D12.
c00727
Unknown: It's 7D12.
c00728
DM: [laughs] Oh, my God.
c00729
Unknown: 7D12 plus...
c00730
Delwath: Four attacks hit, so-
c00731
Kenzo: Plus, plus 9 times 4-
c00732
Unknown: Yeah
c00733
Kenzo: ... is 36.
c00734
Unknown: Yeah. So 7D12 plus 36.
c00735
Kenzo: Okay.
c00736
Kenzo: That's good. This is good.
c00737
Kenzo: D12s are so good.
c00738
Delwath: There's two right here. There's five right there.
c00739
Kenzo: Oops.
c00740
Kenzo: Five right here. Okay. All right.
c00741
Kenzo: That's six.
c00742
Wellby: And here's 7.
c00743
Kenzo: Yeah. Oh, that's fun.
c00744
Kenzo: Okay, so 7D12 plus 36.
c00745
Seeker: Just roll it right on the, uh, on the ooze.
c00746
Kenzo: Yeah, I'll roll it on the ooze. [dice clatter] That is...
c00747
Kenzo: That's not-
c00748
Delwath: Reroll that.
c00749
Kenzo: Huh?
c00750
Delwath: Oh, one of them was on its side.
c00751
Kenzo: Oh, which one?
c00752
Unknown: That one.
c00753
Kenzo: Is it just-
c00754
Unknown: Just leave it.
c00755
Kenzo: I think it's fine.
c00756
Unknown: Just leave it, just leave it. It's fine.
c00757
Kenzo: 20, 35, uh,
c00758
Kenzo: 35. Oh, fuck. 35 plus 9 is 44.
c00759
Wellby: We're doomed.
c00760
Kenzo: 52 plus...
c00761
Unknown: 36.
c00762
Kenzo: 52 plus 36
c00763
Kenzo: is 88.
c00764
Wellby: That's 88.
c00765
Kenzo: 88.
c00766
Unknown: That's a lot.
c00767
Wellby: Holy shit. [laughs]
c00768
Kenzo: All right, 88.
c00769
Wellby: 88.
c00770
Kenzo: Cool.
c00771
DM: Okay, so you do 88 damage.
c00772
Unknown: Bam, bam, bam, bam.
c00773
DM: As four staff, four staff attacks all strike it.
c00774
DM: And as your, as your, um...
c00775
DM: Does that ends your turn?
c00776
Kenzo: Yes.
c00777
DM: As your turn ends-
c00778
Unknown: I'm moving pretty closer
c00779
Seeker: Same
c00780
DM: ... okay, um, the ooh- you see it moving stone out to the outside of the ooze.
c00781
DM: It hardens and protects itself.
c00782
Kenzo: From bludgeoning damage?
c00783
DM: It's, it switches resistance.
c00784
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
c00785
DM: So you just can't... So now it's not resistant to piercing, it is resistant to bludgeoning.
c00786
Kenzo: Oh, but I, I was doing... I can do force damage.
c00787
DM: Only with your punch, not with your staff.
c00788
Kenzo: No, I can do force damage with anything.
c00789
DM: Uh, when you make an unarmed strike you can switch it to force.
c00790
Kenzo: Okay, all right.
c00791
DM: Uh, but it doesn't matter, it just means you guys can't do the same damage type two rounds in a row.
c00792
Kenzo: Got it. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00793
DM: 'Cause it's reactive, not predictive.
c00794
Kenzo: Right.
c00795
Wellby: Does that make it complicated for the two of you?
c00796
Unknown: Well, we just really only have bludgeoning damage-
c00797
Delwath: We only can
c00798
Seeker: ... for leviathan attacks, but I can cast spells.
c00799
Delwath: Right. And I'm... I actually think as soon as I get up to it, I'm just gonna change into Delwath.
c00800
DM: Uh, so that ended, uh, Kenza's turn.
c00801
Delwath: I don't know if that's a good idea, but.
c00802
DM: It's going to use, uh...
c00803
DM: So how... Wait, how close are the leviathans?
c00804
Unknown: 120.
c00805
Seeker: Yeah, we've done two 40 foot moves.
c00806
DM: Okay.
c00807
DM: Um, uh, it is going to, um...
c00808
DM: Oh, huh, this isn't gonna do anything, but it doesn't know that.
c00809
DM: Um, it's going to, um, uh, r- reach out, like with a, a s-, a pseudo, a spray of ooze, um, to hit Kenzo.
c00810
DM: Uh, that is...
c00811
DM: Oh, that's only a 20 to hit, so it misses
c00812
Kenzo: It does miss.
c00813
Unknown: Ooh.
c00814
Kenzo: I have an AC of 24 now.
c00815
DM: That's its legendary action.
c00816
Kenzo: Nice.
c00817
DM: Now it's its turn.
c00818
DM: Uh, it is going to-
c00819
Kenzo: Come at me, bro
c00820
DM: ... s-
c00821
DM: s- uh, move forward, attempting to engulf Kenzo.
c00822
Unknown: Oh.
c00823
DM: Make a strength saving throw.
c00824
Unknown: Well, that's new.
c00825
Unknown: This one's got some different skills.
c00826
Seeker: The big one.
c00827
Kenzo: This one's got strength saving throw.
c00828
Unknown: Oh.
c00829
Kenzo: Uh-oh.
c00830
Kenzo: This is not good.
c00831
Delwath: Do our, um, breaths recharge?
c00832
Unknown: [die rolling] 20.
c00833
Kenzo: Oh.
c00834
DM: Oh my God.
c00835
Delwath: So you got a 19.
c00836
Kenzo: Huh?
c00837
DM: No, no, he's proficient.
c00838
Unknown: Ah.
c00839
DM: What's your total?
c00840
Kenzo: Huh? 20...
c00841
Kenzo: 25.
c00842
Unknown: 25.
c00843
DM: Okay, you succeed.
c00844
Unknown: Oh, 'cause 20's not good enough anymore.
c00845
Delwath: Uh, you can't.
c00846
Unknown: Oh.
c00847
Delwath: Saves don't have a crit success.
c00848
DM: Yeah, 20 doesn't automatically succeed on a save.
c00849
Delwath: Only, only attack rolls auto hit on a 20.
c00850
Kenzo: Wow. I think this is my first time ever making a strength save ever.
c00851
DM: [laughs]
c00852
Unknown: Probably. [laughs]
c00853
DM: Uh, so then it's gonna make two pseudopod attacks against you.
c00854
Kenzo: Kenzo, the true leviathan.
c00855
Unknown: Come at me. [die rolling]
c00856
DM: Uh, that's a natural one. That misses, and 28.
c00857
DM: That hits.
c00858
Kenzo: 28 hits.
c00859
DM: You take 24 points of force damage.
c00860
Seeker: Well, fuck you.
c00861
Kenzo: Um, no, yeah, no I don't.
c00862
Kenzo: I use my reaction.
c00863
DM: Okay.
c00864
Kenzo: Um, yeah, I automatically, uh, succeed.
c00865
DM: So Kenzo deflects.
c00866
Kenzo: Um, he has to roll a DC 20 dex.
c00867
Kenzo: [die rolling]
c00868
DM: Ah, that fails.
c00869
Kenzo: So it takes
c00870
Kenzo: 10, uh, it takes, uh, 17 more damage.
c00871
Kenzo: You try to hurt me instead of hurt yourself.
c00872
DM: Yep, so Kenzo ducks out of the way of two attacks.
c00873
Kenzo: Wait, it moved, it moved closer?
c00874
DM: It moved closer. It moved 30 feet closer.
c00875
Delwath: Okay. Wait, and I've moved twice, right?
c00876
Seeker: Yeah, we've moved
c00877
Unknown: 40 and 40 feet.
c00878
Kenzo: All right, guys. I've done 100, 100 damage.
c00879
Delwath: So 40, 40, plus 30, so it's 100.
c00880
DM: [coughs]
c00881
Delwath: So it's 80 feet away.
c00882
DM: [coughs]
c00883
Kenzo: 80 away.
c00884
Delwath: I'm gonna use... Its turn's over?
c00885
DM: Uh, its turn is over, yes.
c00886
Delwath: I'm using n- my last legendary-
c00887
DM: Oh, wait, hold on
c00888
Delwath: ... to move 40 closer so I'm 50 feet away.
c00889
DM: No, no, nope. Sorry, I forgot its bonus action.
c00890
DM: Um-
c00891
Wellby: The, the clearing is like 400 feet across then?
c00892
DM: [coughs] Uh,
c00893
DM: uh, it's going to also, um,
c00894
DM: eject slime at
c00895
DM: Kenzo.
c00896
Kenzo: Wait, is this its turn or is its, uh, its bonus action?
c00897
DM: It's still its bonus action on its turn, yeah.
c00898
Kenzo: On its turn, okay.
c00899
DM: Make a dex saving throw.
c00900
Kenzo: Come at me. [die rolling] What's that?
c00901
Unknown: Uh,
c00902
Unknown: 26.
c00903
DM: Okay. You dodged the slime.
c00904
Seeker: Nice.
c00905
DM: [coughs] So evasion, so you take no damage.
c00906
Kenzo: Kenzo versus slime. Let's go.
c00907
DM: So that ends its turn.
c00908
DM: Delweth is up next.
c00909
DM: I'm gonna have to track its hit points on a spreadsheet because it's too complicated.
c00910
Seeker: You can take a legend- leg- your third legendary before your turn, right?
c00911
DM: Yes.
c00912
Delwath: Yes. So I'm moving 40 feet closer with my third legendary.
c00913
Delwath: So it moved 30 and I moved,
c00914
Delwath: uh, 40... 120, so it's 50 feet away right now.
c00915
Seeker: Oh, we still can't close with it.
c00916
Delwath: Well, you can make your move.
c00917
Delwath: You're gonna be 10 feet away, so you can attack it but,
c00918
Unknown: um...
c00919
Delwath: Ooh, God, I can't decide what to do.
c00920
Kenzo: Um-
c00921
Seeker: It's resist- it's resistant to-
c00922
DM: Currently it's resistant to bludgeoning-
c00923
Unknown: Right
c00924
DM: ... and immune to acid and necrotic poison.
c00925
Delwath: It's like the leviathan can barely hurt it.
c00926
Seeker: So there's no other kind of damage you could do?
c00927
Delwath: I could turn into Delweth.
c00928
Kenzo: Hmm.
c00929
DM: This is a round with advantage.
c00930
Delwath: I'm really tempted to turn into Delweth.
c00931
Delwath: Ah, I'm gonna turn into Delweth.
c00932
Kenzo: Advantage is pretty great.
c00933
Delwath: I'm turning into Delweth.
c00934
Delwath: I'm 50 feet away. My speed is 60.
c00935
Delwath: Uh, my 10 pit points go away.
c00936
Kenzo: Oh.
c00937
Unknown: Um.
c00938
DM: Advantage would be awesome.
c00939
Delwath: And I'm gonna charge towards it as Delweth.
c00940
Delwath: Da, da, da, da, da.
c00941
Delwath: 50 feet move.
c00942
Delwath: I'll bonus action-
c00943
Kenzo: Crap
c00944
Delwath: ... I'll bonus action, um, um,
c00945
Delwath: explay, uh, Diaboli's Curse it.
c00946
DM: Okay.
c00947
Unknown: Um,
c00948
Delwath: uh, my weapon ignores resistance to slashing damage.
c00949
DM: Well, it's not currently resistant to slashing damage.
c00950
Delwath: I know. I'm just telling you.
c00951
DM: Yeah, I know.
c00952
Unknown: First attack.
c00953
Unknown: But you're the only one who does slashing damage-
c00954
Unknown: I know
c00955
DM: ... so it's never gonna be a problem for you.
c00956
Delwath: Uh, my first attack misses 'cause I can't roll above a five.
c00957
Kenzo: Ooh.
c00958
Delwath: I assume, uh,
c00959
Delwath: s- yeah, 17 misses.
c00960
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00961
Delwath: [die rolling] Second attack's better.
c00962
Delwath: That hits. [die rolling] And yeah.
c00963
Delwath: Third attack [die rolling] is much better.
c00964
Delwath: It crits. I'm gonna smite.
c00965
DM: Okay.
c00966
Kenzo: Nice. There we go.
c00967
DM: Yeah. Good move, good move.
c00968
Delwath: Um, so that is a total of one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12 D6 from the smite-
c00969
Kenzo: What?
c00970
Delwath: ... plus, 'cause I critted on a smite.
c00971
Delwath: Um, so 66 plus my regular...
c00972
Delwath: Uh, 68 plus my regular two D8.
c00973
Delwath: Critted aga- man, so the smite, the smite attack alone does
c00974
Delwath: 16 D8. [laughs] Cr- critting on a smite is pretty bad.
c00975
DM: Yeah, it's pretty good.
c00976
Delwath: Okay, so that's 16 D8.
c00977
DM: It's a good thing I gave it a lot of hit points.
c00978
Delwath: Uh, and then my other attack that hit is two D8.
c00979
Delwath: So that is 18 D8.
c00980
DM: Whoo.
c00981
Kenzo: Wow. You rolling on your phone?
c00982
Unknown: Yeah.
c00983
Kenzo: Dodging.
c00984
Delwath: That's too many D... I'm not adding that up.
c00985
DM: Yeah.
c00986
Delwath: That, that's the worst damage roll I've ever seen in my life.
c00987
Delwath: 79 damage on 18 D8.
c00988
Delwath: That's awful.
c00989
DM: So Delweth runs forward.
c00990
Delwath: Plus, plus 10,
c00991
Delwath: plus 26... uh, plus 22.
c00992
DM: Still-
c00993
Delwath: So it's still 101
c00994
Seeker: Not bad
c00995
Wellby: Some, some
c00996
Seeker: Three, three digit damage on one attack
c00997
Wellby: Yeah, yeah
c00998
DM: Yeah, Delwath runs forward and slashes three times at it, appearing as himself.
c00999
DM: At the end of your turn, it is going to, um, use its last legendary for this round to shoot a glob of slime at you.
c01000
DM: Dexterity saving throw for Delwath.
c01001
Delwath: Uh, 18.
c01002
DM: That fails.
c01003
Unknown: Um,
c01004
Delwath: I have Bardak. I think Bardak's a better-
c01005
Wellby: Just do it. Make it restraint
c01006
Delwath: ... 'cause it was like a, a-
c01007
Wellby: A glob of slime or a net of slime?
c01008
Unknown: Um, this one looks like a glob of slime
c01009
Unknown: No, I'm using-
c01010
Wellby: This quest will restrain you anyways.
c01011
Delwath: Ah, no, it's 28.
c01012
DM: 28 succeeds. You dodge out of the way.
c01013
DM: Uh, oh, you do still take nine points of acid damage,
c01014
DM: and the glob retracts into its body.
c01015
Unknown: Ah, shit.
c01016
DM: Uh, that ends Delwath's turn.
c01017
DM: Um,
c01018
DM: did Seeker use all his legendary actions?
c01019
Seeker: I've only used two, so my turn-
c01020
DM: So you can do one right before your turn.
c01021
DM: Your turn is next
c01022
Seeker: Yeah, my, my turn takes me another 40,
c01023
Seeker: so I'm also
c01024
Seeker: 10 feet away from it now, I think.
c01025
DM: Yep.
c01026
Unknown: Yeah.
c01027
Seeker: So I'm right up close.
c01028
Seeker: I could now
c01029
Unknown: either
c01030
Seeker: go for incapacitating it with Rune of Psychic Destruction
c01031
Unknown: which I'd save.
c01032
Seeker: and save or-
c01033
Delwath: It's a bump damage. It's above average.
c01034
Wellby: It wasn't as bad as I thought
c01035
Seeker: ... or I could try to dash and just, like, dive into the center of it.
c01036
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry, Mike. You did slashing damage to it, right?
c01037
Unknown: Slashing, yeah.
c01038
DM: Um, acid erupts in the wound.
c01039
DM: You take six points of acid damage.
c01040
DM: The first time you hit it each round,
c01041
DM: I'll roll differently
c01042
Delwath: Okay.
c01043
Delwath: Uh, is that, uh...
c01044
Delwath: I'm 10 feet away.
c01045
DM: Yeah, you're within 60 feet-
c01046
Unknown: Okay
c01047
DM: ... so the acid spray still hits it.
c01048
Unknown: Yeah.
c01049
DM: Do what?
c01050
Seeker: I was thinking about trying to i- incapacitate it with Rune of Psychic Destruction-
c01051
DM: Yeah
c01052
Seeker: ... versus just dash and, like, dive.
c01053
DM: Just don't waste a high level spell slot while it still has all its legendary resistances.
c01054
Wellby: Oh, right.
c01055
Unknown: Right, so I-
c01056
DM: It's a good thing to try and force it to save, 'cause it's bad at end
c01057
Unknown: Yeah. Mm.
c01058
Seeker: So, so I shouldn't just di- dive for this as well?
c01059
DM: No, I'm just saying don't, like, burn your eighth level slot on a Rune of Psychic Destruction-
c01060
Unknown: Yeah
c01061
DM: ... when it's going to use a legendary if it fails.
c01062
Seeker: So I can use a much lower...
c01063
Seeker: I can use a fourth level on Psychic Destruction
c01064
DM: It's a strong effect, 'cause if it fails the save, it's gotta burn a legendary resistance.
c01065
DM: Being incapacitated is really bad.
c01066
Kenzo: All right. So yeah, I will do the Psychic Destruction.
c01067
Wellby: Nice. It's immune to exhaustion
c01068
DM: It's immune to exhaustion
c01069
Seeker: And to save, you can empty.
c01070
DM: Uh,
c01071
DM: it burns a legendary resistance.
c01072
Wellby: Nice.
c01073
Seeker: Nice. And then I can use my move still to go onto it, right?
c01074
DM: Yep.
c01075
Unknown: On the ooze.
c01076
DM: Okay.
c01077
Unknown: And then-
c01078
DM: That ends Seeker's turn. Wellby is up.
c01079
Wellby: Uh, oh
c01080
DM: Sorry, actually, one sec.
c01081
DM: So-
c01082
Seeker: I was gonna maybe do the concert idea. Let me do it next.
c01083
Unknown: Next turn, yeah
c01084
DM: So at the start of the round,
c01085
DM: I'm gonna do a little recap at the beginning of each round.
c01086
DM: It's 'cause it's hard to track with the battle map not being perfect.
c01087
DM: So Wellby is still 180 feet away, or 170 feet away from it on the edge of the battlefield, aiming with his bow, while Kenzo has just dodged
c01088
DM: out of the way of its attempt to engulf him.
c01089
DM: Delwath is on the other side of the front, 10 feet away from it, and Seeker has just dived towards the middle of the goop.
c01090
DM: And we will see what happens.
c01091
DM: [laughs]
c01092
Wellby: It's probably be fine. It's not, uh, it's not, uh, resistant to piercing anymore, right?
c01093
DM: Nope. It's now resis- it's currently still resistant to sl-
c01094
Wellby: Slashing
c01095
DM: ... slashing 'cause that's the last damage it took.
c01096
Wellby: Oh. Yeah.
c01097
Wellby: Yeah. Okay. So I will shoot it.
c01098
Kenzo: So what's the thing where you shoot it and then we get advantage?
c01099
Kenzo: Why, what, what
c01100
DM: That's only the first round
c01101
Kenzo: What effect does that have?
c01102
DM: It's a rogue s- it's a scout rogue ability.
c01103
Wellby: Uh, Second Strike or something like that.
c01104
Kenzo: Yeah. That's awesome.
c01105
Kenzo: I love having advantage.
c01106
Wellby: Uh, 20-
c01107
Unknown: I know
c01108
Wellby: ... 3 at least.
c01109
DM: 23 hits, yes.
c01110
Wellby: Uh, all right. And all the damage is...
c01111
Wellby: [dice rolling] Uh, okay.
c01112
Wellby: 10, 15, 29, 32, 40.
c01113
Wellby: 40.
c01114
DM: 40 piercing?
c01115
Wellby: Yep.
c01116
DM: Uh, so as you expect, as the arrow hits, it, um...
c01117
DM: Oh, sorry, that's gonna be at the end of your turn.
c01118
Wellby: With the advantage, yeah [laughs]
c01119
DM: If you want to do another attack, it won't be resistant to it
c01120
Wellby: Another attack.
c01121
Wellby: Uh, something like 30.
c01122
Wellby: [die rolling] Uh, another 12 points of piercing.
c01123
Wellby: Yeah.
c01124
DM: Okay.
c01125
Wellby: That's me.
c01126
DM: Um, it is going to use, at the end of your turn, it's going to use a legendary resistance.
c01127
DM: I mean, a legendary... Well, first it's...
c01128
DM: Sorry, not a legendary resistance. It again becomes this sort of gloopy mess, resistant to piercing.
c01129
DM: It's gonna use a legendary action
c01130
DM: to, let's see, use that one.
c01131
DM: Uh,
c01132
DM: it will try that one on...
c01133
DM: You're out of range, so it'll try that on Delwath.
c01134
DM: Um, it reaches out to hit you.
c01135
DM: [die rolling] 60 foot reach.
c01136
DM: Uh,
c01137
DM: whoops, I didn't mean to roll advantage, but a 24.
c01138
Unknown: That's shield.
c01139
DM: Okay.
c01140
DM: So that misses. That's its legendary action.
c01141
DM: Uh, Kenzo is up.
c01142
Unknown: All right.
c01143
Unknown: Kenzo is gonna-
c01144
Wellby: Oh, can I...
c01145
DM: You can legendary action
c01146
Seeker: Yeah, go, do it. I'm just g- so should I bludgeon...
c01147
Seeker: Should I slam attack or should I just...
c01148
Seeker: No, I should probably-
c01149
DM: No
c01150
Seeker: ... attack it so it doesn't attack me and then just use-
c01151
DM: No, but don't bludgeon because then-
c01152
Unknown: Right, but that can't, yeah
c01153
DM: ... it'll be resistant to Kenzo's attacks.
c01154
Seeker: So with my move, can I try to, like, tunnel into it?
c01155
Unknown: Sure
c01156
Unknown: Right?
c01157
Delwath: I mean, well, if I think and move up to move through other creatures and up the space of one inch.
c01158
DM: Make a s- make a strength check.
c01159
Unknown: Yeah.
c01160
Unknown: Well, if I think-
c01161
DM: Or athle- well, yeah.
c01162
Unknown: No, it's-
c01163
DM: Athletics, but it's just straight strength
c01164
Seeker: 27 strength.
c01165
Unknown: Plus eight.
c01166
c01167
Seeker: [dice rolling] That's a 21.
c01168
DM: Um, you, you push your way through it a little bit.
c01169
Unknown: [squelching]
c01170
DM: Like,
c01171
DM: it's, it's currently a little bit gloopy 'cause it's, like, thinned itself out to be resistant to piercing damage.
c01172
Seeker: Amazing.
c01173
DM: So you-
c01174
Seeker: So how are you doing it [laughs]?
c01175
DM: You tunnel 40 feet in, so you're-
c01176
Seeker: Well, am I swimming in the ooze?
c01177
Unknown: 'Cause that's [laughs] only 20 foot.
c01178
DM: Mm.
c01179
Unknown: [laughs]
c01180
DM: I'll say it's swimming, but it counts as difficult terrain, so you can move 60 feet.
c01181
Seeker: Amazing. I'm going straight down.
c01182
DM: So you, you still have 100...
c01183
DM: You still have 200 feet, or 200 feet of ooze to cross before you even get to the part that goes down.
c01184
Kenzo: Oh, okay. So-
c01185
DM: So you're 140 feet from the sinkhole.
c01186
Delwath: So you're about... And the sinkhole is, like, 40 feet we think, or 30 feet.
c01187
DM: The sinkhole is, like, 40 feet deep.
c01188
Delwath: So you're, you're 160 feet from it.
c01189
Unknown: [laughs]
c01190
Kenzo: No, you know what, though? You know what, though?
c01191
Seeker: Come with me, guys.
c01192
Kenzo: No, but if he gets, like, to where we need to go-
c01193
Unknown: [laughs]
c01194
Kenzo: ... I wonder if he can dimension door or just teleport us right to the, the, you know.
c01195
Unknown: That's insane.
c01196
Kenzo: Like, you know what I'm saying? Like, once you get there.
c01197
Wellby: Well, you can keep moving with your other legendary actions.
c01198
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, keep go. Next action.
c01199
DM: Yeah, it's Kenzo's turn now.
c01200
Unknown: Yeah.
c01201
Kenzo: Yeah.
c01202
Unknown: Yeah.
c01203
Kenzo: But keep going in there.
c01204
Unknown: [laughs]
c01205
Kenzo: Let's see what's-
c01206
Unknown: Just, just go for it
c01207
Kenzo: ... yeah, let's see what's at the heart of this thing.
c01208
Unknown: [laughs]
c01209
Kenzo: This is cool. I like this.
c01210
Kenzo: This is, this is, this is
c01211
Kenzo: really weird and awesome.
c01212
Seeker: Yeah. This, this leviathan thing is really cool.
c01213
Kenzo: Yeah, the leviathan tunneling into the middle of the ooze.
c01214
DM: Seeker much prefers to be a leviathan [laughs] than a dragon.
c01215
Kenzo: Yeah.
c01216
Delwath: I mean, it helps to pick something that's immune to the primary damage type.
c01217
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah.
c01218
Delwath: But it's throwing force now. You will take the force damage.
c01219
Kenzo: Um.
c01220
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c01221
Delwath: But, again, unless you take 22, you can't fail the...
c01222
Unknown: Yeah.
c01223
Kenzo: Okay. So I'm gonna-
c01224
Unknown: I'll s- like, attack the body
c01225
Kenzo: ... attack a lot. I don't have advantage anymore, right?
c01226
DM: You don't have advantage anymore, no.
c01227
Kenzo: Okay. First staff attack, uh, 24 hits.
c01228
DM: Yep.
c01229
Kenzo: Actually, I'll do these all together.
c01230
Unknown: Yeah.
c01231
Kenzo: Uh.
c01232
Delwath: No, just roll the staff attack and then roll the-
c01233
Kenzo: Yeah. The second staff attack. Oh, great.
c01234
Unknown: Nice.
c01235
Kenzo: Holy shit.
c01236
DM: Good job.
c01237
Kenzo: Great. And then, um, three unarmed strikes.
c01238
Kenzo: Here.
c01239
Kenzo: Um, [dice rolling] uh, plus 13, so-
c01240
Unknown: 19 will miss.
c01241
DM: 19 misses. And-
c01242
Kenzo: Everything else hits
c01243
Delwath: So it's 20.
c01244
Kenzo: 22 hits.
c01245
Unknown: 22 hits.
c01246
DM: 22 hits.
c01247
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So,
c01248
Kenzo: oh, fuck. How do we calculate this?
c01249
Delwath: Is it your first attack?
c01250
DM: The, the first attack that hits.
c01251
DM: The, you can't... Yeah.
c01252
Delwath: Yeah, it's the first attack that hits.
c01253
DM: Yeah.
c01254
Delwath: So it's, uh, 2d, it's 4d 12,
c01255
Delwath: plus two more, so 6d 12.
c01256
DM: 6d 12 plus...
c01257
Unknown: 6d 12 plus-
c01258
Delwath: Plus 18 plus 14
c01259
Kenzo: 18 plus 14, yeah.
c01260
DM: Yeah. [laughs] Jesus. Okay.
c01261
DM: Well, I'm calculating this with a spreadsheet, so 18, 14, just tell me what the 6d 12 are.
c01262
Kenzo: Okay. So 6d 1, 2, 3, 4...
c01263
Kenzo: Wait, is somewhere.
c01264
DM: Yeah, that should be 20. That's a 12.
c01265
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c01266
Kenzo: [dice rolling] Okay. If, uh...
c01267
Kenzo: Oh, this is noth- oh, this is terrible.
c01268
DM: That's a terrible roll.
c01269
Kenzo: Yeah.
c01270
Kenzo: 10, 20, 24.
c01271
DM: Okay.
c01272
Kenzo: 24 plus-
c01273
DM: Yep
c01274
Delwath: ... how much?
c01275
DM: I got it. I got it. 24 plus 18 plus 14.
c01276
Kenzo: Okay.
c01277
DM: I just, I just have a spreadsheet-
c01278
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah
c01279
DM: ... that's subtracting its hit points-
c01280
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah
c01281
DM: ... 'cause it's too complicated in here. Ah, Seeker, from inside you feel as it hardens to stone, this, like, to be resistant to bludgeoning damage, this m- this, like, tight
c01282
DM: mesh kind of traps itself around you.
c01283
Kenzo: Ugh.
c01284
Seeker: Am I... Can I use my legendary action to keep him in the ooze?
c01285
Unknown: [laughs]
c01286
DM: Uh.
c01287
Unknown: [coughs]
c01288
DM: Y- you can try. But first it gets to use its last legendary action for this round.
c01289
Unknown: Mm.
c01290
DM: Um, sorry, for its, its round one.
c01291
Delwath: You should be able to, like, try and punch through with your-
c01292
Unknown: Yeah
c01293
Unknown: ... super strength.
c01294
Kenzo: Leviathan strength.
c01295
DM: Uh, it's...
c01296
DM: Yes. It's just, it's easier to move through depending on what it's resistant to.
c01297
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. It, yeah.
c01298
DM: Um, so it's gonna use its legendary first,
c01299
DM: um, and it is going to, uh,
c01300
DM: try
c01301
DM: the
c01302
DM: corrupting touch on Kenzo again.
c01303
DM: [dice rolling]
c01304
DM: That's total crap.
c01305
DM: That's a 30-something to hit.
c01306
Kenzo: Okay, that hits.
c01307
DM: Um, you take-
c01308
DM: I'm fine. You can't be corrupted
c01309
DM: ... 23 points of poison damage.
c01310
Unknown: I have?
c01311
Unknown: No you don't
c01312
DM: ... whi- which you're resistant to.
c01313
Unknown: I-
c01314
DM: And you are poisoned, which you are immune to, so it does nothing to you.
c01315
Kenzo: Well, but also 23, I'm gonna use my reaction.
c01316
Unknown: 23.
c01317
Kenzo: And, um, I should be good.
c01318
DM: Yeah, you just got reaction back.
c01319
DM: So you take no damage.
c01320
DM: It's really not doing well attacking Kenzo.
c01321
Kenzo: With a DC 20. [dice rolling]
c01322
DM: It, uh, that it passed.
c01323
Unknown: Okay.
c01324
DM: So now it's Seeker legendary action.
c01325
Seeker: I will try to fight through, keep moving.
c01326
DM: Strength, strength check.
c01327
DM: Higher DC this time. [dice rolling]
c01328
Kenzo: Nice.
c01329
Seeker: So that's a 22.
c01330
DM: A 22? Okay.
c01331
DM: You push your way through.
c01332
Unknown: Leviathan.
c01333
DM: Uh, this...
c01334
Unknown: [laughs]
c01335
DM: Yeah. I, um, this is, like, twice difficult terrain now, so you move 30 feet.
c01336
Unknown: 30, okay.
c01337
DM: You need to get back to piercing.
c01338
DM: That's the easiest to swim through.
c01339
DM: Uh-
c01340
Seeker: I, I'll let you know [laughs]
c01341
DM: ... now it's its turn.
c01342
Unknown: Piercing, piercing.
c01343
DM: It is going to move forward and attempt to engulf Kenzo and Delwath.
c01344
Unknown: Oh, no.
c01345
DM: Strength saves from both of you.
c01346
Kenzo: Oh no, I hate this.
c01347
Unknown: [laughs]
c01348
Unknown: I hate this.
c01349
Delwath: Well, I have ways to get out of this once we-
c01350
Seeker: I, I engulfed myself, guys. It's not so bad.
c01351
DM: Uh-
c01352
Unknown: I hate this. Yeah
c01353
DM: ... your turn hasn't started yet, Del, since you dived into it.
c01354
Kenzo: Oh, 21.
c01355
Seeker: What's that? No, I'm just saying, they're tr-
c01356
Unknown: Three
c01357
Seeker: ... he's, it's trying to engulf them. I'm like, that's-
c01358
DM: Uh, both of those fail.
c01359
Kenzo: Uh, I will re-roll.
c01360
Unknown: That's very smart.
c01361
DM: Okay.
c01362
Kenzo: Spend a ki to try to re-roll.
c01363
Kenzo: Fuck, I need to get even higher than a 16.
c01364
Unknown: Shit.
c01365
DM: Uh, you are... Delwath is engulfed.
c01366
DM: [dice rolling]
c01367
Delwath: What does being engulfed mean?
c01368
Seeker: 15.
c01369
Unknown: 15 is what I was-
c01370
Unknown: 20.
c01371
Unknown: 16.
c01372
DM: You are also engulfed.
c01373
Unknown: Oh, no.
c01374
DM: You are, you have total cover from attacks and other effects outside the ooze, and it moves you with it, and then you'll see what else happen.
c01375
DM: Oh, and you're- Suffocating and restrained
c01376
Seeker: Oh, God. What does that mean?
c01377
DM: Disadvantage on all attacks
c01378
Seeker: And you can see Leviathan swimming inside the ooze
c01379
DM: Uh,
c01380
DM: and that ends its turn. Delwath is up.
c01381
DM: Uh, you take-
c01382
Wellby: Leviathan
c01383
Kenzo: Wait, can I be res- can I be res- restrained as a, as a natural being?
c01384
DM: Yeah.
c01385
Unknown: Can-
c01386
DM: It doesn't say you're immune to restraint
c01387
Kenzo: I can pass through objects and creatures, except barriers of magical force, as if they were difficult terrain
c01388
DM: Uh, Delwath takes 22 points of force damage.
c01389
Delwath: Okay. Hold on one second. I'm just trying to look at one thing.
c01390
Delwath: Um, okay, 22 points of force damage and I...
c01391
Delwath: Wait, I have disadvantage on attacks?
c01392
DM: Yep
c01393
Unknown: Um,
c01394
Unknown: uh,
c01395
Unknown: okay. But
c01396
Delwath: I turn into a cloud immune to restraint.
c01397
DM: Yep
c01398
Delwath: Okay. So I use a metamagic to bonus action
c01399
Delwath: transform. Delwath transforms into, like, a cloud of, like,
c01400
Delwath: some kind of, like, maybe like a water creature of some...
c01401
Delwath: A little water insect of some kind.
c01402
Delwath: Uh, which, um-
c01403
Seeker: You turn into a tiny cloud of tiny bugs
c01404
Delwath: A cloud of tiny bugs. You've seen Delwath do this before
c01405
Unknown: Mm-hmm
c01406
Delwath: ... uh, which is immune to restraint, so I presumably no longer restrained.
c01407
Unknown: Yep
c01408
Delwath: And then I can move to the outside of it.
c01409
DM: Uh, yep.
c01410
Delwath: Okay. So I...
c01411
Delwath: That's my bonus action.
c01412
Delwath: Now I'm outside it and I will attack it.
c01413
Delwath: I'll be 20 feet away.
c01414
Delwath: Uh, oh, wait, how much damage did you say?
c01415
Unknown: 22?
c01416
Delwath: 22 points of force.
c01417
Delwath: Uh, 24
c01418
DM: Uh, 24 hits.
c01419
Unknown: Uh,
c01420
Unknown: 22
c01421
DM: That hits
c01422
Delwath: And higher than either of those.
c01423
Delwath: Uh, one, two, three, four, five, six.
c01424
Delwath: So that is 32 damage plus
c01425
Delwath: 15 plus 18.
c01426
DM: 32 plus 15 plus 18?
c01427
Delwath: Yep. Three attacks.
c01428
Delwath: I used my bonus action.
c01429
Delwath: I used a quicken metamagic-
c01430
DM: So that ends-
c01431
Unknown: ... which costs me a lot
c01432
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry, I forgot.
c01433
DM: It was bonus action.
c01434
DM: Um,
c01435
Unknown: uh, I'm gonna-
c01436
Unknown: Um
c01437
DM: ... just run it as a legendary.
c01438
Delwath: I'm gonna smite it also
c01439
DM: Okay
c01440
Wellby: Do Tasha's Hideous Laughter incapacitates?
c01441
Seeker: I mean, I have wish.
c01442
Delwath: That's 30 more damage.
c01443
DM: Okay
c01444
Seeker: Is that 100?
c01445
DM: Uh, so it also-
c01446
Wellby: But it incapacitates
c01447
DM: Uh-
c01448
Unknown: I see.
c01449
Seeker: Yeah, th- that's what I was going for with second
c01450
DM: Sleep also incapacitates
c01451
Wellby: Sleep still work with the hit die or no?
c01452
Delwath: Nah, it's... Now it's just an incapacitate save
c01453
DM: So, um, Wellby, make a dexterity saving throw.
c01454
Delwath: So I need to use my bonus action-
c01455
DM: As another glob of acid flies towards you
c01456
Delwath: ... to escape on this turn.
c01457
Delwath: But if I-
c01458
Wellby: Uh, uh, 20
c01459
DM: Fails
c01460
Wellby: Huh. [laughs]
c01461
DM: You want to do something? Do you have anything you can do?
c01462
Wellby: I... No, I've burned the heroic. I've burned the bardic.
c01463
DM: Okay.
c01464
DM: Uh, you take...
c01465
DM: Ooh, why isn't that working? Uh,
c01466
DM: I'm gonna have to roll this manually.
c01467
DM: Sorry, 10 D10 takes a while.
c01468
DM: Uh, you take 10, 19-
c01469
Unknown: Oh
c01470
DM: ...
c01471
DM: uh,
c01472
DM: 29, 31
c01473
DM: plus seven-
c01474
Wellby: That's lovely
c01475
DM: ... so 40.
c01476
DM: 57 points of acid damage.
c01477
Wellby: Is this a uncanny dodge sort of a thing?
c01478
DM: No, it's a saving throw
c01479
Wellby: All right
c01480
DM: And you are dragged, uh,
c01481
DM: 60 feet closer towards the ooze.
c01482
Wellby: Awesome
c01483
DM: So you are now-
c01484
Wellby: 110
c01485
DM: ... 110 feet away.
c01486
DM: Uh, no, it moved 30 feet on its turn, so you're now-
c01487
Unknown: 80
c01488
DM: ... 80 feet away.
c01489
Wellby: Got it.
c01490
DM: Um, and it is now gonna use...
c01491
DM: That was actually a bonus action on its turn, which I forgot.
c01492
DM: So after Delwath's turn, it's using a legendary action to crush those inside it.
c01493
Seeker: Oh no, me and Kenza.
c01494
DM: [laughs]
c01495
Wellby: Good
c01496
DM: Uh, make a strength saving throw.
c01497
Wellby: Tim, I'm pulled closer but not grappled or restrained
c01498
DM: But not grappled or restrained, no
c01499
Wellby: So it's fine
c01500
Seeker: That's, uh, 23.
c01501
Unknown: 23.
c01502
Unknown: Sure.
c01503
Unknown: It's a critical.
c01504
DM: Uh,
c01505
Delwath: both of you rolled a 23?
c01506
Delwath: No, you rolled a 23. I have a-
c01507
DM: Oh, 23 succeeds
c01508
Unknown: Something really high.
c01509
Kenzo: Uh, it's not high enough. 17.
c01510
DM: 17-
c01511
Kenzo: I'm, I'm gonna reroll
c01512
DM: Okay.
c01513
Unknown: Uh, it didn't help
c01514
DM: So 17 fails, so, um...
c01515
DM: Ugh, why isn't this dice roller working?
c01516
DM: Okay. Uh,
c01517
DM: Kenza takes 31 points of force damage.
c01518
DM: Um, you take half that.
c01519
Unknown: So-
c01520
DM: So 15
c01521
Unknown: ...
c01522
Unknown: 15.
c01523
DM: Uh, and that's its legendary, so Seeker is up.
c01524
Unknown: Ugh.
c01525
Unknown: Down to 306. [laughs]
c01526
Delwath: Plus Seeker hit points
c01527
Seeker: Yeah. [laughs] Well, it would be bad to be back to Seeker.
c01528
Seeker: I'd be inside the ooze, so.
c01529
Unknown: True
c01530
Unknown: Um,
c01531
Seeker: oh, I can use my...
c01532
Seeker: Crap, do I have another legendary?
c01533
Seeker: I think I do.
c01534
Seeker: I think I used two already.
c01535
Unknown: Yeah
c01536
DM: You used two, so you can use one more-
c01537
DM: At the, at the-
c01538
DM: ... at the end of Delwath's
c01539
Unknown: ...
c01540
Delwath: move, move towards it. Move inside it, right?
c01541
Seeker: Yeah, I keep moving as much as possible
c01542
DM: Okay, so another strength check.
c01543
Seeker: How far away is this, this...
c01544
Unknown: Oh
c01545
Seeker: ... natural one
c01546
DM: You do not move any further
c01547
Wellby: All right
c01548
Seeker: Okay. And then on my turn...
c01549
Delwath: How many... It's burned one legendary?
c01550
DM: You've burned one legendary resistance, yeah
c01551
Kenzo: Yeah, make it do some other unsavvy things
c01552
Seeker: Versus just trying to move a lot more
c01553
DM: And wait, Dal- you were the last one to attack it.
c01554
Unknown: Yes, I did.
c01555
DM: So it's currently immune to slashing.
c01556
Unknown: Currently what?
c01557
DM: Immune to slashing, or resistant to slashing.
c01558
Unknown: Hmm.
c01559
Unknown: There's some other stuff it could use.
c01560
DM: I mean-
c01561
Seeker: No, I'll just, I'll just do psychic disruption again.
c01562
DM: Okay.
c01563
Unknown: Uh, so yeah.
c01564
DM: That fails again.
c01565
Unknown: Fourth one.
c01566
DM: Oh wait, it hasn't been.
c01567
DM: Uh, oh no, that's gonna succeed.
c01568
Unknown: No.
c01569
DM: 21.
c01570
DM: Wait, 21. What's your d...
c01571
DM: It's-
c01572
Unknown: 19.
c01573
DM: Okay, so it succeeds.
c01574
Delwath: Yeah. Dope.
c01575
Delwath: So you can still use your move to move.
c01576
Seeker: Yes, I use my move to move.
c01577
DM: Yeah. So another strength check.
c01578
Unknown: 16.
c01579
DM: Yeah, that's fine.
c01580
Unknown: So you move 60 further?
c01581
Delwath: 60 further, yeah.
c01582
Unknown: Okay.
c01583
Seeker: So now on the track.
c01584
Delwath: You should just write down on the-
c01585
DM: Just keep track on the...
c01586
DM: You, I think you were a hundred and tw-
c01587
Delwath: You were a hundred and... You were, you were-
c01588
DM: You had moved 90 feet.
c01589
Unknown: Yeah.
c01590
DM: So you move another... You moved 150 feet.
c01591
Unknown: [gasps]
c01592
DM: So you're 50 feet from the sinkhole now.
c01593
Unknown: Right.
c01594
Unknown: Okay.
c01595
DM: Um, that ends Seeker's turn.
c01596
DM: It will use another legendary resistance.
c01597
DM: It already did the-
c01598
Unknown: Action
c01599
DM: ... sorry, action. It already did the force crush.
c01600
DM: Uh,
c01601
DM: Delwath is just standing outside there.
c01602
DM: It's gonna pseudopod hit you.
c01603
DM: That's a 30.
c01604
Unknown: Okay.
c01605
DM: Uh, that is going to be 21 points of force damage.
c01606
Unknown: Okay.
c01607
DM: Um,
c01608
DM: Wellby is up, so as the round begins, now Kenzo is being slowly crushed inside the blob.
c01609
DM: Seeker is-
c01610
Wellby: Charging
c01611
DM: ... charging through the blob.
c01612
DM: Um,
c01613
DM: Wellby is-
c01614
Wellby: Wellby moves back to I think 170 is now the furthest distance away-
c01615
DM: Okay
c01616
Wellby: ... that I can get. And shoots.
c01617
Unknown: Nice.
c01618
Seeker: Safety first, Wellby.
c01619
Unknown: Yeah. Safety first indeed.
c01620
DM: Mm-hmm.
c01621
Wellby: Uh, that's a hit.
c01622
Delwath: Wait, what did we... We know its AC is 22, right?
c01623
Delwath: Or at least not higher than 22.
c01624
Unknown: 22.
c01625
DM: Not higher than 22. A 22 hits.
c01626
Wellby: Okay. Yeah.
c01627
Unknown: Okay.
c01628
DM: A 20... I don't think anybody's rolled a 21.
c01629
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c01630
DM: A 20 misses.
c01631
Wellby: Okay. For 42.
c01632
DM: 42 piercing?
c01633
Wellby: Yep. Second attack,
c01634
Wellby: uh, also hits.
c01635
Wellby: Uh, nine piercing.
c01636
Kenzo: Piercing plus b- Pushen's bonus, I guess.
c01637
Unknown: Yeah.
c01638
DM: Yep.
c01639
DM: Uh, that ends Wellby's turn. It will use its last legendary action for this round
c01640
DM: to,
c01641
DM: uh-
c01642
Kenzo: Wait, isn't this the beginning of-
c01643
DM: Its legend is reset-
c01644
Unknown: On its turn
c01645
DM: ... on, on its turn.
c01646
Unknown: Oh, I see. Okay. Yeah, yeah.
c01647
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah.
c01648
DM: Um, it is going to,
c01649
DM: uh...
c01650
DM: It did crush, it did pseudopod.
c01651
DM: It's gonna... Uh, how far did you s- you were 170 away?
c01652
Wellby: Uh, feet, yeah.
c01653
DM: Okay. It can't reach you, so it's gonna shoot at Delwath.
c01654
Wellby: My strategy's working.
c01655
DM: Uh, dex saving throw.
c01656
DM: Wait, how long does the butterflies last?
c01657
Delwath: Oh, it lasts till the, till...
c01658
Delwath: It lasts for, for-
c01659
DM: Just for your turn?
c01660
Delwath: I think it lasts for just my turn.
c01661
DM: So are you current... You're not currently immune to restraint, are you?
c01662
Delwath: Not anymore.
c01663
DM: Okay. What is your dex save?
c01664
Delwath: Uh, six, but plus something, but it's not gonna succeed.
c01665
DM: Okay. Uh-
c01666
Unknown: It might...
c01667
Delwath: Heroic.
c01668
Unknown: Yeah.
c01669
Kenzo: You don't want to be restrained.
c01670
Delwath: I mean, I can get out again, but it's annoying.
c01671
Unknown: Yeah.
c01672
Unknown: Dope.
c01673
DM: Uh, you take 16 points of acid damage, and it
c01674
DM: sucks you into itself.
c01675
DM: So you're engulfed again.
c01676
Delwath: [laughs] Delwath just kind of frowns at it, like, "Wait a minute."
c01677
DM: Uh, Kenzo's up.
c01678
Seeker: Oh, and I'll move again.
c01679
DM: Uh, yes. So now it's easy DC and you can move 60 feet 'cause it's resistant to piercing.
c01680
Unknown: Do I have to roll?
c01681
DM: No, you still have to roll, but it's easy.
c01682
Unknown: That's a 24.
c01683
DM: Yeah, that succeeds.
c01684
Seeker: So now I'm at the sinkhole 'cause I was 50 away, and then I can move 10 more straight down.
c01685
DM: Yep.
c01686
DM: So you're now 30 feet away from the
c01687
DM: top. 10, 19.
c01688
Seeker: It's 30 away from the thing.
c01689
DM: 25. From, sorry, from the bottom.
c01690
Unknown: Okay. There.
c01691
DM: 25, 28. Kenzo, at the start of your turn you take 28 points of force damage.
c01692
Unknown: What?
c01693
Unknown: 28?
c01694
DM: Yep.
c01695
Kenzo: So how far, uh-
c01696
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry, Eric, did I...
c01697
DM: At the start of your turn, did I tell you how much force damage you took?
c01698
Unknown: No.
c01699
Unknown: Didn't I roll a save?
c01700
DM: That was the first legendary action.
c01701
Unknown: Right.
c01702
DM: You also take force damage if you start your turn inside it.
c01703
Seeker: Oh, okay. Okay. No, yeah.
c01704
DM: Uh, okay. So 22 for you.
c01705
Unknown: 22.
c01706
Seeker: Down below 300, guys.
c01707
DM: That's rough.
c01708
Unknown: [laughs]
c01709
DM: Okay.
c01710
Delwath: Delwath's kind of questioning his life choices that led him to not being a leviathan.
c01711
Delwath: [laughs]
c01712
DM: [laughs]
c01713
Unknown: Yeah.
c01714
Unknown: Leviathan.
c01715
Unknown: How many, um-
c01716
DM: Oh, wait, sorry. You're immune to the restrained condition, so that's why you didn't take force damage.
c01717
DM: It can only do force damage to you if it intentionally squeezes.
c01718
DM: You don't take force damage just from being inside.
c01719
Unknown: Oh. Yeah. So add them back.
c01720
DM: 'Cause you're immune to restraint.
c01721
Seeker: So I add 22 back? Yeah.
c01722
DM: Yeah.
c01723
Kenzo: How many feet am I away from, like, escaping?
c01724
Unknown: Oh, it can work.
c01725
DM: Ah.
c01726
Unknown: That's fine.
c01727
Kenzo: 'Cause it engulfed me.
c01728
DM: So you're, you're still-
c01729
Delwath: It's not important though. We probably just have to edit it to 284-
c01730
DM: Uh, you're still like, you're restrained.
c01731
DM: You need to, you need to make the strength saving throw to be unrestrained before you can escape.
c01732
Kenzo: I need to make a strength sp- saving throw?
c01733
Kenzo: Even, even if I'm a, if, uh, an astral construct?
c01734
DM: Yeah. It has like, it's a n- like network of this stuff that's like grappled around you.
c01735
Unknown: Um, the ghostly form does not make you immune to the restraint.
c01736
DM: I mean, it... Things can still stop your movement and you're restrained.
c01737
Kenzo: And I'm a... Is this, is it, is it just a regular strength save or is it at disadvantage?
c01738
DM: No, just reg- it's a strength save.
c01739
DM: You don't have disadvantage on str- 'cause you just need to, you just need to break through this, these filaments and then you can-
c01740
Unknown: Yeah
c01741
DM: ... s- fly out because of your, um-
c01742
Kenzo: I- is it, uh... Also, is it the case that, um,
c01743
Kenzo: um, to try to escape, is that a bose- bonus action to move or is it something I could just, I just try?
c01744
DM: You just automatically get a strength save at the end of every turn to, like, bust the-
c01745
Kenzo: But it's at the end of the turn?
c01746
DM: It's at the end of your turn.
c01747
Kenzo: Okay.
c01748
DM: I mean, you could, if you wanted to use your action to attempt to escape, you could also use your action to make a strength save.
c01749
Kenzo: So, so I could do twice?
c01750
DM: You could do it twice, but you use your whole action if you do that.
c01751
DM: It's-
c01752
Kenzo: Well, but I mean, I'm stuck here right now.
c01753
DM: Well, you could, you could still attack it.
c01754
Kenzo: You can attack with it
c01755
DM: ... you're inside.
c01756
Kenzo: Yeah, but that's, that's not... 'Cause I'm also getting crushed every round that I'm in here.
c01757
DM: Yes.
c01758
Kenzo: The only, the only type of damage that I'm not resistant to is force damage.
c01759
DM: Mm-hmm.
c01760
Kenzo: So this is like not a good place for me to be.
c01761
Kenzo: Okay, uh, I'm gonna bonus action, um, drink the potion of speed just-
c01762
DM: Okay
c01763
Kenzo: ... 'cause why the fuck not?
c01764
Kenzo: Um, so now-
c01765
Delwath: Oh, 'cause then you could do one attack
c01766
Kenzo: ... bonus action.
c01767
Wellby: Yeah. Or you could try and-
c01768
Kenzo: I can try, I can try to escape three times.
c01769
Unknown: Yeah.
c01770
DM: No. C- the hasted action can, can only be used for a few limited things, right?
c01771
Delwath: But, but utilize is one of them.
c01772
Delwath: I would argue that counts.
c01773
DM: Yeah, that probably d- Let me just look at haste for one sec.
c01774
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah. It would be like equivalent to basically taking the dash action.
c01775
DM: So yeah, you can make three attempts.
c01776
Kenzo: Okay, great. This is kind of six attempts because-
c01777
Unknown: Seven
c01778
Kenzo: ... each, each one that I fail I can try to reroute and spend a ki if I want.
c01779
Delwath: But do use your hasted attempt first.
c01780
Kenzo: Okay.
c01781
Wellby: 'Cause you can't use it for other-
c01782
Kenzo: Well, no, no. But I should use my, my just-
c01783
Delwath: Because it... No, no, no.
c01784
Delwath: Use your h- you... That's a... Yeah, use your haste one first because then if you succeed you can use your regular action to attack three times.
c01785
Kenzo: Ah.
c01786
DM: Yeah.
c01787
Unknown: Right?
c01788
Wellby: I see what you're saying.
c01789
Delwath: But if the regular one succeeds you can only attack once with haste.
c01790
Kenzo: Okay, got it. But I can't use that, 'cause the, the...
c01791
Kenzo: I also just like... Oh, but that's at the end of my turn.
c01792
Unknown: That's the end of your turn.
c01793
Kenzo: Got it. Okay. All right.
c01794
Delwath: Your free one's at the end of your turn.
c01795
Kenzo: Fucking bitch.
c01796
Wellby: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
c01797
Kenzo: All right. First one.
c01798
Kenzo: Damn it, 16. That fails.
c01799
DM: Fails.
c01800
Kenzo: I'm gonna spend a ki to retry that one.
c01801
Kenzo: Ah, fucking bitch.
c01802
Kenzo: Yes.
c01803
Unknown: Yeah.
c01804
DM: 25-
c01805
Unknown: Good retry
c01806
DM: ... does succeed.
c01807
Kenzo: Thank fucking God. Oh my God, that was pretty stressful.
c01808
Kenzo: All right.
c01809
Wellby: That's the third 20 you've rolled in this combat.
c01810
DM: Yeah.
c01811
Unknown: Wow.
c01812
Kenzo: Yeah. But, um, two of them have been for saves which has been kind of useful.
c01813
Kenzo: That's, it's just two successes.
c01814
Delwath: So, sorry, which a- That was your hasted action?
c01815
DM: Okay.
c01816
Kenzo: That was my hasted action. Okay, so now I get three attacks.
c01817
Delwath: Now you can break free if you want.
c01818
DM: So you're not as, you're not restrained now, so you can fly out of it with your astral being.
c01819
Kenzo: Right.
c01820
Unknown: So move.
c01821
Kenzo: I will move. I will move the full 70 feet.
c01822
Kenzo: The thing is, I do not want it to do that shit again, 'cause every time it does that, like strength saves are fucking terrible.
c01823
Kenzo: I cannot... I, I feel like I need to, like-
c01824
Delwath: But remember that you're hasted
c01825
Kenzo: ... I just know that if I succeed-
c01826
Delwath: Its range is 60 feet, so it's tough.
c01827
Delwath: Oh, what you, what you need to do is attack it and then-
c01828
Kenzo: And then move
c01829
Delwath: ... and then move after your attack.
c01830
Kenzo: Yeah.
c01831
Unknown: You w-
c01832
Kenzo: That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
c01833
Delwath: Oh, no. Wait, haste doubles your speed?
c01834
Kenzo: It does.
c01835
DM: Yeah.
c01836
Kenzo: So I've got 140 move now.
c01837
Unknown: So yeah, do that.
c01838
Kenzo: Totally.
c01839
Delwath: Fly out of it.
c01840
Kenzo: I already-
c01841
Delwath: On your way out... [imitates clashing]
c01842
Kenzo: Yeah, on my way out I hit it three times-
c01843
Unknown: And then keep going
c01844
Kenzo: ... and then I'll, and then I keep going.
c01845
Delwath: You might get an opportunity attack against you, but it-
c01846
DM: You hit it twice.
c01847
Kenzo: Huh?
c01848
Unknown: Twice.
c01849
DM: Twice with your-
c01850
Delwath: Not th- Yeah, sorry. Yeah, 'cause you don't have your bonus action, so twice.
c01851
Unknown: Two separate-
c01852
Unknown: Two staff attacks.
c01853
Kenzo: Just because I drank a potion.
c01854
DM: You drank your potion and then-
c01855
Kenzo: All right, so-
c01856
DM: Yeah.
c01857
Kenzo: All right. So I get two att- staff attacks.
c01858
Unknown: Yes.
c01859
Kenzo: Just regular-
c01860
Unknown: Yes
c01861
Kenzo: ... normal staff attacks. All right, cool.
c01862
Kenzo: And they both... 21.
c01863
Kenzo: Does 21 hit?
c01864
DM: 21 does not hit.
c01865
Unknown: Dope.
c01866
Kenzo: All right, so only one hits.
c01867
Kenzo: One attack.
c01868
Delwath: Was that a six and a nine?
c01869
Kenzo: Yeah, six and a nine. I have a plus 15.
c01870
Delwath: Oh, the 21.
c01871
Delwath: Sorry, you were doing the higher one.
c01872
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. Well, no, this is, this is two attacks.
c01873
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
c01874
Kenzo: All right. So I get, uh-
c01875
Delwath: I was doing the math wrong. I thought-
c01876
Kenzo: You get two, d-
c01877
Unknown: I thought the six was the 20
c01878
Kenzo: ... two D12, two D12 plus nine.
c01879
Delwath: No, a nine, a nine plus...
c01880
Delwath: Don't you have a plus 15?
c01881
DM: So one of the two attacks hit.
c01882
DM: The 21 misses.
c01883
Unknown: Ah. Oh, oh. Yeah, yeah.
c01884
DM: So if the 21-
c01885
Delwath: Sorry, I thought you said they both hit
c01886
DM: ... but you know that 21, that 22 hits.
c01887
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01888
DM: So now you know its AC is 21.
c01889
Kenzo: All right. So that's 14 plus 9 is 23, and I move 140.
c01890
Kenzo: Get the fuck out of there. Oh, wait, no, I don't want to move all full.
c01891
Kenzo: What's the, what's the extent of its attack?
c01892
Delwath: We don't know. It could be 600 feet.
c01893
DM: It's been hitting Wellby from 600 feet away.
c01894
Kenzo: God.
c01895
Wellby: Even shoots the-
c01896
Kenzo: But, but, but no, but this, the engulf is 60 foot, right?
c01897
DM: Oh, the engulf was, well, 60 f- maybe.
c01898
DM: You don't quite know for sure.
c01899
Kenzo: Because the thing is, if I move 140, then I'd have to, like, just fly back in to attack it, and then I would be stuck right next to it.
c01900
Delwath: You should be... I would be...
c01901
Delwath: You can move 140 a turn.
c01902
Kenzo: Yeah.
c01903
Delwath: So if you're 70 feet away from it-
c01904
Kenzo: Yeah
c01905
Delwath: ... you can fly in and fly out in the same turn.
c01906
Kenzo: All right. I'll, I'll go, I'll go to 70 feet away and hope that that is, you know, a good distance.
c01907
DM: Okay. It is its turn now, um, relentlessly moving towards the three people here.
c01908
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Actually I move 100 feet away so that I can be 70 feet from Theoseus, 'cause I had 140 movement.
c01909
DM: Okay. Uh, it is going to first, um, move 30 feet forward
c01910
DM: attempting to engulf Dalwath.
c01911
Delwath: I'm already engulfed.
c01912
DM: Oh, you're already engulfed. Yeah, yeah.
c01913
DM: Dragging Dalwath with it.
c01914
Kenzo: [laughs]
c01915
DM: Uh, and then it is going to,
c01916
DM: um-
c01917
Kenzo: Oh, I didn't do that potion
c01918
DM: ... shoot a glob at, uh,
c01919
DM: Kenzo.
c01920
Kenzo: Okay.
c01921
Kenzo: Come at me.
c01922
DM: Uh,
c01923
DM: make a dex saving throw.
c01924
Kenzo: Uh, 21.
c01925
DM: Fails.
c01926
Kenzo: Reroll.
c01927
Seeker: Fuck. Four- uh, 16.
c01928
DM: Uh, you take 13 reduced to six points of acid damage and you are
c01929
DM: yanked back inside with Dalwath.
c01930
Kenzo: What? I'm restrained again?
c01931
Unknown: Wellby, come over here next to me.
c01932
DM: Uh, I forgot to mention though, it was bloodied on your last attack.
c01933
Kenzo: Oh, wow.
c01934
Unknown: Ah.
c01935
Kenzo: Wait, but on, on a... It can...
c01936
Kenzo: But why am I doing a dex save to get restrained?
c01937
DM: It has a, it has multiple attacks.
c01938
DM: It has a pseudopod attack and then it has a restraining glob attack that pulls you back into its body.
c01939
Kenzo: Bitch.
c01940
DM: And then it has a bonus action attack that did tons of damage to,
c01941
DM: um-
c01942
Wellby: So much damage.
c01943
Kenzo: Wellby.
c01944
DM: Oh, and then I keep forgetting it's totally chip damage.
c01945
DM: I keep forgetting the first time you do slashing damage in a turn you take acid damage.
c01946
DM: So...
c01947
DM: Oh, but- It's been a while since your turn.
c01948
DM: All these legend... It doesn't matter.
c01949
DM: Uh-
c01950
Delwath: It has been a while since Delwath's turn.
c01951
DM: Um, anyway, the ooze, uh,
c01952
DM: globs you, and then it's going to shoot a
c01953
DM: pseudopod at,
c01954
DM: uh, Wellby is the only one who is outside of it.
c01955
DM: That's a 23.
c01956
Unknown: Yeah.
c01957
DM: And that's gonna do [laughs] 26 points of force damage.
c01958
Wellby: I will uncannily dodge it.
c01959
Wellby: That's 13.
c01960
DM: Yep.
c01961
Kenzo: How many points you got left?
c01962
Unknown: 51.
c01963
DM: Um, and it does not get back its slime ejection.
c01964
Wellby: It also pushes it in, in attack.
c01965
Kenzo: Yeah. So all, all those pushages.
c01966
Unknown: You didn't drink the fourth one. You saved the fourth one.
c01967
DM: So that, uh, that ends its turn.
c01968
DM: Gets its legendaries back.
c01969
Unknown: [laughs]
c01970
DM: Who's, who's next?
c01971
DM: Delwath is next.
c01972
Delwath: Okay. I'm gonna misty step outside it.
c01973
DM: Okay.
c01974
Delwath: Uh, which is bonus action.
c01975
DM: Uh, so who's...
c01976
DM: Kenzo was the last one who dealt damage to it, so it's resistant to bludgeoning.
c01977
Delwath: Um, so I don't know.
c01978
Delwath: How far away can I get from it with a misty step?
c01979
DM: Uh, you're like right at...
c01980
DM: You're pulled right within the edge, so you can get-
c01981
Delwath: Okay. So I can go... I'll misty step...
c01982
Delwath: Well, actually, it doesn't really matter. It, it hit you when you were 70 feet away, right?
c01983
Unknown: Yeah, 70 feet away.
c01984
DM: It's the range of all of its attack is 600 feet, so.
c01985
Unknown: Okay, so.
c01986
DM: Oh, except the only one that's not 600 feet is the, is the,
c01987
DM: the slime ejection.
c01988
Delwath: But that hit Wellby.
c01989
DM: Yes.
c01990
Delwath: So being 40 feet away versus 20 feet away makes no difference.
c01991
Delwath: Wait, the, uh, even the acid splash is 60 feet.
c01992
DM: The acid splash is 60 feet.
c01993
Delwath: Man, this thing's annoying. Okay. Uh, I will, I will bonus action misty step to be out of the restraint,
c01994
Delwath: and then I will attack it.
c01995
Delwath: First attack. I'm from 20 feet away at least.
c01996
DM: Okay.
c01997
Delwath: Little caution here.
c01998
Delwath: Uh, 20...
c01999
Unknown: Uh, wait. What's-
c02000
DM: Easy as 21
c02001
Delwath: ... what's 12 plus 7? That's 10.
c02002
Unknown: 19.
c02003
Delwath: 19. That misses.
c02004
DM: Uh, y- Oh, that misses, so you don't take damage.
c02005
Delwath: 20. Also misses.
c02006
Kenzo: Yeah, you have to get a 22.
c02007
Kenzo: 21 misses.
c02008
Delwath: That's nine. Okay. I will auto hit it on the last attack.
c02009
DM: Okay.
c02010
Delwath: And, and smite.
c02011
Kenzo: Nice. Nice. Nice. Get that smite in.
c02012
Kenzo: How many times can you smite?
c02013
Unknown: Four.
c02014
Unknown: Sweet.
c02015
Delwath: With starting this level.
c02016
DM: Right.
c02017
Delwath: I used to be able to do three. Well, it takes a spell slot.
c02018
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
c02019
Delwath: So as long as I don't cast my spells for something else, but I misty stepped.
c02020
Delwath: I went sorcerer slot.
c02021
Delwath: So 28 plus, uh, 11.
c02022
DM: Uh, okay.
c02023
Unknown: I smited.
c02024
DM: That's your third smite.
c02025
Delwath: My third smite, okay. That's what I thought.
c02026
DM: Uh,
c02027
DM: you're doing damage to it. Uh-
c02028
Delwath: Oh, I need to remember, I can use my reaction to auto dodge.
c02029
DM: It is now gonna legend- it's now gonna use its first legendary action to crush.
c02030
Unknown: Fuck.
c02031
DM: So strength saves on you two.
c02032
Unknown: Damn it.
c02033
Unknown: 25.
c02034
Unknown: 18.
c02035
DM: Uh,
c02036
DM: Kenzo takes,
c02037
DM: uh, 26 points of force damage.
c02038
Delwath: [laughs] But you b- uh, l- Leviathan beats the save, so you take
c02039
DM: half that, so s- 13 points of force damage.
c02040
Delwath: Seeker's just like, "I'm gonna be a Leviathan."
c02041
Unknown: [laughs]
c02042
DM: [laughs] But it's gonna be pretty bad for Seeker,
c02043
DM: uh, if you, if you get forced out of your Leviathan form in the middle of the ooze.
c02044
Seeker: Right. That would be very bad.
c02045
DM: Uh, so let's hope that doesn't happen. That was its first legendary.
c02046
DM: After Delwath's turn, Seeker is up.
c02047
Delwath: You're still immune to... I guess you take a lot of acid damage.
c02048
Seeker: All right. So before my turn I will-
c02049
DM: No, it's not doing... It's just doing...
c02050
DM: It's not doing acid damage, it's just the immune to restrain is helping him a lot.
c02051
Seeker: Okay. I will close the last 30 feet to the bottom of the-
c02052
Unknown: That's the top.
c02053
Unknown: That's 50 feet.
c02054
DM: No, no, no.
c02055
Unknown: 30, 30, 30 to the bottom.
c02056
DM: He's, he's 30 feet to the bottom.
c02057
Unknown: Okay, cool.
c02058
Unknown: What do you see? What do you see when you-
c02059
Seeker: So before my turn I close the gap with my-
c02060
DM: So right now it's immune to bludgeoning, so that's a hard s- harder strength check.
c02061
Unknown: You have to make it.
c02062
Unknown: Yeah.
c02063
DM: 'Cause it's...
c02064
Seeker: Oh, that's only a 15.
c02065
DM: Nope, you do not move.
c02066
Seeker: That's my legendary action.
c02067
DM: That's your legendary action. Now it's your turn.
c02068
DM: So you can try to move your turn.
c02069
Delwath: So you can try it again.
c02070
DM: But still, strength, strength check.
c02071
Unknown: [dice rolling]
c02072
Unknown: That's much better.
c02073
Unknown: 24.
c02074
DM: Okay. 24, you push through,
c02075
DM: down to this,
c02076
DM: uh, incredibly hard crystal shell.
c02077
DM: There's like a 10-foot crystal shell at the-
c02078
Unknown: Oh, 10 feet.
c02079
DM: Yeah, and it's like the ooze, the matter of the ooze is, like, piling up down here and forming this.
c02080
DM: It's not actually really crystal, it's just super dense.
c02081
Seeker: Okay. What do, what do I do?
c02082
Seeker: [laughs] Um-
c02083
DM: It is... Oh, cherries.
c02084
Wellby: Break the shell with Leviathan.
c02085
Unknown: Yeah, maybe I try and smash it.
c02086
Seeker: Yeah, but it's, it's already...
c02087
Seeker: It, it's, um, resistant to bludgeoning right now, isn't it?
c02088
DM: It is currently-
c02089
Wellby: Is there a bludgeoning gap in the shell anywhere?
c02090
Seeker: Oh, can I go inside of it though?
c02091
DM: No.
c02092
Unknown: Hmm.
c02093
Unknown: Interesting idea.
c02094
DM: Yeah, it's currently resistant to bludgeoning.
c02095
Unknown: Hmm.
c02096
Unknown: I mean-
c02097
Unknown: Spell damage?
c02098
Seeker: That's gonna be the thing.
c02099
Unknown: Um...
c02100
Kenzo: I mean, you could just cast wish and end the whole battle right now.
c02101
Delwath: Can't use a scroll when you're controlled.
c02102
Unknown: Can't use scrolls.
c02103
Seeker: When I'm Leviathan. And I don't have a gap or an entrance
c02104
Unknown: to the-
c02105
Unknown: That's why you're a Leviathan, is 'cause...
c02106
Seeker: Okay. Telekinesis on an object could move it 30 feet.
c02107
Seeker: I could try to rip it out, but that's pretty far to go.
c02108
Unknown: Are you gonna crush it with telekinesis?
c02109
Delwath: Oh, wait. Leviathan's auto crit against objects.
c02110
Delwath: Or, like, do massive damage against objects.
c02111
Unknown: Uh, hold on.
c02112
Unknown: Um
c02113
Wellby: Double damage to objects and creatures
c02114
Unknown: Double damage
c02115
Seeker: Oh, siege monster
c02116
Unknown: Yeah
c02117
Unknown: Is an object?
c02118
Unknown: So not, not a crit.
c02119
Delwath: Just attack it. Even if it's, even with bludgeoning resistance, you're better off.
c02120
Delwath: You do double damage, that cancels...
c02121
Unknown: Use your attacks
c02122
Seeker: All right. All right. So then I'll just do my multi-attack, which is a slam and a tail-
c02123
Delwath: No, wait, make a tidal wave
c02124
Unknown: Oh.
c02125
Seeker: Yeah, so that's a DC 24 strength saving throw
c02126
Delwath: But, like, against an object?
c02127
Delwath: I don't know. Can you, like, make a massive blast of water from the middle of the leviathan?
c02128
DM: You can't make a tidal wave inside a creature
c02129
Delwath: Okay, fair enough
c02130
Unknown: [laughs]
c02131
Unknown: That's fair
c02132
Unknown: Tim, Tim makes the rules
c02133
Delwath: [laughs] No, that, that seems-
c02134
Unknown: Tim knows the rules
c02135
Delwath: That seems reasonable
c02136
Seeker: Yeah, the tidal wave was a good idea, but no, I get-
c02137
Delwath: No, just attack it
c02138
Seeker: ... a slam and a tail attack, so that's-
c02139
Unknown: Yes.
c02140
Delwath: You gotta roll, uh, you have a plus 14, so...
c02141
Delwath: You need an eight?
c02142
Delwath: 21 hit. No, 21 missed
c02143
DM: AC is 22
c02144
Delwath: Yeah, so you need eight.
c02145
Wellby: Nice, nice
c02146
Seeker: That's a nine and an eight
c02147
Unknown: So it's okay
c02148
Unknown: So-
c02149
DM: Oh, wait, wait. Which one are you doing first?
c02150
Seeker: 16 and an eight. Yeah.
c02151
Unknown: Um-
c02152
DM: The slam or the tail?
c02153
Seeker: Uh, I do the slam first, 'cause I'm facing it
c02154
DM: Okay
c02155
Seeker: And then I'll spin around and do the tail [laughs]
c02156
DM: So you, you slam into it, uh, striking this crystalline shell.
c02157
DM: And for
c02158
DM: a moment,
c02159
DM: you get, like, a flash of, a flashback, like, a Seeker flashback to Limbo, and it is completely immune to the damage you do
c02160
Unknown: Ugh
c02161
DM: The form that it is in is resistant to, immune to all damage except thunder, currently
c02162
Unknown: Thunder?
c02163
Unknown: Ugh
c02164
DM: But it's a fragment of Limbo
c02165
Wellby: Oh, so it must be constantly changing, maybe?
c02166
Seeker: So, so both my attacks are just
c02167
Unknown: repelled
c02168
DM: N- neither of your attacks do anything
c02169
Unknown: Wait, no, 'cause acid
c02170
DM: But it is a fragment of Limbo
c02171
Unknown: Yeah
c02172
Unknown: Tim
c02173
Unknown: So I just, I just-
c02174
Delwath: That is a clue. I don't know what kind of clue it is, but...
c02175
Kenzo: Tim, I just, uh, realized, uh, with Haste-
c02176
Wellby: Hit it with Order
c02177
Kenzo: With Haste I have, uh, advantage on dexterity saves
c02178
Wellby: Give it proofs
c02179
Unknown: I could... Oh, I can't put proofs of creation
c02180
Kenzo: So I failed once and then I, so I, I don't know, I won't-
c02181
DM: Eh, the last combat you were supposed to have disadvantage on dex saves, and you forgot about it, so-
c02182
Unknown: All right. All right
c02183
DM: ... it's even now-
c02184
Unknown: Can't do that
c02185
DM: ... but don't forget for the next one
c02186
Unknown: [laughs]
c02187
Wellby: Do we have anything from Mc- Me- McAnnis, Mechanicus, whatever it is?
c02188
Delwath: My sword's attuned to McAnnis.
c02189
Delwath: Wait, but, but you're not standing in...
c02190
Delwath: There's, there's not, like, a...
c02191
DM: No, this is inside the creature
c02192
Delwath: It's not like there's not-
c02193
DM: This is, like, its heart
c02194
DM: There's no, but there's not, like, some space to stand
c02195
DM: No, no, no, no,
c02196
DM: no
c02197
Delwath: Can you do thunder damage?
c02198
Seeker: Well, my turn is over
c02199
Unknown: Right, okay
c02200
DM: Uh, yeah. Seeker's turn is over and it's now gonna use a legendary resistance, um-
c02201
Unknown: Action
c02202
DM: Sorry, action. I keep saying resistance.
c02203
DM: Uh, with, now with you this close, it is, um, clearly getting quite nervous about...
c02204
DM: Or it's reacting to the presence of you here and it is going to,
c02205
DM: um, crush again.
c02206
DM: Uh, you have disadvantage on the strength save because you are so close to its heart
c02207
Unknown: Ugh.
c02208
Unknown: So
c02209
Unknown: Take a lot of damage
c02210
Kenzo: [dice rolling]
c02211
DM: Uh, Kenzo, you're also engulfed
c02212
Unknown: No, I-
c02213
Delwath: You need to make a strength save
c02214
Unknown: 17
c02215
DM: 17 fails.
c02216
DM: Um, so you take 26 points of force damage
c02217
DM: [dice rolling]
c02218
Unknown: Oh, that's fine
c02219
Delwath: I have, you have to make a con save
c02220
DM: And Kenzo also takes 26 points of force damage
c02221
Delwath: 13. You have to roll a s- But not, don't roll one or two
c02222
Unknown: So I have to make a concentration save
c02223
DM: Concentration check, yep
c02224
Delwath: You have four legendary resistances
c02225
DM: Yeah
c02226
Delwath: Wait, why aren't you using... Well, it's probably not worth it, but...
c02227
DM: I would save your legendary resistances-
c02228
Unknown: Yeah
c02229
DM: ... for failing concentration saves
c02230
Unknown: Yeah
c02231
DM: So roll
c02232
Seeker: That's a three
c02233
Delwath: That's not a one or a two [laughs]
c02234
DM: So pass
c02235
DM: You're gonna get it.
c02236
Wellby: It's only a matter of time
c02237
Unknown: You're gonna pull it in
c02238
Wellby: That doesn't have to be a five or six
c02239
Unknown: Yeah [laughs]
c02240
DM: Uh-
c02241
Delwath: Seeker's gonna get nervous if I keep rolling a five or six
c02242
Unknown: [laughs]
c02243
Seeker: I'm liking it so far
c02244
DM: That ends Seeker's turn as we start the next round.
c02245
DM: Wellby is now 140 feet away, which is the furthest away you can be, as it's moved 30 feet closer.
c02246
DM: Um, the ooze is still moving slowly towards
c02247
DM: the edge of the mist, uh, trying to get Wellby, Kenzo, and Delweth.
c02248
DM: That are the three it can see, while Kenzo is currently engulfed and Delweth has been dodging out of the way, while Misty's stepping out of the way or using other magic, 'cause Delweth is almost impossible to restrain.
c02249
DM: Seeker, meanwhile, as the leviathan, is at its heart
c02250
DM: a fragment of Limbo which has currently taken the shape of a crystal immune to everything but for, but thunder damage
c02251
Seeker: Can you make a demiplane and then push it into the door?
c02252
Kenzo: [laughs] Push the heart into the door
c02253
Delwath: Or the mist
c02254
DM: And it is Wellby's turn
c02255
Wellby: I mean, we could put two extra dimensional spaces together right in the middle of it
c02256
Seeker: Oh, and just deaden it. Yeah
c02257
Wellby: Uh, okay.
c02258
Wellby: I am shooting.
c02259
Wellby: That is a 18, 1 and an 18.
c02260
Wellby: That's funny. Um...
c02261
DM: Okay.
c02262
DM: Shifts to Piercing at the end of Wellby's turn
c02263
Wellby: Uh, 10,
c02264
Wellby: 32, maker, 20, 35, 38, 46.
c02265
Wellby: And then I'm gonna drink a healing potion and then move 90 feet straight up
c02266
DM: Okay.
c02267
DM: Um, it is going to use its, uh, last legendary action, um, before its turn,
c02268
DM: uh, to fire a pseudopod at Wellby Um, that is a 19
c02269
Wellby: 19 just hits me.
c02270
Wellby: 19 is my AC.
c02271
DM: That's, uh, that's only 16 points of force damage.
c02272
DM: And now Kenzo is up.
c02273
DM: You are restrained.
c02274
DM: You take 24 points of force damage.
c02275
Kenzo: I'm almost dead.
c02276
Kenzo: Thanks.
c02277
DM: No, you're really far from being dead, 'cause if you drop to zero you actually only drop to-
c02278
Delwath: You get
c02279
DM: ... 70-
c02280
Kenzo: Oh, yeah.
c02281
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah
c02282
DM: ... like 80-some high number.
c02283
Kenzo: I'm so glad I took that.
c02284
DM: [laughs]
c02285
Kenzo: Okay.
c02286
Delwath: Wait, what's the turn order?
c02287
Delwath: When does Kenzo go compared to Delwath?
c02288
DM: The ooze is in between the two of them.
c02289
Delwath: Okay, so it goes the two of them, the ooze, Delwath, then Seeker?
c02290
DM: Yep.
c02291
Kenzo: Yeah. In fact, I... How many times...
c02292
Kenzo: I, I can... Do I... Does that just keep happening?
c02293
DM: Every time you start your turn in the ooze you take force damage.
c02294
Kenzo: No, no, I know, but I mean, uh, um, the, uh...
c02295
Kenzo: I can... If I go down to zero and then I spend-
c02296
Unknown: Once
c02297
DM: No, it's once.
c02298
Kenzo: Once. Okay. All right. 'Cause I'm saving a...
c02299
Kenzo: I want to use my 10 hit dice too, but I'm gonna wait, wait for that until after I
c02300
Kenzo: die once.
c02301
DM: After you die once-
c02302
DM: Yeah
c02303
DM: ... you could use the 10 D10 healing.
c02304
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Um, okay, cool.
c02305
Kenzo: In that case then, so now I've got three actions, a bonus action.
c02306
Kenzo: Can I have bonus action try to es- uh...
c02307
Kenzo: I have to use actions to get out of the restraint.
c02308
DM: No. It's, it has to be your haste action or your regular action.
c02309
Kenzo: All right. Ah, fucking bitch, man.
c02310
DM: I, I think your... I would...
c02311
DM: I mean, I think your odds of hitting-
c02312
Kenzo: Just stand here and fight him? Just-
c02313
DM: Fighting is not that... I mean, you, you're not gonna hit.
c02314
Kenzo: Yeah, but you might-
c02315
DM: But you make so many attacks
c02316
Delwath: ... you might be better off making six attacks.
c02317
DM: If you waste your whole turn doing no damage, if instead you make six attacks, you're almost certainly gonna hit on three of them.
c02318
DM: You're gonna hit for three of them. [sighs]
c02319
DM: And you get one au- You get one automatic free try without spending an action at the end of your turn.
c02320
Kenzo: That's true. All right.
c02321
Kenzo: I gotta stay in here and just fight, fight for a little while, 'cause yeah, that-
c02322
Delwath: Well, you could use your haste action.
c02323
Delwath: That's not a... No, no. Use your haste action to try and escape.
c02324
Unknown: Right.
c02325
DM: 'Cause there's only one attack.
c02326
Unknown: But at half value. At half value.
c02327
DM: It's not that valuable.
c02328
Kenzo: Okay. All right. All right. I'll use my haste action
c02329
Kenzo: to try to escape.
c02330
Delwath: 'Cause last turn you couldn't use your bonus action 'cause you tried with the haste potion, right?
c02331
DM: Yeah, correct.
c02332
DM: Yeah.
c02333
Kenzo: That fails. I will spend a ki to try again.
c02334
Kenzo: 18 still fails, right?
c02335
DM: Yeah. 18 fails.
c02336
Kenzo: [coughs] All right, I'm still in there.
c02337
Kenzo: So now
c02338
Kenzo: the idea is to attack twice with a disadvantage?
c02339
DM: Well, you can attack five times, 'cause you have-
c02340
Kenzo: Five
c02341
Unknown: ... your bonus action attack too.
c02342
Kenzo: Right. Um-
c02343
DM: But each attack is with disadvantage.
c02344
Kenzo: All right. Why the fuck not? Let's, let's give it a go.
c02345
Kenzo: First attack.
c02346
Kenzo: That hits.
c02347
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
c02348
Kenzo: Um, second attack.
c02349
Kenzo: That misses.
c02350
Kenzo: Third attack.
c02351
Kenzo: That misses. Fourth attack.
c02352
Kenzo: That misses.
c02353
DM: [laughs] That was-
c02354
Kenzo: Fifth attack. That misses.
c02355
Kenzo: [laughs]
c02356
DM: Wow, you do-
c02357
Unknown: That was brutal
c02358
DM: ... 2 D12.
c02359
Kenzo: 2 D12 plus, uh, nine.
c02360
DM: Plus s- plus nine.
c02361
Kenzo: 15.
c02362
DM: 20.
c02363
Kenzo: Or 24.
c02364
Unknown: 15 plus 9. Yeah, 24.
c02365
Kenzo: And now I, I roll one more time.
c02366
DM: Now you get one sa- strength save.
c02367
Kenzo: I'm just gonna roll them at the same time like I have advantage, 'cause I do.
c02368
DM: Well, no, because it costs you ki.
c02369
Unknown: You don't... Oh.
c02370
Kenzo: No, I don't... Dude, I still have, I still have, I still have, like, I still have, I still have-
c02371
DM: Well, each Flurry of Blows also costs you ki.
c02372
Unknown: Okay. Let's see.
c02373
Wellby: Do you have, like, 20 ki at this point?
c02374
DM: Yeah, you have 20 ki.
c02375
Kenzo: Yeah.
c02376
DM: So you're probably not gonna run out, but-
c02377
Kenzo: No, no, I'm still good. I, I'm still gonna try.
c02378
DM: Okay.
c02379
Kenzo: All right. Well, I'll s- I'll roll the first one first.
c02380
Delwath: You just roll one attack-
c02381
Kenzo: Yeah
c02382
Unknown: ... 'cause you might escape
c02383
Kenzo: ... 'cause I might escape.
c02384
Delwath: On the first.
c02385
Unknown: [dice rolling]
c02386
Kenzo: Fuck. Did not escape.
c02387
Kenzo: Did not escape. Ugh.
c02388
Kenzo: Damn.
c02389
DM: That ends Kenzo's turn.
c02390
Kenzo: Ouch.
c02391
DM: Um, the ooze is up.
c02392
DM: So, sorry, Wellby, how far are you away?
c02393
Wellby: 165 feet.
c02394
DM: Okay. How far is Delwath away?
c02395
Unknown: Uh...
c02396
DM: Like 20 feet?
c02397
Unknown: 20...
c02398
Kenzo: You're 20 feet.
c02399
Delwath: Yeah.
c02400
DM: So it's gonna move 30 feet and try and engulf Delwath.
c02401
DM: Strength saving throw.
c02402
Delwath: Wait, my... Why roll? What's the DC?
c02403
DM: Uh, 23.
c02404
Delwath: I can't actually make it. It's impossible for Delwath to make a DC.
c02405
DM: Did you already use your-
c02406
Delwath: I haven't used the-
c02407
DM: ... favor of the...
c02408
Unknown: Yes
c02409
DM: ... So if you roll high you could use...
c02410
Unknown: Yeah, I know.
c02411
Unknown: Yeah.
c02412
DM: Okay. Delwath is engulfed.
c02413
Delwath: No, it's easier honestly to just get engulfed.
c02414
DM: To just get out.
c02415
Delwath: This time I'll get us both out.
c02416
Kenzo: How do you do that?
c02417
Unknown: Scatter.
c02418
Kenzo: Oh my God.
c02419
Wellby: Oh.
c02420
Kenzo: Thank you, fucking Delwath.
c02421
Kenzo: Jesus Christ.
c02422
DM: Um-
c02423
Kenzo: 'Cause now that I'm out again it needs to do dexterity saves for me.
c02424
Unknown: Yeah.
c02425
Kenzo: And I have haste, so I can... I will, I will make those.
c02426
DM: Well, no, the engulf is a strength save.
c02427
DM: The restraining glob that pulls you in from a distance is dex.
c02428
Kenzo: I know, but if I'm, if I'm far away-
c02429
Unknown: If you're far away, then the dex saves are-
c02430
Kenzo: Exactly
c02431
Unknown: ... yeah.
c02432
Delwath: Exactly. Which I want to be, so.
c02433
DM: Um, so, uh, all it can do is pseudopod on,
c02434
DM: um... Sorry, you're 170 you said?
c02435
Wellby: 165.
c02436
DM: So you're too far away for the restraining glob.
c02437
Kenzo: This might take it down.
c02438
Wellby: Surely it can attack someone else.
c02439
DM: So it's gonna attack you twice.
c02440
Wellby: Awesome.
c02441
DM: Everybody else is inside it. All it can do is crush them to death.
c02442
Delwath: I'm gonna get us out this time.
c02443
Delwath: I only have one more-
c02444
DM: So that's a 20-
c02445
Unknown: After that I-
c02446
Kenzo: I'm not gonna get back in there
c02447
DM: ... one and a 30-something
c02448
Kenzo: ... I'm not, I'm not gonna get...
c02449
Kenzo: I'm, I'm not gonna get back in there again.
c02450
Wellby: It presumably has
c02451
Wellby: blindsight.
c02452
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah, it's not great.
c02453
DM: Yeah, it has-
c02454
Unknown: I, I've, I've wore, I've wore darkvision
c02455
DM: ... 600 feet of blindsight.
c02456
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, you'll be fine.
c02457
Wellby: I'll be fine.
c02458
Unknown: Delwath will not.
c02459
DM: Uh, 19 force and then 22 force with the second.
c02460
Wellby: Each of those is an attack.
c02461
DM: Yeah.
c02462
Wellby: Uh, I'll uncanny dodge the second one.
c02463
DM: Okay.
c02464
Wellby: So that's total of 30.
c02465
Wellby: Awesome. I'm down to 23.
c02466
DM: Um, and then it's... Does it get its bonus action back?
c02467
DM: Nope.
c02468
DM: It is not going to spray slime.
c02469
DM: That, uh, ends its turn.
c02470
Delwath: So Delwath?
c02471
DM: So Delwath is up.
c02472
DM: You take 21-
c02473
Delwath: Wait, wait, wait, hold on. Voluntory action. Voluntory action.
c02474
DM: Oh, yeah.
c02475
Seeker: What? I could move or slam attack.
c02476
Delwath: Why don't you hit the orb again? Is it still...
c02477
Delwath: Oh, do you know if its resistance has changed?
c02478
Kenzo: Is there any way to tell?
c02479
Seeker: What, what's the resistance? Yeah.
c02480
DM: It, the physical appearance of the orb has not changed.
c02481
Kenzo: I think so. It probably has not changed.
c02482
DM: Uh, the, the thing itself is resistant-
c02483
Unknown: Wait
c02484
DM: ... to bludgeoning
c02485
Delwath: ... punch the outside.
c02486
Unknown: Don't attack the heart.
c02487
Kenzo: Touch, touch the ooze.
c02488
Unknown: Just punch those-
c02489
Kenzo: Touch the ooze, yeah.
c02490
Unknown: Yeah.
c02491
Kenzo: Yeah.
c02492
Seeker: So I do my, my usual slam attack.
c02493
Unknown: Just, I mean it's resist-
c02494
DM: Well, right now it's resistant to bludgeoning.
c02495
Delwath: So what? You can still do 10 damage.
c02496
DM: Yeah.
c02497
Delwath: It's not gonna hurt it. I mean, it's not...
c02498
Wellby: It must be headed towards like a quarter or so.
c02499
Unknown: Yeah.
c02500
Unknown: It's gonna tip away.
c02501
DM: It's, it's very close to a quarter.
c02502
Delwath: It did not. I rolled a three, so.
c02503
Unknown: Yeah.
c02504
DM: So that misses.
c02505
Unknown: Okay.
c02506
DM: Uh, Delweth, you take...
c02507
Delwath: 22, you said
c02508
DM: ... 22 points of force damage at the start of your turn.
c02509
Delwath: I'm not in love with the number of hit points I have left.
c02510
Kenzo: Mm.
c02511
Unknown: But 75, I'll be okay.
c02512
Wellby: Ugh, I dream of having 75 hit points.
c02513
Unknown: [laughs]
c02514
Delwath: Yeah. Uh, bonus action, use metamagic to quicken Scatter.
c02515
Kenzo: Oh, thank God.
c02516
DM: Okay.
c02517
Delwath: Kenzo and Delweth both appear anywhere you'd like within 120 feet.
c02518
Kenzo: Uh, I'm gonna be... I'm gonna get myself fucking away from this motherfucker.
c02519
Kenzo: Uh, I'm gonna get... Oh, 70 feet again.
c02520
Delwath: Yeah, I'm gonna be-
c02521
Kenzo: So I can attack and come back
c02522
Delwath: ... 20 feet away
c02523
Delwath: and then I will...
c02524
Delwath: So I'm out of metamagics.
c02525
Kenzo: This is a great combat though, 'cause this is definitely very challenging.
c02526
Delwath: And I will just attack it.
c02527
Delwath: Let's see. I used
c02528
Unknown: Scatter.
c02529
Delwath: Oh, I could always Plane Shift.
c02530
Delwath: I could just, I could go to the Feywild if I really thought I would die otherwise.
c02531
DM: Yeah.
c02532
Delwath: Or somewhere. I could go back to Limbo, that doesn't sound wise.
c02533
Unknown: Um.
c02534
Unknown: [coughs]
c02535
Delwath: Okay. I am gonna-
c02536
DM: Well, that was your bonus, so you still have your action.
c02537
Unknown: Yep. Yep.
c02538
Kenzo: You still have your standard, your dash. Your dash move.
c02539
Delwath: I am just going to attack.
c02540
Unknown: That's true.
c02541
Seeker: Oh, the soil.
c02542
DM: Yeah.
c02543
Seeker: But I'm in leviathan form.
c02544
Kenzo: I know, I was saying, is there a reason for me to use-
c02545
Delwath: First attack is a 20
c02546
Unknown: ...
c02547
Kenzo: the dirt?
c02548
Unknown: Uh, 22.
c02549
Unknown: You're right, yeah.
c02550
DM: 22, yep.
c02551
Unknown: 'Cause I'm in leviathan form so I can access to my-
c02552
DM: Right.
c02553
Delwath: Second attack is a 23.
c02554
DM: I mean, it's a piece of Limbo.
c02555
Delwath: Third attack crits. Another crit smite.
c02556
Unknown: Last-
c02557
DM: Good
c02558
Seeker: ... piece of Limbo.
c02559
Delwath: Last spell slot
c02560
Seeker: ... what I can do is-
c02561
Kenzo: Lots of damage
c02562
Delwath: Okay. So that's six.
c02563
DM: What do you, what do you do to Limbo?
c02564
DM: What's-
c02565
Seeker: Control is my mind?
c02566
Unknown: Uh.
c02567
Unknown: But I have to be inside of it?
c02568
Delwath: Wait, I hit with all attacks, that's two-
c02569
Unknown: Maybe I just like get up-
c02570
Unknown: Four
c02571
Unknown: ...
c02572
Seeker: and wrap my tentacles around it
c02573
Delwath: ... 12. 12 plus four
c02574
Delwath: is 16, plus 20.
c02575
Unknown: And
c02576
Seeker: can... And what do I imagine?
c02577
Unknown: Just, just like...
c02578
Kenzo: You've got, you've got imagination dirt in your pocket.
c02579
DM: Delweth does...
c02580
Unknown: Ah.
c02581
Unknown: 5, 10, 15.
c02582
Delwath: 99 plus 15 plus 18.
c02583
Unknown: Hell yeah.
c02584
Wellby: Holy shit. In one attack?
c02585
Unknown: Three attacks.
c02586
Kenzo: Wow.
c02587
DM: Uh, it's b- it's below a quarter.
c02588
Delwath: I mean, that was a crit and my last...
c02589
Delwath: I critted twice and smited on crits twice.
c02590
Kenzo: Dude, 120.
c02591
Delwath: That's 20 D8.
c02592
DM: So Delweth-
c02593
Delwath: Oh, then I run away.
c02594
DM: How far away are you?
c02595
Delwath: I'm 20 feet from
c02596
Unknown: it.
c02597
DM: But after you run away, how far?
c02598
Delwath: Oh, after I run away, uh, I am...
c02599
DM: Uh, you also take five points of acid damage.
c02600
Delwath: After I run away, I'm 20 plus 60.
c02601
DM: Okay. Well, you're...
c02602
DM: I mean, you actually technically haven't left its reach, 'cause its reach is 600.
c02603
DM: So it's not gonna have an opportunity to attack you.
c02604
Delwath: Well, no, I mean just the engulf.
c02605
DM: Yeah, yeah. It's, you're out of the range of engulf.
c02606
DM: Um, it is going to use a legendary action to use its grasping blob on Delweth, who just attacked it.
c02607
Unknown: That's an attack.
c02608
DM: Dex saving throw.
c02609
Unknown: One.
c02610
Kenzo: [laughs] No.
c02611
DM: Uh-
c02612
Kenzo: Oh, no
c02613
DM: ... you take 21 points of acid damage and you are back in the blob.
c02614
Kenzo: Dude, this thing is gnarly as fuck.
c02615
Unknown: I'm, I'm not in good shape here, guys.
c02616
DM: Please kill it.
c02617
Kenzo: I mean, we're probably gonna do it next round.
c02618
DM: Uh, that was its legendary. Seeker's up.
c02619
Kenzo: I'm, I'm gonna fuck it up this round.
c02620
Unknown: All right.
c02621
Unknown: I'm gonna fuck it up.
c02622
Unknown: I can get out...
c02623
Delwath: I can get out twice more.
c02624
Kenzo: I know where, we're gonna kill it. You, that, that has my-
c02625
Delwath: I only have 45 hit points left
c02626
Unknown: ... we're gonna fuck him up this turn.
c02627
Seeker: I will use my action
c02628
Seeker: to reach out
c02629
Seeker: and... What kind of limbs does the, does this leviathan even have?
c02630
Seeker: Or reach out with my-
c02631
DM: You just shape whatever you want out of water
c02632
Seeker: ... ah, reach out with my enormous flippers and give this thing kind of like a,
c02633
Seeker: a hug. 'Cause it's, I'm huge, but this is also huge.
c02634
DM: Yeah.
c02635
Kenzo: How big is the thing, the object?
c02636
DM: 10 foot... It's a crystal s- shell that's like a 10-foot,
c02637
DM: uh, diameter sphere.
c02638
Seeker: And just focus my mind and all my energy on it
c02639
Seeker: vanishing into a poof of feathers.
c02640
Delwath: What are you... Are you just literally trying to manipulate Limbo?
c02641
Seeker: I'm just using, using my-
c02642
DM: Make an intelligence check
c02643
Seeker: ... which is, uh...
c02644
Seeker: Oh, with the leviathan-
c02645
DM: It's your own intelligence
c02646
Unknown: ... your stats, your intelligence
c02647
DM: ... it's your, your shape change, so you get your stats, your mental stats.
c02648
Seeker: But I'm using the leviathan's... Oh, it's mental stats.
c02649
Delwath: Physically. You get your mental and its physical.
c02650
Unknown: Yeah.
c02651
Unknown: Oh, so that's the plus five.
c02652
Seeker: All right.
c02653
Seeker: That's a 15.
c02654
Unknown: 10 plus 5.
c02655
DM: Uh.
c02656
Unknown: I can heroic it.
c02657
DM: Um,
c02658
DM: nothing happens.
c02659
Delwath: It could... I mean, 50/50 chance of doing better than 10.
c02660
Delwath: This might be worth heroicing.
c02661
Delwath: Wait, you're trying to turn it into feathers?
c02662
Seeker: I just want it to vanish, yeah.
c02663
Seeker: I don't know. I didn't... If anybody has a better idea.
c02664
Kenzo: No, feathers, feathers are great.
c02665
Delwath: I mean, try and... I would think try and turn it into something fragile so that your bludgeoning attack can hurt it.
c02666
Unknown: Oh.
c02667
Delwath: Trying to change its resistance might be easier than making it go away.
c02668
Unknown: Well-
c02669
Unknown: But
c02670
Unknown: ... I did what I did.
c02671
Unknown: Feathers are fragile.
c02672
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, feathers are fragile.
c02673
Seeker: Okay. Okay, I'll use my heroic.
c02674
Wellby: Yeah.
c02675
Unknown: Reroll.
c02676
Unknown: No, that's way worse.
c02677
DM: Nope, you do not change it.
c02678
Unknown: Leviathan.
c02679
Unknown: You can bonus action attack it now, right?
c02680
DM: Does leviathan have bonus actions?
c02681
DM: No.
c02682
Wellby: You can't legendary after your own turn
c02683
DM: ... So that ends Seeker's turn.
c02684
DM: Um, it will,
c02685
DM: uh, legendary after
c02686
DM: Seeker to crush you.
c02687
DM: So disadvantage on the strength save, that's 22 points of force damage.
c02688
DM: D- roll a strength save with disadvantage.
c02689
DM: I think you're the only one inside it now, right?
c02690
Unknown: Yeah.
c02691
Delwath: I think we had been in just engulfed Delwath.
c02692
DM: Oh, it just engulfed Delwath. So same thing, strength save for you.
c02693
Kenzo: That's a three.
c02694
Delwath: Um, Delwath was probably gonna die guys.
c02695
Delwath: I need some help.
c02696
Delwath: How many points is that?
c02697
Kenzo: 25?
c02698
Unknown: [coughs]
c02699
Kenzo: Nope.
c02700
DM: What did you roll?
c02701
Kenzo: A three. I'm done.
c02702
DM: So you take 21, you take 21.
c02703
Delwath: I have 20 hit points.
c02704
DM: Um, that's the second legendary.
c02705
Unknown: Yeah, it's 23. I'm not at the bottom anymore.
c02706
Kenzo: Well, I actually had 20.
c02707
Wellby: No.
c02708
DM: Uh, Wellby is-
c02709
Wellby: I'm not at the bottom
c02710
DM: ... is on the top of the order.
c02711
DM: Um,
c02712
DM: and currently now Seeker is trying to shift this
c02713
DM: knot of limbo into something that is not immune to all damage but thunder.
c02714
Kenzo: Yeah, but you can put out one.
c02715
Unknown: I know, I know, but how many of us here?
c02716
DM: 23.
c02717
Unknown: Wow, what a club.
c02718
Unknown: [laughs] And 400.
c02719
DM: [laughs]
c02720
Wellby: Do you have anything for healing?
c02721
Delwath: Yeah, I c- I have healing potions and I, well, I can cast a second level healing word.
c02722
DM: Delwath is engulfed.
c02723
Unknown: Yeah, put y- put yourself in there if you're engulfed, so I can tell.
c02724
DM: Kenzo is not engulfed.
c02725
Unknown: I'm 70 feet away.
c02726
DM: 70 feet away. Wellby is 165 feet away.
c02727
DM: And it's Wellby's turn to attack.
c02728
Wellby: I do that.
c02729
Wellby: I shoot it, and that's a 20...
c02730
Wellby: It's almost, like, s- like a 30 or something.
c02731
DM: That hits.
c02732
Unknown: Let's just fucking kill it.
c02733
Wellby: [die rolling]
c02734
DM: So-
c02735
Unknown: Oh, no.
c02736
Wellby: That's poor rolling.
c02737
Unknown: 10. 15.
c02738
Unknown: That's terrible.
c02739
Unknown: 25, 33.
c02740
Wellby: 33. And then, uh, second shot, uh, hits.
c02741
Wellby: And it's another nine, so that's 42 altogether.
c02742
DM: Got it.
c02743
Delwath: Can you use your, like, lightning arrow or something?
c02744
DM: He already used it.
c02745
Wellby: No, I already used it.
c02746
Unknown: Um,
c02747
Wellby: and I don't think it can be restrained.
c02748
DM: It is immune to restraint, yeah.
c02749
Wellby: Um, and then I'll move another 90 feet.
c02750
DM: So you're gonna mo- Oh, straight up.
c02751
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c02752
Unknown: Yeah.
c02753
DM: So you're going up in the clear sky.
c02754
DM: So now you're quite far away from it.
c02755
DM: But you're still within 600 feet, and you attacked it last, so it's gonna use its last legendary to pseudopod shot you.
c02756
DM: Oh,
c02757
DM: that's a natural 20.
c02758
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
c02759
Wellby: That's a long way to fall.
c02760
Unknown: Oh, shit.
c02761
DM: Uh, you take
c02762
DM: 69-
c02763
Wellby: Probably this other call auto kicks in if you're in the air
c02764
Delwath: ... C- can you, you can, you can dodge it.
c02765
Unknown: Oh, I can.
c02766
Kenzo: Right?
c02767
Wellby: I can.
c02768
DM: So that's 10, 26.
c02769
Wellby: It has to be less than... It has to be 45 or fewer.
c02770
DM: 26.
c02771
Kenzo: That's what I think.
c02772
DM: Um, plus eight is 34.
c02773
Kenzo: Oh, that's actually pretty sick.
c02774
Unknown: 34.
c02775
DM: Plus eight is 42.
c02776
Kenzo: That's great.
c02777
Wellby: Awesome.
c02778
DM: One hit point.
c02779
Wellby: That works. [laughs]
c02780
Kenzo: I'm going again?
c02781
DM: Twice.
c02782
Wellby: On any dodge, I have
c02783
Wellby: two hit points.
c02784
Delwath: Two hit points. Damn. No, that's like twice what I thought.
c02785
DM: It is now resistant.
c02786
Unknown: [laughs]
c02787
DM: It is now res-
c02788
Unknown: I said twice as many hit points as you thought.
c02789
Unknown: Yeah
c02790
DM: ... It is now resistant to piercing and Kenzo is up.
c02791
Kenzo: All right. Now I'm gonna fuck this motherfucker up.
c02792
Wellby: Do you have any healing that heals all of us?
c02793
Kenzo: So I get six attacks now, right?
c02794
DM: No.
c02795
Kenzo: Or-
c02796
Unknown: Yeah
c02797
Kenzo: ... six, right?
c02798
Kenzo: Yeah, 'cause I get three staff attacks-
c02799
DM: Yep
c02800
Kenzo: ... three, three, um...
c02801
Kenzo: But these are just regular attacks. There's no advantage or anything else going on.
c02802
Kenzo: But still, let's fucking go.
c02803
Kenzo: Okay, so these are all plus 15.
c02804
Kenzo: [die rolling]
c02805
Kenzo: 20, 20 misses, right?
c02806
DM: 20 misses.
c02807
Kenzo: 20 misses.
c02808
Unknown: 20.
c02809
Kenzo: Okay, so two, two staff attacks hit, and then three unarmed strikes.
c02810
Kenzo: Ooh, a crit.
c02811
Unknown: Ooh, crit.
c02812
Kenzo: Uh, I have a crit.
c02813
Delwath: A miss and a hit.
c02814
Kenzo: A miss and a hit. Yeah, so.
c02815
DM: So two staffs and a crit, and a hit.
c02816
DM: So that's three D12 on the staffs-
c02817
Kenzo: And three
c02818
DM: ... two D12 on the hit, on the crit.
c02819
DM: 6 D12 total.
c02820
Delwath: 6 D12 plus-
c02821
Kenzo: Plus
c02822
Delwath: ... you had three hits.
c02823
Delwath: So 6 D12 plus, uh-
c02824
Kenzo: Oh, no
c02825
Unknown: ...
c02826
Delwath: uh, plus nine plus 12.
c02827
Kenzo: Pl- plus, plus 18.
c02828
DM: Two staff and two-
c02829
Kenzo: Minus, two staffs
c02830
DM: ... plus 18 plus 14.
c02831
Kenzo: Plus 18.
c02832
Delwath: Wait, both your staffs hit?
c02833
Kenzo: Two out of three staffs.
c02834
DM: He has three staffs on the haste.
c02835
Kenzo: I'm hasted. I'm hasted.
c02836
DM: Okay, roll your 6 D12.
c02837
Kenzo: So it's 6 D12 plus what?
c02838
DM: I got it, plus 18 plus 12.
c02839
Kenzo: I, I know. I like to know. I wanna know.
c02840
Kenzo: I wanna-
c02841
DM: 6 D12 plus 18 plus 14.
c02842
Kenzo: Okay, 6 D12. All right, fucking die.
c02843
Unknown: 12 plus 32.
c02844
Kenzo: Fucking die.
c02845
Delwath: Wait, don't you get two D12 on... Don't you get a bonus D12 on the first staff that hits?
c02846
Kenzo: I do.
c02847
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. So-
c02848
Kenzo: D12
c02849
DM: ... so three D12 on the staff.
c02850
Kenzo: For two hits.
c02851
DM: For two hits, and three D12 on the-
c02852
Kenzo: And for the crit
c02853
DM: ... punches for two hits.
c02854
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay, yeah, that's right.
c02855
Kenzo: Fucking die, motherfucker.
c02856
Wellby: Big numbers. Yeah, okay.
c02857
Kenzo: That's good.
c02858
Unknown: Oh, that's 12. That's 12. That's good.
c02859
Kenzo: Okay, so hold on. 20, 30,
c02860
Kenzo: 38,
c02861
Kenzo: 42.
c02862
Wellby: Plus 32.
c02863
Kenzo: 42 plus 32.
c02864
Delwath: Well, plus the 15 plus-
c02865
Kenzo: Yeah
c02866
Unknown: ... 18 that ti- or 14 plus 18.
c02867
DM: I got it. It's looking pretty weak.
c02868
Kenzo: Close. Oh, yeah, so I go in 70 feet and then I come out 70 feet.
c02869
Kenzo: So I'm at, I stay 70 feet away.
c02870
DM: Uh, yeah, it moves seven, it moves 30 feet in your direction.
c02871
DM: It can't engulf you, but it can shoot two pseudopods at you.
c02872
Kenzo: Come at me. Come at me with your pseudopods.
c02873
Kenzo: [dice rolling]
c02874
DM: That's a
c02875
DM: 26-
c02876
Kenzo: That hits
c02877
DM: ... and a 24.
c02878
Kenzo: They both hit.
c02879
DM: Okay. So the first one is going to do...
c02880
DM: Ooh, that's a good damage roll. 36 points of damage, force damage.
c02881
Kenzo: So, so basically, like, you see, like, this thing, it shoots, like, right through Kenzo's heart.
c02882
Kenzo: He's like, "Ah, I'm dead."
c02883
Kenzo: And then like s- Kenzo magically revitalizes me [laughs].
c02884
DM: [laughs]
c02885
Kenzo: All right. I'm so glad I took that fucking hit point thing.
c02886
Unknown: So-
c02887
Kenzo: Yeah
c02888
Delwath: You at half of the hit points now
c02889
Kenzo: ... uh, so now I'm back to 50%, so whatever 174 over...
c02890
Kenzo: Oh, actually no. It wouldn't be the temporary.
c02891
Kenzo: Half of my original, right?
c02892
Kenzo: Not like-
c02893
DM: No, it's just whatever your hit point maximum, so you're at 87.
c02894
Unknown: Yeah.
c02895
Kenzo: Okay. Fuck yeah. Great.
c02896
Kenzo: Nice.
c02897
Kenzo: All right.
c02898
Delwath: Yeah, the age doesn't go away for eight hours.
c02899
DM: Yeah.
c02900
Kenzo: All right, great.
c02901
Unknown: Or until you die.
c02902
Kenzo: So I'm back at 87.
c02903
Unknown: You capacity it does.
c02904
DM: And then the second one is 21.
c02905
Kenzo: Okay. So I still take that 21 damage.
c02906
DM: Well, unless you reaction block it.
c02907
Kenzo: Yeah, of course I would... I'd do that.
c02908
Kenzo: So now I'm good.
c02909
DM: So you take none.
c02910
Kenzo: A- and then now it does a DC 20.
c02911
Kenzo: Oh, maybe I can kill it here.
c02912
DM: N- uh, yeah, it fails.
c02913
Kenzo: Oh, it fails. Cool. So it, uh, it now-
c02914
DM: Well,
c02915
DM: h- badly hurt. It still has over 100 hit points.
c02916
Kenzo: Okay.
c02917
DM: It's just like around 100.
c02918
Kenzo: I'm gonna... Who's next?
c02919
Unknown: Delwath.
c02920
Kenzo: Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
c02921
DM: Uh, Delwath is next, yeah.
c02922
Kenzo: Seven plus seven, so it does 14 more damage.
c02923
DM: Okay.
c02924
Kenzo: Okay.
c02925
DM: So it
c02926
DM: is finished with its turn as Delwath moves
c02927
DM: to escape.
c02928
Unknown: So-
c02929
DM: Uh, wait. First you take 14 points of force damage
c02930
Unknown: ... why are you doing this?
c02931
Kenzo: Just-
c02932
Delwath: Okay. Um, so [laughs] here's the thing.
c02933
DM: Um, is there... Is...
c02934
Delwath: Wow, that's pretty amazing.
c02935
Unknown: Um,
c02936
Delwath: uh, m, do we...
c02937
Delwath: Are we gonna... I...
c02938
Kenzo: Are we what?
c02939
Delwath: I guess I can't really effectively run away.
c02940
DM: I mean, unless you run into the ash where it can't see you.
c02941
Unknown: Wait.
c02942
Wellby: It can't see us in the ash? This has been an option the entire time?
c02943
DM: I mean,
c02944
DM: I can see you 'cause it has blind sight, but it might not care about you so much.
c02945
Unknown: [sighs]
c02946
DM: If you just don't attack it, it's not gonna attack you.
c02947
DM: It's easy to run away.
c02948
Kenzo: We're so close to killing it, guys.
c02949
Delwath: I know. It's just I won't survive another hit.
c02950
Kenzo: Yeah.
c02951
Delwath: I can bonus action misty step out.
c02952
Kenzo: Cool.
c02953
Delwath: But then I don't have a lot of...
c02954
Delwath: I mean, I could just attack it and hope to kill it.
c02955
Kenzo: Can you smite again?
c02956
Unknown: Nah, I'm out of smites.
c02957
Kenzo: Ah, that sucks. Smite would've been good.
c02958
Unknown: Yeah.
c02959
Wellby: You- you're gonna drop at the end of your turn.
c02960
Wellby: I'm gonna drop at the end of my turn.
c02961
Wellby: Kenzo's gonna drop at the end of his turn.
c02962
DM: No, no. Kenzo's back to 87.
c02963
Unknown: Kenzo's gonna revive.
c02964
Kenzo: Yeah.
c02965
DM: He's all good.
c02966
Wellby: Kenzo's gonna revive us all.
c02967
Delwath: Wait, you have a key that can bring the dead back, right?
c02968
Kenzo: I do.
c02969
Delwath: Ah, screw it. [laughs]
c02970
Kenzo: [laughs]
c02971
Delwath: If I die, if I die, bring me back.
c02972
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, of course. No, but that's only...
c02973
Kenzo: Die, like you have to use all, all your death saving throws too, right?
c02974
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c02975
Kenzo: Yeah.
c02976
Unknown: If that's likely.
c02977
Kenzo: I can bring, I can bring you back.
c02978
Wellby: If we both die, though. [laughs]
c02979
Unknown: [laughs]
c02980
Unknown: If we both die, [laughs] then...
c02981
DM: Then one of you is counting on the scroll of wish.
c02982
Delwath: Uh, but you can't cast...
c02983
Delwath: Oh, you can cast regular resurrection with wish.
c02984
Delwath: You don't need actual resurrection.
c02985
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c02986
Delwath: I will bonus action misty step,
c02987
Delwath: then I will attack it.
c02988
DM: Okay.
c02989
Kenzo: Hell yeah, dude. Fucking finish it off.
c02990
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
c02991
Kenzo: Let's go.
c02992
Unknown: Bonus. Epic.
c02993
Kenzo: I like this. I like this.
c02994
DM: It's gonna attack you, but that's fine.
c02995
Kenzo: We go for the win.
c02996
Delwath: Uh, that hits.
c02997
Wellby: Yes, it does.
c02998
Unknown: I mean,
c02999
Delwath: hopefully it'll be dead before its turn.
c03000
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c03001
Unknown: Yeah.
c03002
Kenzo: You're gonna kill it.
c03003
DM: Yeah, it just cast its-
c03004
Unknown: You're gonna kill it right now
c03005
Delwath: ... it's three legendaries, which just-
c03006
Delwath: That misses
c03007
Wellby: Do you have any inspirations left?
c03008
Delwath: I used my inspiration. I used my heroic.
c03009
Delwath: I can add a 2d8, a 2d4, but that won't make it one into a hit.
c03010
Delwath: Oh my God.
c03011
Kenzo: Whoa.
c03012
Seeker: Is that two ones?
c03013
Seeker: Was that two ones in a row?
c03014
Delwath: No, that's two ones in a row.
c03015
Kenzo: That's insane. Man.
c03016
Delwath: That is one hit.
c03017
DM: You should use your mechanist ability.
c03018
Unknown: I mean, you can't now 'cause you already rolled, but-
c03019
Delwath: I can't now. Oh, I didn't think of that
c03020
DM: ... it's, it's in the sweet spot of AC where that ability is very strong
c03021
Delwath: I, I meant to use it. I meant to use it on...
c03022
Delwath: I actually meant to use it after my first failure.
c03023
Delwath: I, my, my rule is I'm supposed to use it after I fail.
c03024
DM: Fail once, right.
c03025
Delwath: My th- on my third attack, I've always used it.
c03026
DM: You use it, yeah.
c03027
Delwath: But I forgot to say that even though that's what I meant, so I guess...
c03028
Unknown: Ah.
c03029
Kenzo: Fair enough.
c03030
Delwath: It's only an extra 1d8-
c03031
DM: Right
c03032
Unknown: ... damage.
c03033
Wellby: We got this. We got this.
c03034
Delwath: Seven plus...
c03035
Delwath: Actually, it's an extra 1d8 plus 11.
c03036
DM: Yeah.
c03037
Delwath: So seven, that's 16, uh, 16.
c03038
Delwath: Seven, 18. 18.
c03039
DM: Okay. Well, it's-
c03040
Unknown: Uh
c03041
DM: ... it's, it's below 100 now.
c03042
Delwath: Yeah, but [laughs] that's not-
c03043
Wellby: It's not
c03044
Unknown: ... that wasn't-
c03045
Wellby: ... it's not as small of a number as we want it to say
c03046
DM: ... um, and now resistant to slashing.
c03047
Unknown: Uh.
c03048
DM: But you've been quite good at never doubling the same attack.
c03049
Delwath: There's really n-
c03050
Wellby: We can do 100 between the two of us
c03051
Unknown: ... nothing I can do.
c03052
Kenzo: Yeah. We'll live.
c03053
DM: So here comes the pseudopod.
c03054
Delwath: Is that attack roll?
c03055
DM: Yeah.
c03056
Unknown: Okay.
c03057
DM: Um, that's a 29.
c03058
Delwath: I will... Okay.
c03059
Delwath: Gotta roll a four or higher.
c03060
Unknown: For what?
c03061
Delwath: To dodge it automatically with Tanji's, with the Tanji blessing.
c03062
Wellby: Come on, Tanji blessing.
c03063
Wellby: [laughs]
c03064
DM: Try again. [laughs]
c03065
Unknown: [laughs] Oh, no.
c03066
Unknown: Three straight ones.
c03067
DM: Three straight ones doesn't seem fair.
c03068
DM: 30 points of force damage.
c03069
Delwath: Shalub goes down.
c03070
DM: As the pseudopod smacks into Delwath.
c03071
DM: That's one legendary action down.
c03072
DM: Seeker is up.
c03073
Seeker: um, all right. Hive Mind I need your help here.
c03074
Unknown: Um, all right.
c03075
Kenzo: I think you should attack it. We, we have like, we're, we just need to like kill it.
c03076
Wellby: Let's finish kill-
c03077
Unknown: Yeah
c03078
Wellby: ... yeah, kill the slime.
c03079
Unknown: It's currently resistant to slashing.
c03080
Wellby: All of this like special whatever...
c03081
Wellby: Huh?
c03082
DM: It's currently resistant to slashing, so your damage is gonna be half.
c03083
Wellby: Okay. So I should-
c03084
Unknown: Yeah
c03085
Wellby: ... just use my multi attack.
c03086
Unknown: Overload your-
c03087
Unknown: Yeah.
c03088
Wellby: Yeah.
c03089
Kenzo: Let's just fucking damage it.
c03090
Wellby: All right.
c03091
Delwath: And yeah.
c03092
Seeker: All right. [dice rolling] So that's a 25-
c03093
Unknown: Yep
c03094
Wellby: ... and a 19.
c03095
Unknown: 19 misses.
c03096
Wellby: 2d-
c03097
Delwath: What did, what did- 2d 12 plus 8, or 2d 10.
c03098
Unknown: I don't know which one was which.
c03099
Seeker: Uh, it was the first one, so 2d 12.
c03100
DM: Yeah. Yeah. [dice rolling] [laughs] Oh my God.
c03101
Unknown: Wow.
c03102
Unknown: I'm rolling so badly.
c03103
Wellby: You're rolling so bad.
c03104
Seeker: So a total of tw- three one.
c03105
Unknown: The campaign doesn't want to end.
c03106
Wellby: Yeah.
c03107
Unknown: That's all. It's like it knows.
c03108
Unknown: 12 damage.
c03109
Kenzo: It's trying to just stretch this battle out.
c03110
Unknown: It's now resistant to bludgeoning.
c03111
Kenzo: Uh-oh. Okay.
c03112
Kenzo: That's okay. You're gonna pierce it.
c03113
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
c03114
Unknown: Wellby's up.
c03115
Delwath: But you can legendary... You should do a slam legendary after Wellby's attack.
c03116
Unknown: Okay. Uh-
c03117
Wellby: To reset it again?
c03118
DM: It's gonna try to squeeze you now.
c03119
Delwath: Oh, no, but then it'll be resistant for-
c03120
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, so I shouldn't use it again.
c03121
Unknown: Yeah.
c03122
DM: Uh, it's gonna try and squeeze you.
c03123
DM: You're inside it. That's its next legendary.
c03124
Unknown: Nice.
c03125
Wellby: Okay.
c03126
Unknown: So like that, like that.
c03127
Unknown: So strength save with disadvantage.
c03128
Wellby: Yes. [dice rolling] Easy peasy.
c03129
Unknown: We got this.
c03130
Unknown: [dice rolling] Nice.
c03131
Wellby: That's a five.
c03132
Unknown: Great.
c03133
Wellby: Disadvantage.
c03134
Unknown: Oh, no.
c03135
Seeker: So it's a 10. So fail.
c03136
DM: So you take 20 points of force damage.
c03137
Wellby: Oh, no. How much are you down to now?
c03138
Unknown: [laughs] 226.
c03139
Wellby: [laughs]
c03140
Delwath: It's very close to [laughs] 200.
c03141
Wellby: [laughs] Down to your last 400 hit points.
c03142
Unknown: [laughs]
c03143
Unknown: [laughs] So heal me actually.
c03144
DM: That ends Seeker's turn.
c03145
Unknown: [laughs]
c03146
DM: As the sixth round of combat begins, Wellby is hovering in the air far above it, nearly dead, but not dead.
c03147
Wellby: Not dead.
c03148
DM: Um, Delwath is unconscious on the ground and seemingly out of the ooze's mind.
c03149
DM: Kenzo is-
c03150
Unknown: 70 feet away
c03151
DM: ... 70 feet away. Well, move 30 feet towards me, so you're-
c03152
Unknown: 40 feet away
c03153
DM: ... 40 feet away from it.
c03154
DM: Um, and Seeker is still trying to figure out how to do something to it.
c03155
Unknown: [laughs]
c03156
Seeker: Usefully acting as part of combat.
c03157
DM: And the, Wellby is up.
c03158
Unknown: [laughs]
c03159
Wellby: Uh, Wellby is not taking chances.
c03160
Wellby: He uses the arrow of seeking, and you see him just shoot it randomly at nothing and it turns and zooms down.
c03161
Wellby: Just checking if I crit, and I do.
c03162
Wellby: [laughs]
c03163
Unknown: Yeah.
c03164
Unknown: Yay.
c03165
Unknown: Hell yeah. Finish it off Wellby.
c03166
Wellby: Oh, fuck yeah. Okay. [dice shaking]
c03167
Unknown: Good job.
c03168
Wellby: So we got some dice.
c03169
Unknown: Thank you.
c03170
Wellby: Here's the first set.
c03171
Wellby: Uh-
c03172
Unknown: Wow
c03173
Wellby: ... 12, 16, 21.
c03174
Unknown: Oh, he's gonna do it.
c03175
Wellby: 22, 23.
c03176
Unknown: He's gonna do it.
c03177
Wellby: And six is 20, uh, nine.
c03178
Wellby: Remember that?
c03179
Unknown: 29.
c03180
Unknown: Oh, that's a much better roll.
c03181
Wellby: 29, uh, 31, 36, uh, 42, 46,
c03182
Wellby: uh, what?
c03183
Wellby: 52, uh, 57, 59 plus 8 is 60-
c03184
Unknown: Plus 29?
c03185
Delwath: ... seven. Or no, total.
c03186
Unknown: Oh, 67 total.
c03187
Wellby: 67 total.
c03188
DM: Nothing... It's, I mean, it's writhing.
c03189
DM: This mass is, mass is writhing, and you start to see it's beginning to pull away from the center and it's beginning to de- decohere a little bit.
c03190
Wellby: Wellby sighs
c03191
Wellby: and points the bow at it and attacks a second time.
c03192
Wellby: That's a hit, 18.
c03193
Wellby: [dice rolling] That's another nine points of damage.
c03194
Wellby: 78 all together.
c03195
DM: Uh, it's, it's thinning out and the ooze is sort of bubbling around the sides.
c03196
Wellby: All right.
c03197
Delwath: And you can see now the, the,
c03198
DM: where Seeker is, the crystal sphere kind of now mostly clear as it begins to spread out over a larger and larger range.
c03199
Unknown: Um-
c03200
Wellby: Uh, and then with his move, Wellby flies down to the ground and just sort of puts his bow down and waits for the hit to come.
c03201
Unknown: [laughs]
c03202
DM: Uh, and with his last legendary action.
c03203
Unknown: [laughs]
c03204
Unknown: Oh my God. [laughs]
c03205
DM: Sorry, legendary action, it smacks Wellby in the face.
c03206
Wellby: Oh my God.
c03207
Unknown: Um...
c03208
Unknown: [laughs]
c03209
Wellby: [laughs]
c03210
DM: And that is 27 points of force damage.
c03211
Wellby: And Wellby hits the ground.
c03212
Unknown: Oh my God.
c03213
Wellby: Well- Wellby is already going to sit down as the ooze is like...
c03214
Wellby: [laughs]
c03215
Unknown: Kenzo is up.
c03216
Unknown: Oh my God.
c03217
Unknown: You just have to kill it.
c03218
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, of course. Kenzo, or Kenzo's like, you know, a hundred, like flying, like watching, you know, fucking Delwath like [laughs] goes unconscious.
c03219
Kenzo: Like, and, uh, Wellby goes unconscious.
c03220
Kenzo: And, and then as he like flies in to go and make what he hopes is gonna be the killing attacks, like, you know, gives like a kiss attack-
c03221
Kenzo: [laughs] On the way down. Buzzing, buzzing to Wellby on the way down
c03222
Wellby: [laughs]
c03223
Kenzo: And then [laughs] tries to deliver the, uh, fatal blows to this fucking ooze.
c03224
Wellby: [coughs]
c03225
Kenzo: [laughs] Okay, uh, all right.
c03226
Kenzo: So three staff attacks.
c03227
Kenzo: So I'll start with the three staff attacks.
c03228
Unknown: And... Oh, crit.
c03229
Wellby: Oh.
c03230
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c03231
Unknown: Crit. They all, uh-
c03232
Unknown: They all hit, yeah.
c03233
Unknown: So-
c03234
Unknown: I need-
c03235
Delwath: It's 22. You have one at 15
c03236
Kenzo: ... yeah, plus 15. Yeah, all three hit.
c03237
Unknown: All three-
c03238
Unknown: All three hit
c03239
DM: ... do, do the... Roll your damage one at a time.
c03240
Kenzo: Okay. Um, well-
c03241
Wellby: You gotta roll the crit first
c03242
Kenzo: ... I, I gotta... I'm gonna roll my...
c03243
Kenzo: Do I, shall I roll my punches too, just as well, make it a-
c03244
Unknown: Well, I mean, just-
c03245
Kenzo: I'll do the staff. I'll do the... start with the staff
c03246
DM: ... start... Roll damage for each attack separately.
c03247
Kenzo: Okay. So, uh, I should do the crit first.
c03248
Unknown: Okay.
c03249
Unknown: So like I do two, 2d10s.
c03250
Delwath: So that's 4d12 'cause-
c03251
Unknown: Oh
c03252
DM: ... well, whatever, it doesn't matter, 2d12.
c03253
DM: I don't know which one was the first.
c03254
Unknown: The f- this is the first one.
c03255
Unknown: Okay.
c03256
Kenzo: So this is 12 plus-
c03257
Unknown: Nine
c03258
Unknown: ... nine.
c03259
Kenzo: Oh, no. No, no. Is it turning into more...
c03260
Kenzo: No, no.
c03261
Wellby: Oh, it's turning into a bunch of little things?
c03262
Unknown: No.
c03263
Unknown: Oh.
c03264
c03265
Seeker: What are, what are all those things?
c03266
Unknown: Oh my God.
c03267
Wellby: So it's got another form.
c03268
DM: So as you hit it, the sphere, it...
c03269
DM: The... a bunch of the mass of the ooze flies out in all directions, forming
c03270
DM: little minions.
c03271
Seeker: Let's clear out the...
c03272
Unknown: Yeah.
c03273
Wellby: But if we don't attack them, they won't attack us, so we'll be fine.
c03274
Unknown: Ah.
c03275
Unknown: You don't have to worry about anything.
c03276
Unknown: I mean, these ones won't be fine.
c03277
DM: Just, uh, rest in peace for now. The, the ooze is not dead.
c03278
DM: The crystal sphere is just exposed.
c03279
Unknown: Um...
c03280
Kenzo: Well, I, I flew in to the...
c03281
Kenzo: So I'm not even over here. I'm, I'm like in here someplace.
c03282
Wellby: You were diving down.
c03283
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I, I tried... I remember I went by.
c03284
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c03285
Kenzo: I, so I'm in here someplace.
c03286
DM: So 100 feet is like 120, so you're like-
c03287
Unknown: 140
c03288
DM: ... 140, so you're like-
c03289
Kenzo: I was 40 feet away, so I could be 100 feet in.
c03290
DM: Yeah, so you're 100 feet in, so you're like 60 feet from the sphere.
c03291
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
c03292
Unknown: Okay.
c03293
Unknown: Uh-
c03294
DM: And still immune to all damage but thunder.
c03295
Kenzo: Wait, so now what the fuck am I attacking if I'm inside the thing?
c03296
Unknown: You should... I don't know.
c03297
Delwath: You should, you should maybe kill some of the minions.
c03298
Kenzo: How far away are the minions?
c03299
DM: Well, they got scattered on the edges of the ooze.
c03300
Unknown: What do the minions look like?
c03301
DM: They look like little small oozes.
c03302
Seeker: We gotta take out the crystal.
c03303
Kenzo: Hold on. Yeah. Well, can I, can I, um...
c03304
Kenzo: Okay. So if I use, for example-
c03305
Unknown: Do some damage?
c03306
Kenzo: ... that first attack was my haste attack, let's say.
c03307
Unknown: Yeah.
c03308
Kenzo: Then can I use, um, like a dash to then get-
c03309
DM: That's your bonus action to dash
c03310
Unknown: [coughs]
c03311
DM: You can actually use the haste attack to dash.
c03312
Kenzo: Okay, fine. So if I use the haste attack to dash-
c03313
Wellby: Then you have your bonus action to attack the minions?
c03314
Unknown: No.
c03315
Unknown: Well, no, no, the, the sphere.
c03316
Wellby: The sphere. Sorry, yeah.
c03317
Unknown: Can you do thunder damage?
c03318
Unknown: Huh?
c03319
Unknown: Do you have a way to do thunder damage?
c03320
Kenzo: It can only, it can only do thunder damage?
c03321
DM: At the moment it is a solid crystal sphere that is immune to all damage but thunder.
c03322
Unknown: Yeah.
c03323
Kenzo: What? Stone giant key.
c03324
DM: What the fuck can I do? Thunder damage?
c03325
Unknown: Fucking bitch.
c03326
Kenzo: So force damage is too... it's immune to force damage.
c03327
Delwath: But also, um,
c03328
Delwath: somebody needs to come heal Delweth and Wellby.
c03329
Unknown: Yeah.
c03330
Seeker: Inspiration boosted attacks
c03331
Seeker: get like d12 thunder damage, doesn't it?
c03332
Unknown: That's true.
c03333
Delwath: I mean, you could stop being Leviathan.
c03334
DM: There's no... You're not currently...
c03335
DM: It's-
c03336
Unknown: Yeah. Now I-
c03337
Seeker: ... it's like spread out in a thin layer
c03338
Seeker: ... now I can zoom out.
c03339
Seeker: I can, I can fly out now probably, or...
c03340
Unknown: Anyway.
c03341
DM: Yeah, yeah. So it, it loses its engulfing trait and it gains lots of minions and some other traits.
c03342
Unknown: Oh, boy.
c03343
Unknown: Okay.
c03344
Seeker: So yeah, I should on my...
c03345
Seeker: Oh, no. I can use a legendary action-
c03346
Unknown: Okay
c03347
Seeker: ... after Kenzo's turn to start with-
c03348
DM: You can use a legendary action after Kenzo's turn, but what's Kenzo doing on his turn?
c03349
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c03350
Kenzo: Well, I'm trying to figure this out, 'cause if...
c03351
Kenzo: So the, the cube, it's resistant to everything but thunder, but then what changes that for the cube?
c03352
Seeker: We don't know. It has... We have only seen it do-
c03353
DM: You attempted to shift it into a-
c03354
Unknown: Ball of feathers
c03355
DM: ... ball of feathers, but Seeker did not quite roll high enough.
c03356
Kenzo: Oh, so you still need to keep doing that I think,
c03357
Kenzo: probably, like using your hit to like make it-
c03358
Seeker: Well, ver- versus try to hit it with thunder damage, which we can do if I just give anyone inspiration and they roll an attack.
c03359
DM: Right. Well, that's only 1d12 thunder.
c03360
Unknown: Not that much damage. That might not be enough, yeah.
c03361
Kenzo: Oh, Jesus Christ. Okay.
c03362
Seeker: Can my glove flavor my own attacks as thunder damage?
c03363
Unknown: Yep.
c03364
Unknown: So in that case-
c03365
DM: Oh, not your attacks. It can change your spells
c03366
Unknown: ... spells.
c03367
Wellby: So you'd have to un- Leviath- I think Leviathan's served its purpose for this fight
c03368
Unknown: Yeah, I think it's served its purpose.
c03369
Seeker: I think I, I think I need... But I need to get clear of the ooze first.
c03370
Unknown: Well, there's no ooze left to get clear from.
c03371
DM: Well, there... I mean, it still exists, it just lose its engulf trait.
c03372
DM: So it can't do force damage to you.
c03373
Kenzo: All right. Let me try to heal you guys then instead then.
c03374
Kenzo: I really don't want to touch acid.
c03375
Unknown: I feel like I need to...
c03376
Unknown: You don't want to what?
c03377
Seeker: It's the ac- it's the being attacked by the ooze and getting injured as Seeker.
c03378
Seeker: So maybe I just have to be brave for a bit.
c03379
Delwath: Yeah, I think it's time for Seeker to be brave.
c03380
Unknown: [laughs]
c03381
Kenzo: Ugh, Tim, do I have any way to heal these guys?
c03382
Unknown: Yep. You can change your...
c03383
DM: You can change the damage of any spell into acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder.
c03384
Unknown: Yeah.
c03385
Delwath: I mean, if you can get over, you can at worst administer a potion.
c03386
Kenzo: I only... I've got one potion left.
c03387
Kenzo: Wow, you fucking saved me a potion.
c03388
Unknown: I have a potion too.
c03389
Unknown: Did I give all my potions? Did I give you all my potions?
c03390
Unknown: No, you gave them all as you-
c03391
Wellby: You did. Yeah, you gave us all of them
c03392
Kenzo: ... I gave all, I gave everyone all my potions.
c03393
Unknown: Well-
c03394
Wellby: Tim, give me a potion
c03395
DM: ... you have a potion.
c03396
DM: It's a, it's a, it's a free action to grab a potion off of his belt and then an action to administer it.
c03397
Wellby: I have no potions left.
c03398
Unknown: Oh.
c03399
Wellby: So you drank them all.
c03400
Delwath: I have two potions if I want to heal him.
c03401
DM: Okay. So you can fly over Delweth, grab a potion off of his belt-
c03402
Unknown: And give it to him
c03403
DM: ... and give it to him. But it takes your action.
c03404
Unknown: Right.
c03405
Unknown: You could do it from the outside.
c03406
Wellby: But then you can move and use your haste action to fly to the other side.
c03407
DM: Well, he already used his- Use-
c03408
Wellby: Anyways, it gets us started anyways
c03409
Unknown: ... yeah.
c03410
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. But I used my hasted action to kill the-
c03411
DM: Used his hasted action to kill the thing.
c03412
Unknown: Yeah.
c03413
Kenzo: So I still have two actions and a bonus action.
c03414
Unknown: You still have one action-
c03415
Unknown: One action
c03416
Unknown: ... and a bonus action.
c03417
Unknown: And a move
c03418
Wellby: And a move, but you moved up.
c03419
DM: You m- already moved 100 feet in.
c03420
Unknown: Well, I was only moving 100-
c03421
Kenzo: So you need to use your... You'd have to move...
c03422
DM: You'd have to use your bonus action to dash, and then your-
c03423
Unknown: Action to-
c03424
Unknown: ... action to-
c03425
Unknown: To administer a potion
c03426
Unknown: ... administer the potion.
c03427
Kenzo: Okay. And then can you do more stuff after your, your wake?
c03428
Unknown: Uh,
c03429
Unknown: sort of.
c03430
Unknown: Like a-
c03431
Unknown: I mean, yes.
c03432
Delwath: I just... I won't have that many hit points, so...
c03433
Delwath: But, yes. I mean, I could, I could...
c03434
Delwath: If I take a round, I can get back a spell slot.
c03435
Unknown: Like-
c03436
Delwath: And then I could do a lot of damage.
c03437
Kenzo: So I guess it's like, it's better to wake...
c03438
Kenzo: Which one of you is it better to, to wake up?
c03439
Unknown: I think you.
c03440
Unknown: You?
c03441
Delwath: I can also Healing Word you.
c03442
Unknown: Okay.
c03443
Delwath: As soon as I'm awake, I can Healing Word him.
c03444
Kenzo: All right. I will do that. I will, I will do all the things.
c03445
Delwath: 'Cause I still have a charm of Healing Word from-
c03446
Unknown: Right
c03447
Delwath: ... although I guess that's probably a first level
c03448
Unknown: I don't have any
c03449
Unknown: Yes
c03450
Unknown: ...
c03451
Unknown: more healing.
c03452
Unknown: All right. I will, uh-
c03453
Delwath: But still get him up.
c03454
Unknown: Yep.
c03455
Kenzo: All right. After killing the ooze, I will fly back out and, uh, give...
c03456
Delwath: So I get my potion of greater healing?
c03457
Unknown: Yes.
c03458
Unknown: [grunts]
c03459
DM: So you're now over next to Delwath.
c03460
Delwath: Five
c03461
Delwath: and four is nine, plus...
c03462
Unknown: And that ends your turn.
c03463
Wellby: This is nice too. Neither one of us will lose turns in the order.
c03464
Unknown: Yep.
c03465
Kenzo: Uh, it is the ooze's turn.
c03466
Unknown: Oh, so now we can-
c03467
Unknown: Nine plus four
c03468
Unknown: ...
c03469
Unknown: I guess.
c03470
DM: And it is going to,
c03471
DM: um, first
c03472
Unknown: u- use its,
c03473
DM: uh, command minions trait to make these minions attack.
c03474
DM: There should be a few more there.
c03475
DM: There should be five on each.
c03476
Unknown: I don't have enough here. There's
c03477
DM: three more there and two more over there.
c03478
Kenzo: Four. Oh, and this is only four here.
c03479
Unknown: Yeah, one more there.
c03480
DM: To make those five minions attack Kenzo.
c03481
Unknown: Um,
c03482
DM: and that will be a...
c03483
Unknown: Oh.
c03484
DM: Oh, that's only an 18.
c03485
Unknown: That misses.
c03486
Unknown: So the minions miss.
c03487
Unknown: Nice.
c03488
DM: Um, and then it is going to make, uh, two pseudopod attacks against Kenzo.
c03489
DM: That's a 27 and a 23.
c03490
Kenzo: Okay, only one of those hits.
c03491
DM: So you take another 24 points of force damage.
c03492
Wellby: Hold on. The main ooze is still making pseudopod attacks?
c03493
Unknown: Yeah.
c03494
Kenzo: No, except it doesn't. I, uh-
c03495
Unknown: Oh, you-
c03496
Kenzo: I just... I got my reaction back, so.
c03497
Unknown: Okay.
c03498
Kenzo: 20, so DC 20.
c03499
Unknown: This is not over.
c03500
DM: Yeah. The, um, you, you redirect the damage, but it just splashes harmlessly on the ooze.
c03501
Delwath: Yeah, the ooze is unkillable.
c03502
Unknown: We have to-
c03503
Unknown: Mm-hmm
c03504
DM: ... destroy the center thing.
c03505
DM: Um, and then let's see.
c03506
DM: Nope, it doesn't get its bonus action back.
c03507
DM: Um, so
c03508
DM: there's nobody else
c03509
DM: standing.
c03510
DM: Wellby's not standing. There's nobody over there.
c03511
DM: There's nobody over there. So none of the other minions are gonna do anything.
c03512
Unknown: Okay, that ends the ooze's turn.
c03513
Unknown: Uh, Delwath is up.
c03514
Delwath: Okay. Uh, how far away is Wellby from me?
c03515
Delwath: You landed sort of-
c03516
Kenzo: This is an appropriately insane last combat.
c03517
Unknown: Like...
c03518
Unknown: It is. It's insane.
c03519
Unknown: Yeah, you're not that far.
c03520
Kenzo: 30 fucking miles.
c03521
Unknown: 30 feet away, I guess.
c03522
Delwath: Um, okay. I gotta plan this out a little bit though.
c03523
Unknown: So-
c03524
Kenzo: And it still has two legendary saves
c03525
Delwath: ... my action... I... Hold on, I gotta...
c03526
Delwath: [coughs] Sorry, I have to look at some features that I've, like, never used before.
c03527
Unknown: Jesus.
c03528
Delwath: Uh, do I... Can I expend a...
c03529
Delwath: I can expend a slot to-
c03530
Unknown: So if you stop being a bard-
c03531
Delwath: I can expend a slot to get back-
c03532
Kenzo: ... for something a little while, then you can give inspiration again
c03533
Unknown: ... sorcery points, right?
c03534
Unknown: That's true.
c03535
Delwath: C- create... Convert spell slots, no action.
c03536
Unknown: Yep.
c03537
Unknown: How much? I get
c03538
Unknown: two.
c03539
Unknown: Sure.
c03540
Unknown: This is bad.
c03541
DM: With a second level spot, you get-
c03542
Unknown: Yeah, I'm gonna be up in a minute though
c03543
Unknown: ... I don't have any spell slots.
c03544
Unknown: Of course.
c03545
Unknown: First level slot?
c03546
Unknown: Yeah.
c03547
c03548
Wellby: From the cutting action, disengage, and fly up.
c03549
Unknown: No, equal to the slot level.
c03550
Unknown: Nice.
c03551
Unknown: You get one.
c03552
Delwath: Okay. Well, one is all I need to quicken something.
c03553
Wellby: And then get hit by a flying pseudopod attack.
c03554
Unknown: Uh-
c03555
Unknown: And go down again
c03556
Unknown: ... but-
c03557
Unknown: But that's like a next round thing
c03558
Delwath: ... I kind of need to get Wellby up, so I have to use my bonus action for that.
c03559
DM: To cast this... To cast Healing Word, you mean?
c03560
Unknown: Yeah.
c03561
DM: Is it worth it to, um...
c03562
Delwath: So I could do thunder damage.
c03563
Unknown: It's crazy.
c03564
Delwath: I could either get Wellby up or do thunder damage.
c03565
Kenzo: Well, if you don't get Wellby up, he's gonna die, 'cause there's five dudes that are just gonna fucking kill him.
c03566
Seeker: Yeah, get him up.
c03567
Unknown: Yeah, okay.
c03568
Seeker: I have an idea for...
c03569
Seeker: I could use the Scroll of Wish.
c03570
Unknown: Yeah, use that.
c03571
Seeker: And cast Shatter.
c03572
DM: Why don't you just use your glove to change-
c03573
Unknown: To change
c03574
DM: ... something into thunder damage?
c03575
Delwath: Yeah. Catapult into thunder damage.
c03576
Unknown: Or chain lightning.
c03577
Unknown: Yeah.
c03578
Seeker: The question is about the saves, but...
c03579
Unknown: Yeah, or-
c03580
DM: But chain lightning does half damage even without the save.
c03581
Unknown: Damage, yes. Okay.
c03582
Unknown: That's true.
c03583
Delwath: Uh, I'm going to,
c03584
Delwath: um, then in that case run away.
c03585
Kenzo: Yeah, what's your, what's your, what's your Seeker name?
c03586
Unknown: Uh, yeah.
c03587
Unknown: Seeker.
c03588
Unknown: Heals your... Heals the wish
c03589
Delwath: Healing Word Wellby.
c03590
Unknown: How much is that?
c03591
Delwath: It's first level.
c03592
Unknown: Uh, not a lot.
c03593
Unknown: Um, let me check.
c03594
Kenzo: Okay, when does the l- when does the l- the, the ooze attack?
c03595
Delwath: 2d4 plus five.
c03596
Unknown: Oh, the ooze's turn, yeah.
c03597
Unknown: Uh, it just went.
c03598
Unknown: Oh, good. Perfect.
c03599
Unknown: So you all get turns before the ooze.
c03600
Unknown: Oh, cool.
c03601
DM: It still has its refreshed legendary actions.
c03602
Unknown: I'm not gonna roll a lot.
c03603
DM: So it still has its legendary actions.
c03604
Delwath: Can you check for me?
c03605
Wellby: Big numbers, big numbers.
c03606
Unknown: [laughs]
c03607
Unknown: That's...
c03608
Unknown: Seven?
c03609
Unknown: Yeah. At least, I-
c03610
Unknown: Seven? Okay. Um-
c03611
Unknown: [laughs]
c03612
Unknown: That.
c03613
Unknown: But I'm up. I'm up.
c03614
Delwath: Oh, actually I have lots of first level slots left.
c03615
Delwath: Oh, wait. I have a second level slot.
c03616
DM: I should, I should have...
c03617
Unknown: Well, it's okay.
c03618
Unknown: Turn away.
c03619
Unknown: I'm not gonna...
c03620
Unknown: Turn this
c03621
Unknown: way.
c03622
Delwath: And then with my action, I'm gonna get back
c03623
Unknown: a warlock slot.
c03624
Delwath: And then I'm going to move...
c03625
Unknown: [coughs]
c03626
Unknown: [laughs]
c03627
Delwath: I'm going to move 60 feet
c03628
Kenzo: I understand you.
c03629
Unknown: I understand you.
c03630
DM: So you did not attack the ooze?
c03631
Delwath: I did not attack the ooze, no.
c03632
Unknown: Okay.
c03633
Delwath: I moved 60 feet away over here.
c03634
Unknown: Okay. So that ends your turn?
c03635
Unknown: Yep.
c03636
DM: Uh, well, it's gonna use a legendary action against Kenza then.
c03637
Unknown: Good.
c03638
Kenzo: Come at me, bro.
c03639
DM: Yeah, that's a 19 on the die, so that hits.
c03640
DM: And that's gonna deal
c03641
DM: 23 points of force damage.
c03642
Unknown: Dude, why does it keep doing force damage?
c03643
Delwath: It's done force damage the whole game, the whole combat.
c03644
DM: So that's one legendary. Seeker's up.
c03645
Kenzo: Take it out, Seeker.
c03646
Seeker: So I just gotta hit it with anything and then-
c03647
Unknown: That does thunder damage
c03648
Seeker: ... use, use the...
c03649
Unknown: So I-
c03650
Delwath: Yeah. Chain lightning it
c03651
Seeker: ... I'm just gonna stay where I am.
c03652
Unknown: Yeah.
c03653
Unknown: There you go.
c03654
Unknown: And-
c03655
Delwath: You don't even have to... Oh, no, you have to be Seeker.
c03656
DM: You have to be Seeker to use the glove.
c03657
Seeker: Yes. And remove my, um, shape change.
c03658
Unknown: Be brave, Seeker.
c03659
Seeker: [laughs] When I use the Glove of Crystalized Magic to convert the damage type to thunder of...
c03660
Delwath: Eighth level chain lightning.
c03661
Unknown: Eighth level.
c03662
DM: Well, it doesn't scale.
c03663
Unknown: Oh, it doesn't scale.
c03664
Unknown: Yeah.
c03665
Unknown: The damage is-
c03666
DM: It deals the lowest level you can-
c03667
Unknown: Yeah, never mind
c03668
DM: ... 'cause there's no other targets.
c03669
Unknown: Oh.
c03670
Unknown: Eric, it's your call.
c03671
Seeker: Um, what's the lowest level for chain lightning?
c03672
Delwath: Sixth. Do you have a sixth slot left?
c03673
Seeker: I do not.
c03674
Unknown: Do you have a seventh?
c03675
Unknown: I do not.
c03676
Unknown: Oh, does-
c03677
Seeker: Oh, I do have a seventh.
c03678
DM: Kong, were you also recording this?
c03679
Kenzo: recording the, the thing, but I'm just-
c03680
DM: Okay
c03681
Kenzo: ... recording the video with Eric
c03682
DM: 'Cause my recording just stopped.
c03683
Unknown: Yeah, you just have to-
c03684
DM: Let me restart it
c03685
Unknown: All right.
c03686
Seeker: Seventh level-
c03687
DM: Okay
c03688
Seeker: ... chain lightning.
c03689
Seeker: That's a,
c03690
Seeker: a DC 19 dex save.
c03691
Unknown: Uh, uses a legendary.
c03692
Unknown: Nice.
c03693
DM: So it takes half damage.
c03694
Seeker: Which is?
c03695
DM: So roll your damage. So this, okay, so Seeker appears in the puddle of ooze, holds up his glove,
c03696
DM: and this burst of thunderous lightning shoots out of his hand, very Limbo-esque, and it strikes the sphere, and the
c03697
DM: sphere begins resonating. Roll your damage.
c03698
Seeker: That's, uh, 36 divided by two, I guess.
c03699
DM: Not divided by two because it's vulnerable to thunder damage.
c03700
Seeker: Ah.
c03701
DM: So it takes 36 points of damage.
c03702
DM: Little cracks start to appear, but not big cracks.
c03703
Seeker: And I can bonus action inspiration anybody who's likely to damage it, because they will then do thunder damage.
c03704
Delwath: Uh, who's next in the...
c03705
Unknown: Uh, Wellby.
c03706
DM: Wait. All right, Wellby's next.
c03707
Delwath: Oh, you can do thunder damage?
c03708
Wellby: If you, can you turn my piercing into thunder?
c03709
Unknown: No.
c03710
DM: It's just a 1d12 thunder.
c03711
Delwath: It's 1d12 extra thunder.
c03712
Delwath: I mean, more likely it's probably good to bonus action to give inspiration to somebody who's likely to need the-
c03713
DM: Sorry, that was 36 damage you said?
c03714
Unknown: Need the saving throw.
c03715
Unknown: Yep.
c03716
Seeker: Yeah.
c03717
Unknown: Whether that's what, I mean-
c03718
Wellby: We're both gonna die even if we make the saves though.
c03719
Delwath: That's a good point. [laughs]
c03720
Unknown: Maybe Kenzo.
c03721
Unknown: So maybe just give it to Kenzo.
c03722
Unknown: Give it to Kenzo.
c03723
Delwath: Our shining hope.
c03724
Kenzo: But wait, how, but I can't do thunder damage to-
c03725
Delwath: No, no, no. An inspiration's that you can stay up if you have to, if you have to make a save-
c03726
Seeker: Oh yeah, yeah
c03727
Unknown: ... you can use it.
c03728
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c03729
Kenzo: I, I'm actually, I mean-
c03730
DM: Although the force damage saves
c03731
Delwath: ... now I could, I could do thunder damage.
c03732
Wellby: Mm-mm.
c03733
Delwath: I can use a spell.
c03734
Seeker: Do it.
c03735
Kenzo: Because you can do automatic inspirations, you can do, uh, uh, reaction inspirations, so not your-
c03736
Seeker: Is, is that true?
c03737
DM: We've been unclear.
c03738
DM: No, we've been sort of uncl- It's not really.
c03739
DM: I mean, sure, whatever.
c03740
DM: We've been unclear about it. It's not really the rules.
c03741
Unknown: Um-
c03742
Kenzo: He's 20, he's a 20th level bard.
c03743
DM: But-
c03744
Seeker: Come on. I'm really inspiring.
c03745
DM: It's fine. The reason we stopped is 'cause it's kind of annoying to always be tracking reactions because-
c03746
Unknown: Right
c03747
DM: ... you know, everybody has a lot of things to do in a reaction.
c03748
Delwath: Just use a bonus action to give-
c03749
Seeker: That's what I was gonna do, yeah.
c03750
DM: No.
c03751
Seeker: Give it to one person. I'll give it to
c03752
Seeker: Kenzo.
c03753
Unknown: Give it to Kenzo.
c03754
Delwath: Yeah. Kenzo's good. I mean, yeah, give it to Kenzo.
c03755
DM: Uh, it's going to attack you with a pseudopod.
c03756
DM: That's a natural 20.
c03757
Seeker: Oh God.
c03758
Unknown: You'll be fine.
c03759
DM: Um-
c03760
Unknown: Don't you have like 190 hit points?
c03761
Seeker: So I, I removed my temp hit points, so I just-
c03762
DM: So you take
c03763
DM: tw- uh, 20, 32-
c03764
Unknown: You have 190 hit points
c03765
DM: ... 33-
c03766
Kenzo: You're great
c03767
DM: ... 36 points of force damage.
c03768
DM: Uh,
c03769
DM: okay.
c03770
Seeker: Guys, I'm really hurt.
c03771
Unknown: [laughs]
c03772
Seeker: [laughs]
c03773
Delwath: Tollen's gonna attack you. [laughs]
c03774
DM: Um.
c03775
Unknown: Two hours ago.
c03776
Unknown: Do you know what this is like? [laughs]
c03777
DM: Wellby is up.
c03778
Seeker: I didn't know that, Kenzo.
c03779
Unknown: [laughs]
c03780
Kenzo: [laughs] This brave, courageous adventurer.
c03781
Seeker: Note that I did later dive into the center of the ooze.
c03782
Kenzo: You did. You did. You're doing great.
c03783
Unknown: You did great.
c03784
Delwath: I mean, killing minions is beneficial-
c03785
Unknown: Right
c03786
Unknown: ... 'cause they can kill you if you don't kill them.
c03787
Seeker: Combat is therapy, really.
c03788
Unknown: Yeah, it is.
c03789
Seeker: It is real.
c03790
Unknown: It ki- it kind of is actually.
c03791
Unknown: We'll make a save.
c03792
Unknown: For Seeker it is.
c03793
Wellby: Sure, so, um-
c03794
Kenzo: Yeah. So the more bravery you can show in combat, the more healed you are.
c03795
Unknown: Okay.
c03796
Seeker: Uh.
c03797
Wellby: Uh, 9,
c03798
Wellby: 20.
c03799
DM: Wait, why are you rolling two?
c03800
Wellby: I don't know.
c03801
Unknown: [laughs]
c03802
DM: [laughs]
c03803
Wellby: Actually, because I've been used to rolling two this whole time.
c03804
Seeker: Wait, was that a 27 you said?
c03805
Wellby: That was a two and a five. Should I just re-
c03806
DM: Oh, no, no, the two still hits.
c03807
Wellby: Should you just re-roll? [laughs]
c03808
Unknown: Two, okay.
c03809
DM: So re-roll.
c03810
Unknown: Should he just re-roll?
c03811
DM: The minions don't have a high AC.
c03812
Wellby: Well, I rolled them both at once.
c03813
DM: You have a plus 15?
c03814
Wellby: With the scare arrows.
c03815
DM: Okay, so the minions have a-
c03816
Unknown: That's what's sad, is you have a bunch of dice you haven't used
c03817
Delwath: ... the minions have a 16 AC.
c03818
Unknown: I think I can re-roll, right?
c03819
DM: So the two still hits.
c03820
Wellby: Awesome. Let's see if I can do more than one.
c03821
Delwath: Oh yeah, you can overkill.
c03822
Unknown: Are, are you killing minions?
c03823
Wellby: Uh, I probably didn't.
c03824
Delwath: Wait, what do you get, how do you get sneak attack damage?
c03825
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
c03826
DM: Yeah.
c03827
Unknown: Shoot these ones.
c03828
DM: Shoot those ones, not the ones-
c03829
Wellby: That's how I get sneak attack damage.
c03830
DM: Yeah. Okay.
c03831
Wellby: Indeed.
c03832
Unknown: [laughs]
c03833
DM: [coughs]
c03834
Unknown: 24, 32.
c03835
DM: Um,
c03836
DM: your arrow
c03837
DM: strikes this line down.
c03838
Delwath: Okay, and so then we have
c03839
Delwath: Kenzo.
c03840
DM: Uh,
c03841
DM: and now a pseudopod
c03842
DM: strikes at you.
c03843
Unknown: Oh.
c03844
Wellby: Wait, me?
c03845
DM: You just hit its minions.
c03846
Wellby: I thought maybe it considered them a different thing.
c03847
Unknown: Nevermind, just goes down its own.
c03848
Unknown: Cast feather fall.
c03849
Kenzo: Wait, wait. We're gonna make this all work.
c03850
Seeker: It's gonna land again.
c03851
DM: 25 points of damage.
c03852
Seeker: I need to do-
c03853
Wellby: Wait, it strikes me?
c03854
DM: Yeah.
c03855
Wellby: Did it, it, so it'd be my AC, right?
c03856
DM: I rolled a 20.
c03857
Delwath: Change its damage type.
c03858
DM: I mean, you have a re- you have your reaction back.
c03859
Seeker: Oh.
c03860
Seeker: That's what Mike was suggesting before.
c03861
Wellby: I only have seven hit points, it doesn't matter.
c03862
DM: Okay.
c03863
Seeker: Yeah.
c03864
DM: So you fall.
c03865
Wellby: Down goes Wellby again.
c03866
Unknown: And then, and then I kill it.
c03867
Seeker: So what would make it vulnerable to your type of damage?
c03868
Kenzo: Make it, make it, turn it into like a thing of, made out of glass.
c03869
DM: Yeah.
c03870
Seeker: Did Wellby go down again?
c03871
DM: Wellby went down again.
c03872
Unknown: Yeah.
c03873
Wellby: I'll be fine.
c03874
Kenzo: [laughs] It, it's my turn now then?
c03875
DM: It's, it's Kenzo's turn, yeah.
c03876
Kenzo: Fuck, it needed to be Seeker's turn.
c03877
Delwath: Seeker is last.
c03878
Kenzo: No, 'cause Seeker needs to use his int-
c03879
Seeker: To turn it to glass
c03880
Kenzo: ... to turn, to use as a fucking Limbo, Limbo action to turn the thing into glass so I can fucking kill it.
c03881
Seeker: Yeah, so you can just smash it.
c03882
Unknown: Yeah.
c03883
Kenzo: Yeah.
c03884
Wellby: How's your int? Can you int it?
c03885
Unknown: I can try.
c03886
DM: You can try. You might roll it.
c03887
DM: It's, it's not a super high DC.
c03888
Unknown: I do have bard inspiration.
c03889
Unknown: Ah.
c03890
Kenzo: I have a 10 intelligence. It's a plus zero.
c03891
DM: So you're gonna have to roll d...
c03892
Unknown: But inspiration is, helps a lot-
c03893
Unknown: 2d12
c03894
DM: ... 'cause it's 2d12, you take the highest And it's only an action, so you can use your haste action to do it.
c03895
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c03896
Seeker: Nice, nice.
c03897
Unknown: Yeah, why don't-
c03898
Kenzo: 'Cause, 'cause right now all these oozes...
c03899
Kenzo: We can't kill these oozes, right?
c03900
Unknown: The minions we can-
c03901
Unknown: They'll just reappear.
c03902
Unknown: Yeah.
c03903
Wellby: Yeah. Turn it into something that you can damage.
c03904
DM: Exactly.
c03905
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. That's what I'm saying.
c03906
DM: Turn it into glass.
c03907
Kenzo: I'm, I'm turning them into-
c03908
DM: Yeah
c03909
Kenzo: ... I'm, I'm turning it into glass.
c03910
DM: Yeah.
c03911
Unknown: Yeah.
c03912
DM: Do that.
c03913
Unknown: All right. [sighs] Fuck.
c03914
Kenzo: Okay. I will do that.
c03915
Kenzo: All right.
c03916
Delwath: Yeah, you're giving Kenzo inspiration.
c03917
Unknown: The cosmic roll, right?
c03918
DM: It's great.
c03919
Kenzo: Okay, so Kenzo goes up and now is, um...
c03920
Unknown: You probably-
c03921
DM: So you have to move your f- you have to use your full move to get there.
c03922
Kenzo: That's fine. I have 140 move.
c03923
DM: Yeah, I know.
c03924
Unknown: Okay.
c03925
Kenzo: So I get there.
c03926
DM: Uh, the minions take an opportunity attack against you.
c03927
DM: [paper rustling] Uh, you take-
c03928
Kenzo: This is your initiative.
c03929
DM: You take, uh, [paper rustling] 16 points of piercing damage reduced by half to...
c03930
Unknown: Eight.
c03931
DM: Eight.
c03932
DM: [die thudding]
c03933
Kenzo: Oh, that's an opportunity attack.
c03934
DM: Yeah. [clears throat]
c03935
Kenzo: Technically I could use my reaction.
c03936
DM: No, you could, but I would save it for the ooze attacks.
c03937
DM: Although, I don't know, this might work.
c03938
DM: Maybe you won't have to face more ooze attacks.
c03939
Kenzo: Okay. All right. So now Kenzo
c03940
Kenzo: closes his mind, imagines it as a sphere of glass
c03941
Kenzo: Limbo style.
c03942
Kenzo: And what I'm doing, I'm doing an intelligence-
c03943
DM: Yep
c03944
Kenzo: ... I'm doing an intelligence...
c03945
Unknown: Yeah
c03946
Kenzo: ... super fragile-
c03947
Wellby: Focus, focus, focus
c03948
Kenzo: ... piece of glass focusing on it.
c03949
Kenzo: [die rolling]
c03950
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
c03951
DM: Woo. Yeah.
c03952
Delwath: He rolled a 20. Yes. [laughs]
c03953
Unknown: Oh.
c03954
Unknown: Yes.
c03955
Unknown: [laughs]
c03956
Unknown: Well done.
c03957
DM: Don't even need to use inspiration.
c03958
DM: [laughs]
c03959
Unknown: Oh my God. [laughs]
c03960
DM: The
c03961
DM: crystal sphere shifts into this fragile glass.
c03962
Unknown: Oh.
c03963
DM: That was your haste. Go ahead and make your five bludgeoning attacks-
c03964
Seeker: Seeker looks over at Kenzo and waves at him
c03965
DM: ... that it is now vulnerable to.
c03966
Kenzo: Oh my God. All right. So now I, I get, uh-
c03967
Delwath: You get five attacks
c03968
Kenzo: ... five attacks. Wait.
c03969
Kenzo: Uh-
c03970
Delwath: And they'll do double damage
c03971
Kenzo: ... but two, two staff attacks, three...
c03972
Kenzo: Yeah.
c03973
DM: Two staff, three.
c03974
Kenzo: Okay. I'll, I'll roll my staff attacks first.
c03975
Unknown: Do,
c03976
Wellby: do your bonus act- Wait.
c03977
Wellby: Are they all regular action?
c03978
Wellby: Or any of those bonus actions?
c03979
Kenzo: Yeah, the three, three bonus actions.
c03980
Unknown: Yeah.
c03981
Unknown: Three bonus, two-
c03982
Delwath: Actually, do your bonus actions first
c03983
DM: ... two bonus-
c03984
Wellby: 'Cause then you can preserve your action- 'Cause then- ...
c03985
Wellby: and then do it for something else ... yeah, yeah, yeah.
c03986
Kenzo: Okay. All right. So I'll do my three unarmed strikes first.
c03987
Kenzo: So each of these is plus three.
c03988
Delwath: Wait, you... They can do bludgeoning if you want.
c03989
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c03990
Delwath: They don't have to.
c03991
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c03992
Unknown: Okay. [die rolling] Oh, no.
c03993
Unknown: Jeez. [laughs]
c03994
DM: Uh-
c03995
Kenzo: Well, it's a, it's a crystal thing.
c03996
Kenzo: Hopefully... It's a, it's a piece of cry- Oh, I fucking rolled a one.
c03997
DM: That one doesn't hit.
c03998
Unknown: But 18-
c03999
DM: What do you have to hit plus?
c04000
Kenzo: 18, 16, plus 13.
c04001
DM: Uh, 18 hits.
c04002
Delwath: Does, does-
c04003
DM: 16 misses.
c04004
Delwath: Uh, you could bardic that.
c04005
DM: Oh, yeah. You could bardic that.
c04006
DM: That's very close.
c04007
DM: Um-
c04008
Wellby: How much damage do you do with this?
c04009
Wellby: 'Cause you still have to roll damage
c04010
Kenzo: ... let me, let me roll damage on the first, the first one that hits.
c04011
Wellby: See how it goes.
c04012
Kenzo: Yeah. [die rolling] So that is...
c04013
Kenzo: Okay, so that's not bad. That's 13 damage
c04014
Kenzo: for the first one.
c04015
Kenzo: I'm gonna, I'm gonna roll my other staff attacks.
c04016
Unknown: Yeah, okay. Yeah. Sure.
c04017
Kenzo: Okay. So now I get two staff attacks.
c04018
Unknown: Two staffs, yeah.
c04019
Kenzo: Right, yeah. Two staff attacks.
c04020
DM: There's big cracks showing up on it.
c04021
DM: [die rolling]
c04022
Kenzo: Fuck. Oh, these are 15 though, so 20 and 21.
c04023
DM: Yeah, that hits.
c04024
Unknown: Okay. So-
c04025
Delwath: Oh, and then 3d 12.
c04026
Kenzo: 3d 12.
c04027
Unknown: Yeah.
c04028
Delwath: Plus 18.
c04029
Kenzo: 3d 12 plus 18.
c04030
Kenzo: [die rolling] Oh, this is... Okay.
c04031
Unknown: 17 and 18.
c04032
DM: 17 and 18.
c04033
Unknown: 35?
c04034
DM: 35 plu- 35 plus 18 or just 35?
c04035
Unknown: Total of 35.
c04036
DM: Uh, hold on.
c04037
DM: Oh, no. Okay. So Kenzo hits this once,
c04038
DM: cracks appear.
c04039
DM: Hits it twice,
c04040
DM: cracks appear. Hits it the third time and you smash right through it.
c04041
Unknown: Yes.
c04042
DM: Uh,
c04043
DM: how far away is Wellby from the edge?
c04044
Unknown: Do I, why, why does it matter how far away I is?
c04045
Wellby: The edge of what?
c04046
DM: The ooze. Pretty close, right?
c04047
DM: How far away is Delwath?
c04048
Unknown: At max move away.
c04049
Delwath: Okay.
c04050
Delwath: So, uh, like 70 feet or something, 70 or 80 feet.
c04051
Seeker: Seeker is right there.
c04052
DM: Okay. Um-
c04053
Unknown: [laughs]
c04054
DM: The, the m- ooze matter begins, like, rushing in in this implosion and it hits
c04055
DM: Kenzo and
c04056
DM: Seeker in the middle.
c04057
DM: You both take 21 points of force damage
c04058
DM: and are tossed 1,000 feet into the air.
c04059
Unknown: Oh my God. [laughs]
c04060
DM: Uh-
c04061
Unknown: [laughs]
c04062
DM: Wellby, uh, you fail one death save.
c04063
DM: You are out of range.
c04064
DM: Nothing happens to you.
c04065
Seeker: 21 damage.
c04066
DM: So that's-
c04067
Unknown: 1,000 feet
c04068
DM: ... 20d6 falling damage.
c04069
Unknown: [laughs]
c04070
Delwath: But you don't...
c04071
Kenzo: I mean, I'm a natural being and I can fly, whatever.
c04072
Unknown: It's all, it's all fine.
c04073
DM: Right. So you take no flying damage.
c04074
Unknown: Yeah.
c04075
DM: It doesn't matter to you.
c04076
Unknown: Yeah.
c04077
Seeker: Uh, I'm gonna have to do something about this.
c04078
Seeker: [tapping keyboard]
c04079
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. You don't wanna, you don't, you don't wanna fall 1,000 feet.
c04080
Kenzo: No, that might be, that might be painful.
c04081
DM: It's 20d6 damage.
c04082
Delwath: But you could possibly do something.
c04083
Delwath: Who's, what, what's...
c04084
Delwath: That was Kenzo's turn.
c04085
Unknown: Uh-
c04086
Unknown: Oh, it would be the oozes's turn.
c04087
DM: It's-
c04088
Wellby: It's gonna take, like, two rounds for you to get back down there
c04089
DM: ... it's now solidifying into crystal-
c04090
Unknown: Right. I see
c04091
DM: ... all across.
c04092
Wellby: There's plenty of time to cast something.
c04093
Unknown: Yeah.
c04094
DM: No, it's dead.
c04095
Wellby: Yes. No, I'm saying falling 10,000 feet or 1,000 feet- 1,000 feet ...
c04096
Wellby: is gonna take, like, 12 seconds.
c04097
DM: You fall 500 feet a round.
c04098
Unknown: Feet a s-
c04099
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
c04100
Delwath: So you have time to cast something.
c04101
Unknown: [laughs]
c04102
Delwath: You use your scroll of wish to cast feather fall.
c04103
Unknown: [laughs]
c04104
Delwath: Don't actually do that.
c04105
DM: [laughs]
c04106
Unknown: Funny anyway.
c04107
Wellby: Okay. Can we run down and grab you?
c04108
Kenzo: Uh, can I step with the wind to pick him up?
c04109
DM: Uh-
c04110
Unknown: I can-
c04111
DM: No, because he falls f- You're, you're just, like, la-di-da, floating.
c04112
Unknown: No, but I can fly.
c04113
DM: I know, but you can't fly 500 feet in a round.
c04114
Kenzo: I'm, I'm, I'm, I have... Oh, I'm, I'm hast-
c04115
DM: He's falling 500 feet down.
c04116
Unknown: Yeah.
c04117
DM: You'd have to catch him 500 feet down, and you can't get that far.
c04118
Unknown: What's your movement?
c04119
Unknown: 140.
c04120
DM: Uh, wait.
c04121
Unknown: On haste.
c04122
Delwath: So hold on. So you, so that's three.
c04123
Unknown: You have to push him that way.
c04124
DM: You can't get quite there.
c04125
Unknown: Oh, oh, oh, hold on, hold on. I can just-
c04126
Delwath: Whose turn is next?
c04127
Seeker: ... animate- The ladder [laughing] and hold on to
c04128
Unknown: Yes. [laughs]
c04129
Delwath: it as we fly down. I was gonna, I was gonna...
c04130
Delwath: I had a plan, but this is a much better plan.
c04131
Delwath: [laughs] Dramatically better.
c04132
Seeker: I knew the ladder was gonna play a role.
c04133
Unknown: [laughs]
c04134
DM: So, so as the, as the force of this Limbo explosion destroying the heart of the Ooze crystallizes this shell of
c04135
DM: matter across the battlefield, um,
c04136
DM: Seeker, you all see, except Wellby, who's unconscious, but hears the story later.
c04137
Delwath: No, I'm, I'm, I'm waking Wellby up.
c04138
Delwath: [laughs] I...
c04139
Delwath: No, wait, Wellby's gonna be conscious.
c04140
DM: Oh, 'cause it's Delwath's turn.
c04141
Delwath: I get a turn.
c04142
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c04143
Delwath: I'm not messing around anymore.
c04144
Unknown: 34.
c04145
DM: Okay.
c04146
Wellby: Points? Yeah. You hit?
c04147
Unknown: Oh, wow.
c04148
DM: So Wellby turns around-
c04149
Wellby: [laughs] What the hell are they doing up there?
c04150
DM: ...
c04151
DM: and sees, sees Seeker madly, like scrambling to pull the ladder off of his like belt or wherever you keep it, strapped to your backpack.
c04152
Unknown: Yeah.
c04153
DM: And then just like m- muttering something, and suddenly you see the ladder
c04154
DM: flying.
c04155
Unknown: [laughs]
c04156
DM: A faint image of a superhero cape streaming behind it as it wraps around Seeker, grabs him, and slowly
c04157
DM: and gently brings him down to the ground, preventing him from being squashed flat by 1,000 foot fall.
c04158
Kenzo: E clu so we may rise.
c04159
Unknown: Yes.
c04160
Unknown: [laughs]
c04161
DM: And then you turn and look at each other.
c04162
DM: The Ooze dead.
c04163
Wellby: Are the minions gone?
c04164
DM: The minions are t- turned into solid crystal.
c04165
Unknown: Crystal. Yeah. All right.
c04166
DM: They're everything turned into...
c04167
Unknown: Oh, my God. Oh.
c04168
DM: And you look as you see the ash slowly beginning to settle from the sky around you.
c04169
Kenzo: Put the cape down now. Phew.
c04170
DM: So stressful. Gotta add a few more.
c04171
Unknown: Kenzo's really the hero of that combat.
c04172
Unknown: You gotta get a few more- [laughs] ...
c04173
Kenzo: a few more little leaves on your tree there.
c04174
Unknown: [laughs]
c04175
Unknown: Yeah.
c04176
Unknown: [laughs]
c04177
DM: And so you turn and you look at each other.
c04178
DM: Seeker's probably scraping some crystal off the ground.
c04179
Unknown: Oh, yes.
c04180
DM: Uh,
c04181
DM: and now what?
c04182
DM: Contact the rangers?
c04183
Unknown: Yeah, we gotta get the Heartroot, right?
c04184
Kenzo: Where's the Heartroot gonna go?
c04185
Kenzo: In the river? Right here.
c04186
Unknown: I think the cistern.
c04187
DM: Put, put it back in the cistern where it came from.
c04188
Unknown: Yeah, yeah,
c04189
Kenzo: yeah. Yeah. Let's, uh, contact the rangers.
c04190
Kenzo: Let's teleport over when we're ready.
c04191
Unknown: Do you have
c04192
Unknown: a seventh level spell slot left?
c04193
Delwath: Um. You have a seventh and an eighth, right?
c04194
Unknown: I think I have.
c04195
DM: Yeah, 'cause Seeker was shape changed for almost the whole combat.
c04196
Unknown: It was casting spells.
c04197
DM: Shape change turned out to be quite a fun spell to have.
c04198
Wellby: Seventh. If you have a seventh and an eighth, we can go pick it up and come right back.
c04199
Seeker: Yeah, exactly. I, I, um, I burned my seventh.
c04200
DM: Ow.
c04201
Seeker: So I'm-
c04202
DM: Unchain lightning
c04203
Seeker: ... I just have a eighth
c04204
Unknown: now.
c04205
DM: Well, it's not gonna kill you to teleport to Aurbez, take a long rest, and then teleport back.
c04206
Unknown: Yeah.
c04207
DM: It might be good, actually.
c04208
Seeker: Yeah, I'm pretty spent.
c04209
DM: So over the course of the day
c04210
DM: you teleport back to Aurbez and-
c04211
Wellby: Can we roll the teleport percent just to-
c04212
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. Just roll
c04213
Unknown: ... to see what happens?
c04214
DM: Just see what happens.
c04215
Delwath: Just for the sake of curiosity. Don't you auto succeed, 'cause you have the dirt from-
c04216
DM: He has the dirt. That's true, he has the dirt.
c04217
Wellby: So is it 100%?
c04218
DM: Yeah, it's guaranteed if you,
c04219
DM: um-
c04220
Unknown: Sover. No.
c04221
Unknown: I'm just too good at this.
c04222
DM: Yeah.
c04223
Unknown: [laughs]
c04224
DM: Uh-
c04225
Delwath: I mean, you took some of the dirt from here too, right?
c04226
Delwath: Yeah
c04227
DM: ... you explain what happened to g- to great, um, excitement in Aurbez.
c04228
DM: Talk to Catiline Malras and some other rangers,
c04229
DM: and then after you've had a chance to rest
c04230
DM: and
c04231
DM: recover a little bit and, you know, maybe communicate with Phaldrik and tell him to meet you at Isengai, which he was already planning on doing, um,
c04232
DM: you carefully, um,
c04233
DM: like you and Sever... How many...
c04234
DM: Oh, you can just teleport an object.
c04235
Seeker: Right.
c04236
DM: But Kenzo counts as part of the Heartroot.
c04237
DM: So I'm gonna say you can teleport Kenzo and the Heartroot together.
c04238
Seeker: Oh, o- okay.
c04239
DM: Um,
c04240
DM: and then you can just use a second teleport to tel- 'cause you have two seventh level slots now.
c04241
Delwath: I mean, you have to do
c04242
Delwath: three to go back and forth, but that's okay.
c04243
DM: No, you're, you're resting in Aurbez.
c04244
Unknown: Yeah.
c04245
DM: So you're gonna end up in Isengai, but then your shard is in Isengai.
c04246
Unknown: Right.
c04247
DM: So you don't have to teleport back to Aurbez.
c04248
Delwath: I just meant if he was gonna teleport to get us as well.
c04249
DM: No, if you teleport an object, you don't have to go-
c04250
Unknown: Oh
c04251
Delwath: ... you don't have to go with it.
c04252
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
c04253
DM: So you teleport
c04254
DM: Kenzo and the Heartroot
c04255
DM: back to the cistern.
c04256
DM: That, that, that is right there, that's Kenzo and the Heartroot.
c04257
Kenzo: There you go. There it is.
c04258
DM: And Kenzo begins to like gradually start to like
c04259
DM: f- you know, settle it back into the, the water.
c04260
DM: Um, you know,
c04261
DM: take your staff and like knock down some rubble and stuff to make a, a path so that some of the river can flow in, and it can start to decontaminate the river from the long influence of
c04262
DM: Limbo.
c04263
DM: And the-
c04264
Kenzo: It's like Charlie Brown's Christmas tree
c04265
DM: ... and the rangers, some of the rangers and you, you can teleport up to eight.
c04266
Unknown: Eight.
c04267
DM: Right? So you bring the three of you and-
c04268
Unknown: Five
c04269
DM: ... five rangers to sort of help start to get things settled.
c04270
DM: Spend a couple of days in Isingue making sure the Heartroot is safe.
c04271
Kenzo: What- what's the Heartroot... Once the Heartroot get...
c04272
Kenzo: Like, what happens once the Heartroot gets-
c04273
DM: So it begins to... It, like, stretches out and it, like, expands.
c04274
DM: And,
c04275
DM: you know, Kenzo's a- attuned to it, right, and pretty connected, so there's this
c04276
DM: massive sigh of relief.
c04277
DM: And then it's almost like it begins to drop these little filaments into the river, and as the water flows past, it's like it's decontaminating the
c04278
Unknown: ash and everything that fell from, from Limbo in the river.
c04279
DM: It's gonna take a while to, like, rebuild the cistern.
c04280
Unknown: Right.
c04281
Unknown: There's some manual labor that needs to happen before it can really
c04282
Unknown: go back, but it's reconnected to the river and sort of...
c04283
DM: And it finds it immediate- You actually see it immediately, the, like, filamentous roots just immediately tunnel through the little gaps so it can reach out and grab the river
c04284
DM: water. And water starts, like, flowing in, back into the cistern along the channels that it carves through the rubble, sort of feeling its way out to
c04285
Unknown: reconstruct the,
c04286
DM: um,
c04287
DM: reconstruct the, the patterns and flows and channels that once were there long ago.
c04288
DM: And actually, as you're here, you get the feeling that the cistern was here even before the city.
c04289
Unknown: Hmm.
c04290
c04291
DM: And the city,
c04292
Unknown: it, like, the Heartroot is actually beginning to grow new pillars that-
c04293
Kenzo: Did we, did we mirror the Heartroot?
c04294
Kenzo: We did, right?
c04295
DM: Yeah.
c04296
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
c04297
DM: That's when you saw it, like, getting created-
c04298
DM: It's like from before time
c04299
Delwath: ... from before time.
c04300
Delwath: From before time.
c04301
Kenzo: Right, right. We should, we should mirror the cistern too.
c04302
Kenzo: There's something in the cistern.
c04303
Delwath: I wanna, I wanna see the, uh,
c04304
DM: the queen of-
c04305
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, yeah. For sure. We'll do that one too.
c04306
DM: So-
c04307
Kenzo: We got a bunch. We got, we got time
c04308
DM: ... yeah. So time passes,
c04309
DM: the
c04310
DM: Heartroot settles into place.
c04311
DM: Um,
c04312
DM: more rangers start to come, um,
c04313
DM: you know, over the course of a, of, of a week or two.
c04314
DM: Um, you establish a little bit of a camp at Isingue.
c04315
DM: There's still dangers in the wild, but nothing that, you know, is particularly challenging for a
c04316
DM: group of such adventurers.
c04317
DM: And
c04318
DM: you remain over the course of
c04319
DM: a couple weeks until
c04320
DM: sometime in October, early October.
c04321
DM: Things seem stable here,
c04322
DM: and you find yourself now back on Vindasharna wondering what you're gonna do next.
c04323
DM: And in that time you can of course look at, you know, three things in the mirror,
c04324
DM: and there's some time while Vindasharna flies to drop the monks off and other people off wherever you want to be dropped off.
c04325
Unknown: Oh, yeah, we found the monks.
c04326
DM: Mm-hmm.
c04327
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c04328
Seeker: So the monks kind of missed 30 years of
c04329
Seeker: local history.
c04330
DM: Yep.
c04331
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c04332
Unknown: Um,
c04333
Kenzo: I gotta use the bathroom.
c04334
Kenzo: Should we, like, sh- should we, like-
c04335
DM: Yeah, let's move over there
c04336
Kenzo: ... shift, shift over to the...
c04337
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c04338
Seeker: That was pretty bonkers.
c04339
Unknown: That was amazing